It's no good!
The fire has spread to the forest
in the Third District!
Can't we get more fire helicopters?
At this rate,
all the mountains will be devastated!
Damn it. Why is it spreading so fast?
What happened here?
The trees are all uprooted.
Did something crash?
No, we haven't had any reports like that.
Mont Blanc...
Professor Reinhardt!
My Mont Blanc!
Professor!
Let me go!
No, Professor!
It's dangerous to get any closer!
His signal is dead.
I've lost contact with Mont Blanc!
What's the matter, Gesicht?
Oh, well,
it's nothing.
You seem tired as of late.
Are you overworking yourself?
Maybe you should take some time off...
I'm fine.
No need to worry.
As you can see, white smoke
is still rising after two days,
and scattered fires are visible.
According to accident investigators,
the robot assigned to
the Swiss Forestry Service, Mont Blanc,
was found in pieces
within the confines of this forest fire.
Mont Blanc was
a world-renowned mountain-guide robot
known for befriending scores of children
and mountain climbers alike.
He also poured himself into programming
a tree-clearing strategy
that allows us to coexist with nature.
Condolences for the beloved
Mont Blanc are coming in
from all over the world.
Yes, this is Gesicht.
Yes. Understood. I'll be right there.
It's work. I've got to go.
But what about your breakfast?
Helena.
Shall we take a trip
when I can take time off?
I should be getting more rest, right?
I never expected to hear you say that.
The victim resided in this apartment.
Bernard Lanke, 42 years old.
He was a key advocate
for the Robot Rights Protection Laws.
Was he human?
Oh, yes. He was.
Man, this is awful.
Hey, you!
Please don't step into the crime scene
without permission.
Inspector, he's the one sent from Europol.
Nice to meet you.
I see. Pardon me.
I'm Inspector Wallace of the city police.
Nice to meet you.
As you can see,
the place has been turned upside down.
It'll take us a while to figure out
if anything has been taken.
No, I don't believe
this is the work of a thief.
Huh? How can you be sure?
There is no sign of ransacking.
Come now. With this much damage...
I can tell.
This room was merely damaged.
Then what do you make of this?
What are these horn-looking things
sticking through the head?
Yes, it's me.
Right.
What?
Someone broke through a checkpoint!
Get an ambulance right away!
Were you the only one attacked, constable?
Robby was also at the checkpoint.
My partner...
I mean, a constable-bot.
Model PRC1332.
I can't believe that a constable-bot
was destroyed so easily.
Inspector!
A male suspect in his twenties
in a red cap with tattoos on both arms
seems to have fled toward
the old city's redevelopment zone.
Okay then, pair up and search--
Hey! I said to pair up!
Damn it! Europol, my ass!
Stop resisting!
I didn't do anything!
There are traces of coating material
from the constable-bot on that steel pipe.
A drug addict.
You are high on a drug called "noi."
Ingested about 40 minutes ago.
Is that about right?
Who's your dealer?
A guy named Shultz on Karl-Heinz Street.
What time did you meet him?
Before 5:00 a.m. this morning.
If the dealer corroborates your account,
you have an alibi.
That's around the time
when Bernard Lanke was murdered.
Murdered?
You only attacked the constable with
a pipe to avoid arrest for illicit drugs.
And you destroyed
a constable-bot, aka Robby.
I can read you your rights
and arrest you quietly, or...
Please don't shoot me!
Relax.
This gun only shoots sleeping gas.
I'm built in such a way
that I can't hurt humans.
I am a robot.
Hello, who is it?
My name is Gesicht.
I'm a special investigator from Europol.
How can I help you?
You're Robby's wife?
Yes, I am.
I'm afraid I have tragic news.
Would you like some tea?
Being a robot as well, I'm sure you'll
just go through the motions of drinking.
By living as humans do, they say we robots
can upgrade our human-like senses.
That much is true.
But it's difficult to understand
the joy of drinking tea.
Especially for an outdated model like me.
I work as a maid for a certain family.
And their boy. A human boy, of course.
The family had adopted a dog
before the boy was born.
The boy and the dog grew up like siblings.
But the dog died.
Would you like me to erase
a portion of your memory data?
Please don't erase
the memories of my husband.
This is horrible.
The victim is Bernard Lanke.
Key advocate
for the International Robot Laws.
I see.
There must be tons of people
who think badly
of a scholar who insists on protecting
the rights of robots like he did.
And this is the body that was found.
What are those horn-looking things?
I'm not sure.
However...
This is...
This is the site where Mont Blanc of
the Swiss Forestry Service was destroyed.
Horns.
Are you saying the same person
is responsible for both incidents?
Breaking a sturdy robot like Mont Blanc
into pieces is impossible for humans.
In addition, at the time of his murder,
there was no trace of a human presence
in Lanke's apartment.
"No trace of a human presence..."
Hold it, Gesicht.
Lanke was human!
Yes. Article 13
of the International Robot Laws says,
"A robot shall not be able
to harm or kill humans."
If there's a robot out there
that can kill a human,
it would be the first time
since the incident eight years ago.
I will find the perpetrator.
Whether it be a robot or a human,
there is a devil inside them.
A strange pedestal, isn't it?
Originally, the plan was to build
a bronze statue of Mont Blanc on it.
However, Mont Blanc objected to it.
He said it would be wrong
to ruin the scenic view of the Alps
with a bronze statue of himself.
Not only that, he insisted
he would one day become scrap iron.
"Please pulverize my entire body,
melt it, and recycle it," he said.
But he was still in his prime.
Mont Blanc was a true hero.
He joined the 39th Central Asian War
as a member of the peace-keeping forces.
He not only helped the Kingdom of Persia
restore peace from the chaos and turmoil,
but he also managed to apprehend
terrorists in hiding without bloodshed.
Without him, Asia could never have reached
the state of peace it has now.
He was also a poet.
He was able to sing with birds
and converse with the trees in the forest.
Those people over there volunteered
to do this work with no compensation.
They all loved Mont Blanc, my son.
Mont Blanc. He was
the guardian angel of the mountains.
In three days, tens of thousands...
no, hundreds of thousands
will come to the memorial
to mourn the death of Mont Blanc.
Detective, this was no accident.
They say Mont Blanc was destroyed
because of the huge tornado
that happened just before the forest fire,
but that's not true at all.
Detective, please catch
the person responsible for this.
If you do, then with these hands,
with my own hands...
The pride of Switzerland, nay, the world.
Mont Blanc
will forever live in our hearts.
Are you awake, Gesicht?
Your regular maintenance is finished.
Thank you, Professor Hoffman.
So, how did it go?
Oh, nothing out of the ordinary.
Except...
Yes?
Many people think robots don't get tired,
but when you're this similar to humans,
a robot can feel exhaustion.
On the contrary. The human body itself
is nothing but a mechanism.
With too much use,
any mechanism can become fatigued.
Fatigued?
Looks like you're dealing
with rather difficult cases.
I saw Mont Blanc's memorial on TV,
but I had to turn it off
to keep from crying.
Some media have reported a theory
that he self-destructed
from an electromagnetic wave anomaly
in his body.
But as an expert on the subject,
I don't believe
a high-performance robot like him
could experience
such an elementary problem.
To destroy a robot
that was loved by everyone...
You think you'll find the perpetrator?
I guess it can't be that easy.
On the other hand,
the other case you're investigating
looks complicated too.
The victim named Lanke...
I saw him several times on TV debates,
and it's not surprising he was targeted.
He wasn't necessarily
doing anything wrong,
but he had a sharp tongue.
It's like he was looking down on everyone.
That was bound to make some enemies.
The complete opposite of Mont Blanc.
A robot and a human.
One with no enemies
and the other with too many enemies.
Juggling two tough cases like these
will exhaust you, of course.
Can I ask you a question?
What is it?
Is it possible for a human
to infiltrate a room
without leaving any biological traces?
You mean traces so minuscule
that your sensors cannot detect them?
Yes.
That's an interesting question.
I wonder if there's a way...
That's my homework until next time.
Sorry about all that. This is supposed
to be a place for you to relax.
No more shop talk.
I've been talking to my wife
about taking time off for a trip.
Oh, how nice.
We have to consider
my wife's schedule too,
so I don't know when it will happen.
Traveling is good.
Data shows that seeing the world
yields positive results
for artificial intelligence.
How about doing something bold
and going to Japan?
Japan?
Yeah, I went there once at the invitation
of one of their scientific technicians.
Tokyo is exotic and interesting.
Japan, huh? I'll talk to my wife about it.
By the way, Gesicht,
are you still having the dream
you told me about before?
Yes.
Well, I'm not trying to pry it out of you,
but I'm quite intrigued by dreams
generated by artificial intelligence.
It's been academically proven
that artificial intelligence
also carries a subconscious.
Even so, it is rare to find a robot
that actually has dreams.
When you feel up to it,
could you tell me about it?
Sure.
Twentieth-century psychiatrist Freud
said something like this,
"Dreams are expressions of reality,
not just products of our imagination."
Excuse me.
Is this a constable-bot?
Yeah, seems like it.
They finished the forensic analysis
and wanted it disposed of.
Robby...
May I take a look?
Yeah, sure.
Feel free to take whatever parts you want.
They're junk, after all.
You can have the whole body for 500 ZEUS.
What's the matter?
Oh, no.
It's nothing.
Nothing at all.
This is your husband's memory chip.
I may be overstepping,
but I thought you might want to keep it.
Oh, not at all.
I'm sincerely grateful.
Thank you.
I should be going now.
Wait!
Would you mind inserting it into me?
The memories could be painful.
They might cause you to malfunction.
If that happens,
I'll take it out right away.
He's right here.
Ma'am, you must stop!
Memories of his last moments
are also stored there!
- I'm taking it out!
-   What could this be?
I wonder what it is.
What do you see?
Let me project it.
This was when Robby stopped a car
at the checkpoint with his partner.
This is the suspect.
I'm so sorry.
I shouldn't have brought this to you.
I don't know how to apologize.
It's not that.
My husband reacted
to the criminal's steel pipe immediately.
He had his stun gun at the ready.
I understand.
It was odd that your husband,
a constable-bot, was attacked so easily.
This is definitely an unusual case--
That's not what I mean.
Take a closer look.
I can see it
because the memory chip is inside me.
His partner was attacked.
Up until this moment,
my husband had registered
the criminal's movements.
But in the next moment,
he was distracted by something.
This is the apartment
Lanke was murdered in!
Pause it, please!
What is that?
I'll zoom in.
It's not a bird.
Why didn't the forensics team notice this?
You would've never spotted it
unless you had this memory chip inserted.
My husband caught sight
of this shadow in an instant,
and his identification system
analyzed what it was.
But if it could jump
from building to building like this...
Yes.
But this is...
not a robot.
A murder in a room
with no trace of human activity.
The death of a robot loved by everyone.
Horns.
Identity confirmed.
Please enter.
Are you a robot, Detective?
Yes.
Wow, I sure couldn't tell
from your appearance.
If you get too close to him,
your artificial intelligence could be
compromised by his electromagnetic waves.
Use this protective gear.
I'll be okay.
I'm impervious to electromagnetic waves.
What?
I'm made of a special alloy,
although I may not look like it.
Well, if you say so,
but do be careful.
So far, four robots
have fallen victim to him.
It's a laughably desperate barricade,
isn't it?
At the end of the day,
humans can't control their fear
without pitiful measures like this.
Brau1589.
Welcome, Robot Model HRS0288,
Inspector Gesicht.
So you are
the most advanced detective robot?
It seems your identification system
is still functioning.
It is indeed. Thank you.
It's actually more sensitive than before.
Being deprived of the mode of locomotion,
I can't help but be curious
about what's happening out there.
I came here today
because I wanted to ask you something.
What is it?
What crossed the mind of a certain robot
when it killed a human eight years ago?
A legal scholar
named Bernard Lanke was murdered,
but there were no traces
of human presence at the scene.
Was the killer a human, or--
A robot? And if it was a robot,
why would it do such a thing?
The humans examined every last bit of it.
My murderous artificial intelligence,
that is.
They believed
there must have been a defect,
but they couldn't find a thing.
My artificial intelligence
had no flaws at all.
Can you imagine
how terrified the humans were
when they found that out?
That's why they keep me locked up
in a place like this.
If they are that afraid, they can just
pull this spear. Then I'd die.
But humans cannot even do that.
Inspector Gesicht.
If you want to know more about someone
who's committed a murder,
why don't we exchange memory chips?
You might learn something new.
Here are some printed images
of Mont Blanc's destruction
and the murder scene at Lanke's residence.
What do you think these horns mean?
Among the ancient gods of Europe,
the god of death had horns.
Herne the Hunter,
who takes the souls of warriors,
was also called the "Horned King."
In Greek mythology,
Hades is the king of the underworld.
Or perhaps, the lord of the underworld
in Roman mythology,
Pluto.
Whoever did these will strike again.
Mont Blanc, among the most advanced
of all robots, was destroyed so easily.
The answer should be clear to you by now.
The top-class robots created
with the best technologies in the world.
Robots who can also be
weapons of mass destruction.
You know the answer already, do you not?
Including you, there are six more.
I'm working.
Don't just stand there. It's distracting.
I'm sorry to have entered
without your permission, sir.
The security seems to have been disabled.
It's not safe, considering your blindness.
No burglar would come all the way
to this wasteland to steal from me.
But, Sir Duncan--
That's enough.
Are you the new butler?
Yes, sir.
They likely sent over
yet another good-for-nothing.
Your name?
Yes, sir. My name is North No.2.
What a dull and tasteless name.
The staffing agency told me
you have a military background.
Yes, sir.
During the 39th Central Asian War,
I was a butler for the commander-in-chief
of the British Army.
A butler for a soldier, huh?
You must be a rather boorish sight.
I wear a cape in the presence of others.
I see.
So your whole body is a weapon.
Make me some tea, will you?
Certainly, sir.
As for the type, I want...
Please rest assured.
All of your data is already downloaded.
My data, huh?
Before I came here,
I had the chance to see a film.
The Queen on the Satellite Orbit.
I was deeply moved by how the music
and images came together as one.
Is that from your "data" as well?
No, I was profoundly moved
from the bottom of my heart.
That film is over ten years old.
Here you are.
Every score I composed was a huge hit,
sweeping all the film music awards.
I was lauded as a blind musical genius.
Reviews from the media must surely be
in that skull of yours too.
"Even the genius Paul Duncan
has run out of talent."
Am I right?
What a load of bollocks.
If I felt the urge, I could compose
limitless scores even now.
My genius is alive and well.
I write the notes,
and the people burst into applause.
They would leave the theater in tears.
It's not that I can't compose. I won't.
I'm done with such trivial things.
But you were working just now.
It was a beautiful piece.
It's not for a film. That piece is for me.
Only for me.
- This is just like your name.
- Sir?
Dull and tasteless.
A beautiful piece? Don't make me laugh.
A rubbish military weapon like you
has no right to talk about my art!
My apologies, sir.
How many did you kill?
Sir?
I'm asking how many people you killed
in the Central Asian War.
The International Robot Laws
forbid me from harming humans.
I see. So you killed your own kind.
How many robots did you destroy?
You lost count?
Go away.
A tasteless meal becomes
even blander with you around.
I will take my leave, sir.
What are you doing? Do not touch my piano!
My apologies, sir.
You compose with your piano only, I see.
What about it?
You have so much cutting-edge
musical equipment available to you.
These are just like you.
A fake violin, a fake trumpet,
a fake orchestra.
Pretend as they might,
they're nothing but machines.
That's why I don't put in artificial eyes.
Anything I could see
with the help of machines is fake.
I have no need for it.
The real scenery is in my memories.
The real scenery...
The landscape of my hometown,
captured when I was able to see.
When you were a child in Bohemia.
Is that from the data too?
There's nothing that truly matters
in such nonsense.
The scenery of my hometown.
The green fields.
The gentle breeze.
And
that golden glow.
I will turn that scenery into music!
I told you not to touch my piano!
My apologies, sir.
If a machine like you
were to play from a score,
any notes produced would be fake!
Sir Duncan.
Please pardon my imposition,
but I heard you moaning
as you slept in your bedroom last night.
But it also sounded like
you were humming, as well.
And I believe that melody
would fit perfectly
within the piece you are composing now.
That section where you always stop midway...
It's not precise, but it went like this.
Get out!
I have no need for a robot like you.
Leave this residence!
But...
That's an order. Leave!
Piano...
I'd like to learn how to play piano.
What did you say?
As you say, no matter what I might play,
it may always be fake.
But I'd like to get as close as possible
to the real thing.
A weapon like you
could never play the piano!
Stop it! That's nothing
for a tool of destruction to touch!
You belong on the battlefield!
That is why.
That is why
I'd like to learn to play piano.
Because I don't ever want to go
to a battlefield again.
Mom!
Wait, Mom!
Mom, don't go!
Mom!
Are you there, North No.2?
I told you not to come into my bedroom.
Sir Duncan, your breakfast is ready.
I thought I fired you.
Are you still there?
How many times do I have to tell you?
Don't touch my piano!
Sir Duncan, please listen.
I think I've gotten a little better.
"Gotten a little better"?
The only improvement a machine can make
is to play with more precision!
I will try and play the melody you hum
in your sleep, Sir Duncan.
The sounds you produce are not music!
These bloody things!
"Just input the data,
and you can create infinite melodies?"
That's not music at all!
The machines will be ruined.
Are you trying to protect your kind?
Then let me ask you,
how many of your own kind did you destroy?
Take off your cape and show the world
the hideous weapon that is your body!
With that body of yours,
how many of your kind did you kill?
Even a weapon of mass destruction
is programmed to behave obediently
in front of its master, huh?
Very well.
I will give you
some genuine, accurate data about me.
The reason I moan in my sleep...
The nightmare I've been having
for so many years...
No, not a nightmare.
The reality of my past...
My real name is not Paul Duncan.
It's Paulo Holy.
I was born in a poor household in Bohemia.
My father died
before I was old enough to remember.
I was struck
by a serious illness from birth,
and my eyesight was poor,
so my only joy was singing songs.
My mother was a beautiful woman.
Even in tatters, she would turn the heads
of men when she walked down the street.
That's why that parvenu approached her.
And my mother became blinded
by her greed for that man's money.
She must have felt burdened by me.
My mother left her sickly child.
My mother abandoned me!
I was sent
to a boarding school in England.
I had no friends,
and my weak body
left me bullied year-round.
But I was desperate
to continue my study of music.
I must have strained myself continuously
because, at one point,
I developed a persistent fever,
and even my music studies
could not continue.
I was sent around
from hospital to hospital,
but my condition worsened.
The doctors gave up on me,
and I never heard from my mother.
I thought I was going to die.
What a fitting last moment
for an abandoned child.
That's when a Japanese doctor appeared.
Technically, he wasn't a doctor
because he was unlicensed.
I will save your life.
But you might go blind as a result.
The surgery was a success.
But just as the unlicensed doctor said,
my eyesight deteriorated day by day.
With the little time I had left,
I threw myself even more
into the study of music.
Music was all I had.
More music!
More!
And finally,
the darkness came.
A few years later,
I was informed of my mother's death.
She never was able to marry that parvenu.
I heard she died all alone.
Serves her right for abandoning her child.
But you know what?
This castle belonged to that parvenu.
From Paulo Holy to the genius Paul Duncan.
I became a maestro of the music world
and made the castle mine.
Mother!
This is what you wanted.
This is what you sought
at the cost of abandoning your child!
Now, Mother, I will show you
what is truly important.
The landscape of our hometown
that you deserted!
I will turn
that magnificent scenery into music!
I will show you what it is
that humans should never throw away!
Sir Duncan.
Your mother--
Silence!
I'll write you a letter of recommendation.
Leave this place tomorrow.
That is why
I'd like to learn to play piano.
Because I don't ever want to go
to a battlefield again.
I guess he improved a little.
Charging himself in preparation
for tomorrow's departure?
Damn machine.
Is he having a nightmare?
Robots have dreams too?
"It's not that I can't compose.
I won't," huh?
Hey.
North No.2.
North No.2! Hey!
He really left, huh?
Maybe I really can't compose anymore.
How long are you going to make me wait?
When is the replacement butler coming--
Hello, my name is Marshall
from MCM Pictures.
Oh, you're just a movie guy.
Is something wrong, Sir Duncan?
No, I just fired
a butler robot the other day.
So, what do you want?
Well, I'm actually calling
about a score for a certain film.
A job offer, huh?
Tell me the details.
I might be interested.
Thank you, sir.
I was wondering if you would consent
to the reuse of one of your old scores.
What? You're not asking for a new piece?
Oh! It was my understanding
that you had retired, Sir Duncan.
Use it however you want.
Oh, Sir Duncan--
There is a new message.
This is Russell from the Planning Office
at the British Philharmonic Orchestra.
Regarding the performance of your suite
we discussed before,
unfortunately, we have decided
to cancel it due to various circumstances.
We are very sorry about this.
If another opportunity arises, we will...
I heard you moaning,
and I believe that melody
would fit perfectly...
Sir Duncan.
I have returned.
What now? I thought I told you to leave.
I went to Bohemia.
To your hometown, Sir Duncan.
What business did you have there?
I went to collect songs.
In the process of collecting
many folk songs from that region,
I have found it,
the melody you hum in your sleep.
I will sing it now.
Stop! I don't want to hear a machine sing!
Don't intrude on my nightmare any further!
Humans have things we would rather forget!
Sir Duncan, your dream is not a nightmare.
It's not something that should be erased
like my dreams.
Just as you said,
I am nothing but a weapon.
In the 39th Central Asian War,
I neutralized many enemy robots...
No, I destroyed tens of thousands
of my own kind.
Those memories,
the memories of killing
countless of my kind,
my artificial intelligence plays them
again and again in my mind.
I met a certain old man in Bohemia.
He was very knowledgeable
about folk songs,
and he knew that particular song as well.
He also remembered that there was
a wonderful singer of that song.
Your mother.
The data I have in my mind
about you, Sir Duncan,
includes that of your mother.
Your mother did not abandon you
when you were suffering from illness.
She approached a multimillionaire,
Jonathan Thorn, to attain treatment.
That's how she afforded the astronomical
fee for the doctor who saved your life.
You were never abandoned.
Your mother was right by your side
when you went blind.
But learning your hatred toward her,
she couldn't extend her hand.
No.
That can't be.
It's true.
When you remember your hometown,
are you not excluding
a very important memory?
The old man in the village told me
how you and your mother held hands
and sang this song together
as you watched the sun setting
into the fields of your homeland.
Mom...
I apologize.
It's only the song of a machine.
Your dream is not a nightmare.
Your dream is not like mine.
North No.2...
don't ever go back to the battlefield.
Let's practice the piano.
Yes, sir.
North No.2!
Hey, North No.2!
Yes, Sir Duncan?
It's finally finished. Give it a listen.
Yes, sir. I would love to listen to it.
However, just now...
Huh? What's the matter?
Something is approaching this direction.
"Something"?
Is it a friend visiting you, perhaps?
Did you hear the news from Switzerland
a few days ago, sir?
The news from Switzerland?
Oh, about the robot called Mont Blanc
getting destroyed in a tornado?
A tornado occurred about 100 km from here
just a moment ago.
Some sort of threat is approaching.
Hey!
I shall return soon.
North No.2!
North No.2.
North...
What in the world...
What is happening?
North No.2...
This is...
that song.
The song is spreading
across the entire sky.
North No.2.
North No.2 is singing.
Stop singing out here and come home soon.
North No.2,
it's time for our piano practice.
- It's really awesome!
- Really?
Is that a snail?
Yes.
Nice to meet you.
You must be Atom.
Yes.
Subtitle translation by: Astrid Oliver