A world in which the Titans
attack and devour humans.
The humans, who became the hunted...
built big walls and lived behind them in
exchange for their freedom to prevent invasion.
However, the fragile peace was destroyed with the appearance of the Colossal Titan.
They're coming inside!
The Titans are coming!
Eren, Mikasa! You two need to live on!
Stop!
Eren Jaeger, whose mother
had been killed by a Titan
became a trainee to polish his knowledge and
skills necessary to exterminate the Titans.
He and his fellow 104th Training Corps,
who spent three years together training,
would need to be determined
to fight against the Titans.
We already have the answer.
Humanity can't defeat the Titans.
And...?
You want us to waste the knowledge we have derived through thousands of deaths
and become food for the Titans?
No way in Hell!
I'm going to join the Survey Corps and exterminate the Titans!
It'll be fine.
Once we recapture the land, we'll be
able to raise more cows and sheep.
Humanity is finally regaining its dignity.
We can win.
Mankind's retaliation...
begins now!
A deadly battle took place in the Trost District against the Titans who appeared again.
Fire!
Humanity broke its chains of fear and faced forward with their knowledge.
But, a new discovery brought back fear to mankind.
Well, Recruit Jaeger?
Can you seal that gate?
That...
well...
I don't know.
I'm just as clueless as
the rest of us present here.
Oh, that's true, I apologize.
That was the wrong question.
Will you do it or not—which is it?
Will Eren Jaeger, who had obtained the power to turn into a Titan,
be the savior of mankind...
or a demon that leads mankind to destruction?
Go, Eren!
Hey, answer already, scum.
What is it you want to do?
I want to join the Survey Corps
and slaughter some Titans!
Oh? Not bad.
[  Part II  ]  -  Wings of Freedom  -
That hurt, Annie.
Can't you go a little easier on others?!
It's because you come at me with full
power that I have to act accordingly.
If you consider yourself a man, shouldn't
you go easier on this fragile body of mine?
Huh?!
Your jokes aren't funny, you know.
If you're weaker than me, then why am I
on the ground and you're still standing?
It isn't like I threw you with force.
The weak have to use
self-protection techniques
to protect themselves against those who are stronger than them, you see.
It won't hurt you to know these kind of moves, too.
I understand, but let's take a break first, alright?
Here I go!
Annie... I give up.
I give up...
Give up?
Don't give up.
Learn how to use your strength...
...and how to talk to girls.
Ok, I'll learn how. Let me go already!
Really? You want to learn more?
Why the hell did you come flying, Reiner?
Hey, Annie...
Can you teach those moves...
...to me too?
I don't know about that.
These moves are only for humans.
I don't think someone like you needs them at all.
But, I'm curious whether these moves will work on a monster.
I...Is this for real? At last...
Hey, hey!
Are they gonna fight?
It's the most anticipated duel!
W...Which one do you think?
Do you think it will be Annie?
Huh? Are you stupid?
I bet my whole dinner on Mikasa.
Which one do you think will win, Eren?
I...
Which one...
Why am I remembering that all of a sudden?
I wonder what the others are doing right now.
Anyway...
...where am I?
How many days have passed?!
How long is this confinement going to last?
Please bear with this for a little longer.
We'll try to sort things out somehow.
Commander Erwin said that but...
Don't tell me...
Am I stuck here for good?
So you're Eren, huh?
You okay? Feeling well?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
You're free to come out of there now.
That's assuming you wear these though.
I am Hange Zoe, a Squad Leader
in the Survey Corps.
The same goes for him.
His name is Mike Zacharias.
Um...
Oh...
He has a habit of smelling people
he's met for the first time...
and snorting afterward.
But I'm sure it's nothing more than just that.
Oh man, sorry for wasting all our time
only talking about insignificant things.
We're here already.
Well, no worries.
In fact, going in clueless is better.
Wait!
It's selfish of us, but we...
can only put our faith in you.
Best of luck.
A courthouse?
I was under a courthouse?
Get a move on!
Why are these people here?
What's going to be decided anyway?
You guys...
Now then, let us begin.
Eren Jaeger, correct?
You are a soldier who has
offered his life for mankind.
Is that accurate?
Yes.
This is an unprecedented case.
The trial will be a special court-martial
in which common law does not apply.
Let us begin with the Military Police
Brigade's opening statement.
Your honor, after conducting a thorough examination of Eren's body,
we dispose of him in a prompt manner.
It cannot be denied that his Titan power
allowed us to repel the latest attack.
However, his existence is also a source
of discord that can incite rebellion.
Therefore, after having him impart all the information he can provide,
we'll have him die as a hero of mankind.
Now then, let us hear the
Survey Corps' opening statement.
Your honor,
We of the Survey Corps will accept
Eren as an official member
and use his Titan power to recapture Wall Maria.
That is all.
Hm?
Is that it?
Yes.
If we utilize his power,
we can recapture Wall Maria.
I believe it's clear what needs to be prioritized.
Wait a second!
Wouldn't it be best to seal
all the gates for good now?
The only parts of the wall the Colossus
Titan can destroy are the gates!
Enough already, you boor!
You want mere humans to tamper
with Wall Rose, a gift from God?!
That's enough out of you, priest!
What?!
Order in the court.
You may argue about differences
in principles elsewhere.
Jaeger, allow me to confirm:
Can you continue to contribute to mankind as you have thus far
and utilize your Titan power to that same end?
Yes! I can!
Really?
But in the report for the
Battle of Trost District, it said:
"After transforming into a Titan,
he swung his fist at Mikasa Ackerman."
What, you wanted me to lie in a report?
Is Mikasa Ackerman here?
Yes, that's me.
You, huh?
Is it true that Jaeger attacked
you in his Titan form?
Yes, it is.
As I thought, a Titan will
always be a Titan, after all.
I tried to kill Mikasa?!
Me?
Mikasa Ackerman lost her parents at a young
age and was taken in by the Jaeger family.
Furthermore, through our investigations,
we have uncovered some shocking events
that took place during that time.
At the age of nine, Eren Jaegar and Mikasa Ackerman
stabbed to death three men wanted for robbery and kidnapping.
Though this falls under legitimate self-defense,
I feel their basic human nature needs to be questioned.
That's right!
He must be a Titan that's been hiding
amongst us in the form of a child!
Her too.
I wouldn't be surprised if she wasn't human!
Yeah!
We should dissect her just in case.
Wait, please!
I might be a monster, but that
has nothing to do with her!
Nothing at all!
As if we could trust you!
It's the truth!
He's covering for her because it's true!
No!
I mean... you're wrong.
So far, all of you've been doing is blurting out
convenient speculations that suits you.
Wh-What did you say?!
To begin with,
I should stop.
you've never even seen a Titan before,
so what are you so afraid of?
I should't say any more.
No, I'll keep at it.
I'll make my stand here!
How can we afford to not
let those with power fight?
If you're scared of fighting to survive,
then lend me your strength!
You... damn cowards.
What?!
Just shut up and bet everything on me!
Take aim!
Y-Yes!
Huh?
Wait, Mikasa!
This is just my pet theory,
but I think pain and
discipline go hand-in-hand.
What you need now
isn't a lecture, but training.
You're in a good position for me to kick too.
Wait, Levi...
What?
That's dangerous.
What'll you do if he gets
angry and transforms?
What're you saying?
You guys are gonna dissect him, right?
Supreme Commander, I have a proposal.
Yes?
Eren's Titan power has
many uncertain points to it,
which poses a constant threat.
So I propose he be entrusted
to Lance Corporal Levi
and taken out on an expedition.
You'll bring Eren outside?
Yes.
I'd like Eren's control over his Titan power,
and his worth to mankind
to be judged based on the
results of that expedition.
Handling Eren Jaeger...
Can you do it, Levi?
I'm certain I could kill him.
The problem is that there'll be no alternative.
I've made my decision.
A Few Days Later
The former Survey Corps HQ.
As an old castle that was renovated to be our base,
it definitely looks extravagant.
But since it's this far away
from the walls and the river,
it really wasn't something we needed.
I never imagined we'd be keeping
you in that old decoration.
Don't get ahead of yourself, recruit.
Excuse me?
You may be a Titan or whatever,
but a pissy brat like you being under
Lance Corporal Levi's watch—
This is what you get for
yapping away on horseback.
First impressions are crucial.
That recruit was scared stiff.
Say, that's not how you usually talk, is it?
If... If that's your idea of
imitating Lance Corporal Levi,
could you seriously stop it?
Then again, it's not like
it was similar in any way.
Are you trying to keep me down, Petra?
You haven't gone through the
proper steps to act as my wife.
If only you had bit your tongue off and died...
These people are the Survey
Corps' Special-Ops Squad,
a.k.a. The Levi Squad.
They're all elites that were
hand-picked by Lance Corporal Levi.
And so...
if I go berserk, they'll be the ones to kill me.
There are weeds everywhere.
This place is a mess.
It's been a while, after all.
The inside's probably covered in dust.
Now that's a problem we can't overlook.
We'll get to work immediately.
The upper floor is clean now.
Which of the rooms should I stay in?
You're to stay in the basement.
The basement again?
Obviously.
You've yet to gain full control over yourself.
If you accidentally transform into a Titan,
we can restrain you as long
as you're underground.
That was one of the conditions given
to us in exchange for your custody.
It's a rule to be followed.
I'll take a look upstairs.
Eren, you finish up here.
Understood.
An expedition to establish a base
for a supply chain in thirty days, huh?
And you want us to bring the
newly graduated recruits along.
That's assuming any of them enlist.
Regardless, I'd have to say this seems too rushed.
Eren's current position is only temporary.
We need to prove to Central that he's
beneficial to mankind as soon as possible.
Otherwise, the Military Police
Brigade might interfere again—
You can't be honest, even with me, Erwin?
You're as sharp as ever, Mike.
I'm still not at your level though.
I'll tell you when the time is right.
Ready to start, Eren?
Once we're ready, we'll fire a smoke signal.
What you do after that is up to you.
Understood!
This dry well will be able to restrain
a Titan even if it's out of control.
Probably.
We've been studying captured
Titans like Sawney and Bean,
but today, Eren is here to help!
How exciting...
That's the signal.
Controlling a Titan...
I haven't done that since sealing the wall.
If I go berserk again,
I might be killed by the Levi Squad, huh?
I wonder if he didn't see the signal.
No.
We weren't even particularly
certain of this in the first place.
Hey, Eren!
The experiment's on hold.
Is something wrong?
Hange...
I can't turn into a Titan.
The wounds you got from
biting yourself aren't healing?
Yes.
If you can't turn into a Titan,
sealing Wall Maria and all
is nothing but a dream.
This is an order.
Do something about it.
Sir.
Don't be so depressed, Eren.
But...
Well, this just means you're
more human than we thought.
I prefer this to hurrying
matters and losing lives.
This wasn't meaningless.
You all right?
Yes.
Whoa...
What happened?!
Why now?!
Calm down.
Lance Corporal Levi!
This is...
I'm telling you to calm down.
All of you.
Eren...
What's the meaning of this?!
Sir?
Why'd you transform without permission?
Eld, hold on.
Prove to us that you're not
our—no, mankind's enemy.
It's your responsibility to do so!
Don't you so much as dare twitch that arm!
The moment you do, your head will roll!
Oluo! I'm telling you to calm down.
Lance Corporal!
Please step away from Eren!
You're too close!
No, you're the ones who should step away.
Stand down.
Why?!
My instincts tell me so.
Well, Eren?!
Say something!
I'm—
Don't make any funny moves!
Prove it already!
Eren!
I'm not sure what's—
Answer me!
You think we can't kill you?!
I'm serious! Hurry up!
You hear me?!
Look, I'll do it!
To mankind, you're—
Please shut up for a minute!
Eren!
Can I touch that arm?!
Hey, is it okay?
It's okay, right?
I'm just gonna touch it!
Hange!
Wait a second!
H...
Hot!
It's damn hot when there's no skin!
It's super hot!
Squad Leader!
You're being too reckless!
Say, isn't it hot for you, Eren?
How exactly are you connected to that arm?
I really want to see!
That's right.
I have to pull my arm out quickly.
H-Hey, Eren! No funny business!
Huh?!
Wait, Eren, that's too soon!
There's so much more I...
Lance Corporal...
How do you feel?
Not... too good.
Sorry for the delay.
They finally let me go.
Explaining to the higher-ups took some time.
Well, anyway,
take a look at this.
A teaspoon?
Yes.
Eren's Titan arm was holding onto this.
And for some reason, there's no
deformation from heat or pressure.
Does anything come to mind?
I believe I was trying to pick
that up when I transformed.
I see.
Then that could explain why you weren't
able to turn into a Titan before.
"Kill the Titans."
"Defend against the cannon."
"Lift the boulder."
In every instance, you had a clear
goal before you transformed.
It's likely that self-injury
isn't the trigger on its own;
you need some sort of objective as well.
But still...
Turning into a Titan to pick up a spoon...
What the hell's up with that?
So basically, you didn't act
against orders on purpose, right?
Yes.
Wait, what are you doing?!
That hurts...
This is tough.
Eren, I'm surprised you
can bite yourself like that.
It was the wrong call on our part.
This is our modest way of apologizing.
Not that it really makes a difference though.
Our job is to keep you in check, after all.
We made no mistakes about that!
Don't get too cocky, brat!
I'm sorry, Eren.
We were too on edge.
You must be upset by our indiscretion.
But, despite that...
As we rely on you,
we also want you to rely on us.
So...
believe... in us.
Is Squad Leader Hange here?!
The experiment subjects...
Both of the Titans were killed!
Sawney! Bean!
Tell me...
Tell me this isn't true!
Our valuable experiment subjects...
Was it a soldier?
Yes.
The culprit's still on the loose.
Apparently, it all happened before sunrise.
When a guard noticed, they got away with
their three-dimensional maneuver device.
Sawney!
What's going on...?
Let's go.
The Military Police Brigade will take over here.
R-Right.
What can you see?
Who do you think the enemy is?
Sorry, forget I asked.
When's the last time the shaft was replaced?
Six days ago, after the cleaning operation.
She checks out.
Okay, next!
You there.
I'm Krista Lenz of the 42nd Squad.
We'll inspect your gear.
So you can be punished for killing a Titan too?
As strange as it sounds,
those were valuable specimens.
Even so, why are they searching
for the culprit amongst us recruits?
Yeah, everyone's exhausted from
cleaning up the battlefield until today.
The culprit must've really hated the Titans.
Yeah.
But in this case, they pretty
much helped the Titans out.
Their lust for revenge may have been sated,
but mankind will suffer for it.
I'm an idiot, so I think I get it.
Before I saw a Titan, I seriously planned
to enlist in the Survey Corps.
But now, I'm not sure.
Today's the day we have to decide too.
Is Jean seriously...
Are you really going to join the Survey Corps?
Yeah.
Because of what happened to Marco...
But... aren't you scared?
What? Of course I'm scared
of joining the Survey Corps.
I'm different from that reckless idiot.
Eren, huh?
He's already in the Survey Corps, isn't he?
You know, I'm not putting my life on
the line because I was persuaded to.
At the very least, this isn't a decision
someone else can make for me.
Damn.
Hey, Annie.
What did you think?
Jean of all people said he'd
enlist in the Survey Corps.
Nothing really.
You're set on the Military Police Brigade, right?
I should go there too, shouldn't I?
Say, if someone told you to die, would you?
What do you mean?
Of course not.
Then, why not decide for yourself?
Armin, how about you?
I think that if there's a legitimate reason,
there might be no other choice but to die.
I wouldn't like it though.
I see.
So you've decided.
Seriously?
Armin, you too?
You're weak, but you do have guts.
Th-Thanks.
Annie, you're actually pretty nice, huh?
I mean, it seems like you don't
want us to join the Survey Corps.
Is there a reason why you want to join
the Military Police Brigade though?
Not really.
I just want...
to save myself.
Everyone!
Oluo,
may I go speak with my friends for a bit?
Jeez, just go already.
Hey, Mikasa, Armin!
Eren!
It feels like it's been forever!
Eren, did they do anything terrible to you?
Like inspecting every bit of your body
or causing you mental anguish?
No, nothing like that.
That shorty went way too far.
I'll pay him back in kind someday.
You're not talking about
Lance Corporal Levi, are you?
Hey, Eren.
It's been a while!
Oh wow, you're all here?
But...
Are you guys here because...
Don't tell me, you enlisted?
Why else would we be here?
Then, the only ones who picked the Military
Police Brigade are Jean, Annie, and Marco?
You're kidding me...
You too?!
Marco's dead.
What... did you just say?
Did you say Marco's dead?
It seems like not everyone
dies a dramatic death.
We don't even know how he went down.
He died alone, without
anyone seeing or knowing.
Marco...
Hey, Eren.
I heard that, as a Titan, you tried to kill Mikasa.
Mind explaining yourself?
That's wrong.
Eren was trying to kill a fly—
I didn't ask you.
I think it's true.
In my Titan form, I tried to kill Mikasa.
So you don't really remember it, huh?
In other words, you weren't aware
you had that power until now,
and you lack the means to control it.
Yeah, that's right.
Hear that, guys?
That's the situation we're in.
We'll probably die without Eren
ever knowing, just like Marco did.
Jean, why are you driving
Eren into a corner like this?
You know, Mikasa...
Not everyone can blindly die for Eren
like you, without anything in return.
We expect something out of Eren.
Let us know what to expect.
And whether it's worth our lives.
So, Eren!
We're seriously counting on you, okay?
Yeah...
Hey, recruits, gather up!
Your uniforms are here!
Commander, we're departing soon.
We've lured away all nearby Titans!
Thirty seconds until the gate is open!
In mere moments, mankind
will advance once again.
Show us what you're made of!
Open the gate!
Forward!
We now begin the 57th expedition!
Advance!
A 10-meter-class approaching
from ahead, on the left!
While I'm quite interested in
the contents of its stomach,
I'll leave this to the support squad!
Damn.
Too shallow.
Defend the ranks!
Don't falter!
Leave it to the support squad and advance!
Forward! Forward!
Oluo, can they...
Can my comrades beat the Titans?
Huh?
What the hell have you been
doing this past month?
Listen, you damn brat.
During an expedition,
the point is to avoid the Titans if possi—
Assume the long-distance scouting formation!
Later, Armin.
Don't wet yourself even if you run into a Titan!
Right.
Same to you.
Line 3-3: Relay
The vanguard will form a semicircle.
Although we're spread out,
Line 5-Center: Standby
stay within eyesight of someone on all sides,
in fixed distances from one another.
Line 2-5: Relay
Extend survey and relay range as far as possible.
Line 3-4: Relay
Line 2-4: Relay
We'll be fine.
Calm down.
Line 1-8: Scout
Line 2-Center: Command
Line 2-3: Relay
Red... Red smoke signal...
Blouse! This way!
Damn!
Looks like we missed one.
Let's draw it toward us.
Blouse! Come this way!
I'll handle it.
Withdraw!
Sir!
Squad Leader...
Get back in position!
He's out of gas.
Something's strange...
It's been a while since the red
smoke signal was fired,
but we've yet to regroup.
Don't tell me...
A black smoke signal?
Is one ignoring nearby people and heading
straight for the formation's center?
There's no doubt about it.
It's...
an Abnormal!
Damn, guess we have no other choice.
Sys, you get its nape!
I'll stop it in its tracks!
Roger!
Arlert should be over there.
I don't want to let a new
recruit run into one of these.
We'll kill it here!
Now, Sys!
Squad Leader Ness did it!
We got it, huh?
You came for me?
That's why you're my favorite.
I love you, Shallot!
Again?
What's the right flank scout squad doing?
If it ignored them and came this way,
then it must be an Abnormal too.
Here we go again.
Sys, let's do it once more.
Sir.
But really, to think we have
to do this twice in a row...
And it looks like it's a 14-meter-class at least.
This one will be tough.
What's that?
It's so fast!
Don't let it get to Arlert!
Sys!
Sir!
Wh-Who is she?!
Why?!
This is bad. What do I do?
I'll die too.
I'll be killed!
Go! Run away!
She's not going to kill me?
What just happened?
She took off my hood...
and looked...
at my face?
Armin!
Reiner!
Hey, can you stand?
Well, for starters, you're dead meat if
you don't have a horse outside the walls.
Hurry!
Right!
From the right flank?
Does that mean we got hit
so bad we can't continue?
It seems we lost part of
the right flank scout squad.
Hordes of Titans came.
That's the same direction she came from.
No way...
Was she leading the Titans here?
An Abnormal?
No, she's a human controlling a Titan's body.
What?!
The moment her vitals were targeted,
she flung Sys to the ground, crushing him.
Regular Titans will only consume.
I get the feeling she's looking for someone.
Assuming that's true,
she must be searching for...
Eren!
Eren?
But the Levi Squad, which Eren's in,
should've been in charge of the
right flank that she passed through.
No.
They should be in the safest spot of this formation.
So I guess they're somewhere in the center rear.
Armin, we don't have time to think right now.
At this distance, we might still be able to draw her attention.
We might be able to buy enough time for everyone else to retreat.
Jean.
I... know what needs to be done now!
Not to mention, this is the job we chose!
Lend me a hand!
Armin!
She covered her nape.
Jean!
Damn, I can't get away!
I'm going to die!
Jean!
Avenge that reckless idiot!
Armin?
She stopped moving?
That's the one!
That's the one that killed him!
He really ended up dying on the right flank!
Avenge that reckless idiot!
Reiner?
It crushed my best friend with one stomp!
I saw his body stuck under its foot!
He's going straight for the nape?
Wait, that might work!
H-Hey...
Reiner, you...
We bought enough time, right?!
Let's get away from her already!
If she doesn't eat people,
she shouldn't follow us!
Look.
The giant bitch got scared
and is running home now!
What... Why?
That's toward the center rear.
Could she be...
heading toward Eren?
Damn it, why?
Reiner's horse came back,
so why is mine still missing?
Armin.
Hey, Armin!
Looks like someone's coming.
With two horses, at that.
That's...
Krista!
Guys! You okay?!
It's my horse!
Whoa, whoa!
Calm down, Bufpart.
It was extremely panicked when it ran to me.
Did you fight a Titan?
Armin!
That injury...
Are you okay?
Yeah, somehow.
I'm glad our smoke signal got through to you.
I happened to be nearby,
and Jean's horse was with me.
Even horses seem fond of you,
so I think you have some special charisma.
You saved us.
But I'm so glad...
I'm so glad you all managed to survive.
A deity...
A goddess...
I want to marry her.
Anyway, we need to hurry back to the formation.
Oh, right. Withdrawal orders
should be relayed soon.
A green smoke signal?!
Looks like the operation's continuing
with just a change in direction.
No way.
Shouldn't we be withdrawing?
What's going through
Commander Erwin's head?!
Don't tell me the command squad
didn't see the smoke signals.
Whatever the reason, it's obvious
what we should do next.
Let's obey the order.
Green smoke signal.
Oluo, you fire it.
Roger that.
It seems like everything's
going smoothly for now.
However...
is that really the case?
Reporting in!
It's an operation report!
The right flank's scouts
have suffered heavy losses!
Scouting ability is crippled!
Please relay this report to the left!
Hear that, Petra?
Go!
Sir!
The right flank?
That's where Armin should be.
A black smoke signal?
An Abnormal!
Eren, you fire it.
Sir!
What a mess.
We let them too far into the formation.
The Titans are right over there.
Whoever it is fighting under that smoke signal...
The right flank is all but annihilated, you say?!
And we're still not withdrawing?
Line 3-1: Transport
Why?!
I don't know!
Commander's orders!
At any rate, relay it to the left!
What's going on?
Line 1-13: Scout
We've been heading east for a while now.
The old town area should
be to the south though.
Line 1-5: Scout
At this rate, we'll run straight there.
Yeah, it's in plain sight now.
The forest of giant trees.
Looks like Titans have passed through here.
There's nothing growing on the road.
The wagons should have no problem.
Relay this to the rear.
Only the center line—the wagon
escort squad—will enter the forest.
Sir!
Um, Squad Leader.
It looks like the center line
is following the forest path.
At this rate, we'll run into the forest.
We're going around.
S-Sir!
All soldiers, halt!
All right, recruits.
Listen up!
We'll now position ourselves to intercept.
Draw your blades and wait in the treetops.
If a Titan attempts to enter
the forest, stop it at all costs!
Huh?
But, Squad Leader, why—
Shut up and obey!
Are you serious?
What the hell is going on?
5-meter-class incoming!
Lance Corporal.
Lance Corporal Levi!
What?
"What", you say?
This is a forest!
If only the center line enters the forest like this,
we won't know if a Titan is approaching!
It seems like something's
coming from the right,
but how will we avoid it
or protect the wagons?
Quit whining about the obvious.
There's clearly no way
we can do either of those.
A black smoke signal!
It's right behind us!
It's the thing that came from the right, huh?
Everyone, draw your blades.
It'll be over in an instant once it appears.
Faster!
It's fast!
There's no way to avoid it in this forest!
It's catching up!
Lance Corporal, let's switch to
three-dimensional maneuvers!
Lance Corporal!
You're not getting away!
Reinforcements from the rear!
I have to turn into a Titan and fight!
What are you doing, Eren?!
That should only be done when
your life is in grave danger.
Didn't you promise us that?
Eren!
You're not in the wrong.
Feel free to do it.
I don't know the right answer.
I never have.
Even if I believed in myself
and the decisions of the comrades
who've earned my trust,
the result was always a complete mystery.
That's why...
you should just do your best to
make a decision you won't regret.
Eren!
Believe in us.
Hurry up!
Decide already!
I'll keep going!
Target is accelerating!
Faster!
We'll outrun it!
Fire!
After securing the horses up ahead,
switch to three-dimensional maneuvers.
I'll act separately for a while.
Eld will take charge of the squad.
Could they be...
capturing that Titan... alive?
It sounds like something
is going on inside the forest.
It's just as I thought.
I think the commander
was planning to capture that female Titan from the beginning, and baited her into this forest.
To be precise, it's to capture the human inside it.
Commander Erwin's goal...
was that all along.
That's what it was, right?
But new recruits like me aside,
why did they not tell Survey
Corps veterans like all of you?
Shut it!
Are you implying that we're not trusted by the Commander and the Lance Corporal?!
No, it's just as Eren said.
I think the Commander had a
reason for keeping this from us.
A transforming human...
Or perhaps, a spy who's working
with such a person is amongst us.
But how many soldiers do you think died?
If we knew that there was a Titan spy in our ranks,
things should have gone differently.
No, he wasn't mistaken.
The lives of a hundred comrades
or the lives of all those within the walls...
The Commander made his choice.
He decided to cast off the
lives of a hundred comrades.
Hey, won't you come out already?
We don't have all day, you know.
If I'm not mistaken, you killed
my subordinates in various ways,
but did you take joy in any of it?
Oh, right.
There's something I want to ask.
Is it all right if I sever your hands and feet?
They'll grow right back, won't they?
I'm talking about your real body.
It'll be a problem if you die, after all.
Why you...
That was quite the scare.
Erwin, it smells.
Direction?
Multiple, from every direction.
All at once.
They're targeting the female Titan?
Titans from every direction!
All soldiers, engage the enemy!
Defend the female Titan!
It's no good!
All soldiers, retreat!
Assume the formation.
Return to Karanese District!
We've been had.
Just look at you.
Don't tell me you—
This shows the enemy was prepared
to abandon everything.
To think they'd have themselves devoured
to avoid leaking information...
I'll call up my squad.
Wait, Levi.
Resupply your blades and gas.
We're short on time.
What I have on hand should last.
Why?
It's an order.
Obey.
Understood, Erwin.
I'll trust your judgment.
Looks like we're done here.
Prepare to withdraw!
Did we really get them?
It's all thanks to you.
I didn't do much.
You believed in us, remember?
It's because you stuck with us then
that we arrived at this result.
It's rather difficult to make
the right decision, you know.
Oh.
That must be from Lance Corporal Levi.
We'll meet up with the Lance Corporal!
Erwin.
Why'd you have Levi resupply?
We don't have time.
The female Titan was devoured.
But... did you see the person inside get eaten?
I didn't.
Don't tell me...
Exactly.
Just as you deduced before,
if they're a type that can move to some
extent even after transforming...
Furthermore,
assuming they had a three-dimensional
maneuver device equipped...
Lance Corporal Levi?
No, that's not him!
Who're you?!
Wait, what happened?!
Gunther!
Eren, don't stop!
Keep moving!
Gunther is...
Who is it?!
Protect Eren!
Is it the female Titan?
Or were there others?
The female Titan?
No way... How?!
Bingo, huh?
Here it comes!
It's the female Titan!
Damn, why you...
I'll do it this time!
I'll kill it!
Don't!
The three of us will take
down the female Titan.
You continue heading to HQ at full speed!
What's with you?!
You doubting our skills?!
Is that so, Eren?
Are we really that unreliable?
I believe my squad will be victorious!
Good luck!
We blinded it.
It won't be able to see for at least a minute!
We'll finish it before that!
To hell with capturing it!
We'll kill it now!
Die a dog's death here!
Down with this damn Titan!
We'll slice all of the muscles around your shoulders
so you won't be able to hold up your arms!
Slice them apart...
And those arms...
Will drop!
They're down!
Now the neck!
Once the muscles supporting its neck are cut...
we can get its nape!
Your nape is mi—
Eld!
How?
It can't possibly see already!
Not even thirty seconds have...
Just one eye?
It prioritized one eye to heal faster?
How is that possible...
Petra!
Right yourself already!
Petra, hurry up!
Hey...
Die!
Why?
My blade won't go through.
I'll...
kill it!
Eren?
Mikasa!
This voice...
Don't tell me...
Because I made the wrong decision...
Because I wanted to believe in my comrades...
everyone died!
If only I had believed in myself
from the start and fought...
If only I had killed her from the start!
I'll rip you apart.
I'll split you wide open...
Tear you to bloody shreds...
Mangle every last chunk...
And devour it all!
Eren!
Wait...
Eren...
Don't go...
Give Eren... back!
Give him back!
Why won't the blade go through?
Wait!
Wh-What're you...
Fall back for now.
Maintain this distance.
We'll stick to a single objective.
First, we'll give up on killing the female Titan.
But they've killed so many of our comrades!
As long as it can reinforce
its skin, we have no chance.
Trust my judgment.
We'll place our hopes on Eren being alive
and rescue him before it gets out of the forest.
I'll hack away at it.
You draw its attention!
He's fast...
So fast that it doesn't have time to reinforce!
I can get the nape.
I can kill it!
Stop!
Eren!
Hey!
We're pulling out!
Eren...
He should be fine.
Alive, at least!
Filthy though.
Don't worry about it anymore.
We're retreating.
Aren't there fewer of them than in the morning?
They've lost quite a few.
Yet another disaster.
They made a real racket when they left
in the morning, but they're back already.
What'd they go for?
Eren, you shouldn't get up yet.
Cool!
The Survey Corps is amazing!
They get beaten so badly,
but they keep fighting!
Commander Erwin! Answer us!
Did this expedition achieve something
worthy of the sacrifices?!
Are you convinced the dead have no regrets?!
The expedition's expenses and
casualties were more than enough
to utterly humiliate the
Survey Corps' power base.
Those responsible, including Erwin,
were summoned to the capital,
and Eren's new supervisor was chosen.
Keep at it, Annie!
Now that's my girl.
What are you doing, Annie?!
No breaks!
Wall Sina
Eastern Walled Town
Huh? You haven't heard?
Seems like the Titan brat and his chief
superiors were summoned to the capital.
Stohess District
They'll be coming through here today.
That so?
Well, I'm sure they'll end up
dissecting him this time.
Stohess District
Military Police Brigade Branch Office
Looks like she's finally up.
You know, you look so scary when
sleeping that I didn't dare wake you up.
Sorry about that, Annie.
You've been slacking off too much lately.
What?
Mad already, are we? Come on...
Just let her be.
Annie's from Trost District of all places.
She's the only one with battle
experience in this branch.
You can't expect her to recover so soon.
I mean, she's fresh out of living hell.
I told you to cut that stuff out.
Today, you'll be assigned to do
something outside your usual duties.
That's why I had you assemble here.
It's about the group of Survey Corps members
that were summoned to the capital.
They'll be passing through
the town's central street today.
The Military Police Brigade HQ
is in charge of escorting them,
so we're only tasked with helping
on their leg through town.
Move alongside the escort squad
and work to bolster their security.
That is all.
Annie.
Hey.
You're really part of the Military
Police Brigade now, huh?
Armin...
What's with the outfit?
I'm a baggage carrier.
I'm using this rain coat to hide my
three-dimensional maneuver device.
See?
What for?
Annie, will you give us a hand
in helping Eren escape?
Where to?
After rebelling against the monarchy,
where within the walls will you run to?
We're only going to hide out temporarily.
We don't plan to oppose them head-on.
It'll be reported as an act of rebellion
by part of the Survey Corps,
but that'll buy us time
during which we'll prepare what's needed to
overturn the commission of inquiry's decision.
Without fail.
Does something that convenient exist?
Any leads?
Sorry, I can't say.
I hate to tell you this,
but it's out of the question.
I won't say anything though, so do what you can.
Annie!
Please!
At this rate, Eren will be killed!
Ignorant people, for their own self-preservation,
are unwittingly attempting to set
humanity on a path to extermination!
I know this isn't convincing.
But even so...
all we can do is take a huge gamble now!
Say...
Do I really seem like such
a good person to you?
A good person?
Well...
I don't particularly like that term.
I mean, that just...
seems like something you'd call
someone who's of use to you.
And I don't think there's anyone
who's of use to everyone.
That said, if you don't agree to cooperate...
you'd be a bad person in my eyes, right?
Fine.
I'm in.
We got through more easily than I expected.
That's the Military Police Brigade for you.
It's clear they work hard day after day.
Quit looking around.
Now we'll just have to hope they
don't notice it's Jean in there.
Can't expect that to work long.
The two of us look nothing alike, after all.
Don't worry too much.
Both of you have a villainous glint in
your eyes and similar, evil-looking faces.
I don't have a horse face like him.
Hey, if I had decided not to help you,
how were you planning to get over the wall?
We planned to get past using
three-dimensional maneuver devices.
That's so reckless.
To begin with, running before
entering Stohess District
would've saved you a lot of trouble, no?
Why here and now?
I predicted the complicated terrain in this city
would make the switch more likely to succeed.
And rather than being openly defiant,
feigning obedience would decrease suspicion
and buy us more time to escape.
I see.
That makes sense.
There it is.
Here?
Yeah.
We go through here.
The ruins of an underground city that
was planned and abandoned still lie here.
This path continues up
until near the outer gate.
Really? That's amazing.
Annie?
What're you doing?
You're not about to tell us that you're
scared of dark, narrow spaces, are you?
That's right.
I'm scared.
I'm sure a brave and reckless idiot like you
wouldn't understand the
feelings of a frail girl like me.
A girl who can flip a massive guy
around in mid-air isn't frail.
Quit joking and let's get moving.
No, I won't go.
I'm scared of going that way.
If we're not moving above
ground, you're on your own.
What the hell are you saying?!
Get over here already!
Enough screwing around!
Eren, keep it down.
It's fine, isn't it, Mikasa?
Since for a while now,
there hasn't been anyone
around for some reason.
Honestly.
I'm hurt.
Just when did you come to
look at me with such eyes,
Armin?
Annie, why...
did you have Marco's
three-dimensional maneuver device?
Down to the slightest scratches and dents...
Because we maintained our equipment together...
I recognized them all.
I see.
It was...
something I found.
But if you suspected something a month ago,
why didn't you do anything?
Because I still can't believe it.
I wanted to believe I was mistaken.
That's why.
But... you too...
Back then... Because you didn't kill me...
it came down to this, don't you see?
Yeah, I completely agree.
I never imagined you'd end up
cornering me to this extent.
Back then...
Why... I wonder...
Hey, Annie!
There's still a chance you're an idiot
who has terrible timing with stupid
jokes that you carelessly throw
into the conversation.
Regardless, just get down here.
You can prove something by
simply stepping down here!
So come here and prove it!
I can't go there.
I've... failed to become a warrior.
I'm telling you, this isn't funny at all!
Let's talk this through, Annie!
We can still discuss—
I've had enough.
I can't listen to this anymore.
It's a waste of my time.
I'll slice you to shreds again...
Female Titan!
Armin, it's great that I was
a good person to you, huh?
Your gamble paid off this time.
But now...
I'll see if my bet...
pays off!
Eren!
Mikasa!
We were too late!
Annie...
Our plan is for the day after tomorrow,
during our passage to the capital where
we are to answer the summons—
at Stohess District.
It will be our first and last chance.
We'll wager everything on this plan.
The plan is as follows:
As we pass through Stohess District,
Eren will act as bait and lure the target
to this underground passage.
Upon bringing them to the lowest level,
judging by their size and power,
their movements should be fairly
restricted, even if they transform.
Sir.
So the main target is, without a doubt,
in Stohess District, correct?
Yes.
The target is part of the
Military Police Brigade.
The Military Police Brigade?
Armin was the one who inferred that.
According to him,
the Female Titan may be responsible
for killing the two Titans we'd captured
and is possibly a member of the
104th Training Corps, like you.
W-Wait just a second.
The name of the female suspected
to be the Female Titan is...
Wait...
Annie...
Leonhart.
Sh... Shoot.
Damn it.
That ring...
So she saw through me from the start, after all!
She even noticed the ambush we planned too.
Hey!
Status of the primary capture?
Unsuccessful!
Please switch over to Plan B!
Wha—
She stomped through?!
We have to save them!
Eren, get back!
Hey, Mikasa!
Is the Female Titan trying to show
she doesn't need Eren alive?
If we stay like this, there's no telling when we're going to be crushed!
I'll figure something out,
like how I was able to block cannon fire that time.
Just follow me!
He—
Here we go.
Stick close to me.
Huh?
Again?!
No way...
At a time like this...
Damn, it hurts!
If you don't have a clear objective,
you can't transform, right?
Visualize and focus on it again.
I know!
But...
Deep down...
you're still hesitant to fight Annie, aren't you?
Eren...
Don't tell me you're still thinking
that we're mistaking Annie as the Female Titan.
Did you not see what happened earlier?
That woman's the one who
killed our comrades, right?
Do you still not see that?
Shut up!
Can't you see I'm trying?!
Annie's the Female Titan?
Why...
Why do you think that, Armin?
The Female Titan knew what
Eren looked like from the start.
Furthermore, she reacted upon hearing
Eren's nickname, "the reckless idiot",
when only our generation
should know about it.
And above all else,
Annie was likely responsible for the murders
of Sawney and Bean, the test subjects.
How can you be sure about that?
Advanced techniques were required
to pull off those murders,
so she must've used her three-dimensional
maneuver device, which she's proficient with.
Yeah...
but that's what the equipment inspection was for.
Annie came out clean.
That's because the device
Annie had was Marco's.
Huh?
Couldn't you have just been seeing things?
No, that was definitely something I—
Hey, kid, we've already heard that.
Isn't there anything else?
Not that I know of.
I believe that Annie's face
resembles the Female Titan's.
Huh?
What're you saying?
Eren, has anything come to
mind after hearing all this?
When you fought hand-to-hand
with the Female Titan,
did it use any techniques
that are unique to Annie?
You realize now, don't you?
The Female Titan is Annie.
In that case, shouldn't you be fighting?
Or...
is some particular emotion hindering you?
Huh?
I have a plan.
Mikasa and I will exit from that hole
and the entrance simultaneously.
Doing so will force Annie to focus on one of us.
At that time, Eren, follow the one she ignored.
Wait!
Wouldn't that mean one of you will die?!
Staying here will get all three of us killed.
Mikasa, get in position!
Okay, I'll take the front.
Mikasa!
Armin!
How?
How can you two still fight?!
How?!
What choice do we have?
The world is a cruel place.
Eren!
Don't let the Female Titan get away!
We'll stop her from getting out no matter what!
Eren!
I'm here to save you!
Open your eyes!
Something's off.
There seemed to be some sort of explosion and—
Nile.
Dispatch all your soldiers at once.
We should assume a Titan has appeared.
What are you saying?!
This is Wall Sina, you know!
It's impossible for a Titan to appear here!
Wait!
Don't move, Jaeger!
I've had enough of playing doppelgänger!
Don't ever call me that again, retard!
Commander, let me go too!
Get your equipment from the 4th squad.
Yes, sir!
It's good to be enthusiastic, but don't
forget to guard your own life.
Sir.
Erwin!
What's going on—
Everyone that can move, follow me!
We'll join the Female Titan capture squad!
Levi, you stay put.
You dislike meaningless death, don't you?
Yeah, that's right.
Whether it's mine or others'.
It's a Titan! A Titan's here!
Why here of all places?!
Didn't they seal the wall—
Eren!
Hey, what're you doing?!
Jean!
Eren is under this!
Huh?!
Shouldn't he have transformed already?
He wasn't able to.
The fact that Annie's the Titan
might be what's hindering him.
What?
We'll have to do something about her first!
Eren.
People who are unable to abandon anything
will fail to bring about any change.
If it's required to overcome monsters,
one must toss aside their humanity.
I'm sure Annie is capable of that.
those who can do so are victorious!
Annie!
If you don't kill me this time,
you won't be able to make excuses like
"I'll see if my bet pays off!"
Armin, this way!
All right!
People who are unable to abandon anything
will fail to bring about any change.
I know.
When the time came...
I clung to my comrades and the
bonds we shared, and failed.
Think back.
I'll... exterminate.
No...
I'll kill!
I don't have time to think about
whether it's right or not!
Just start by moving!
Don't get caught up in ideals!
Yes...
Mikasa!
The world's a cruel place!
What is it this time?!
Eren!
Eren...
A Titan?
Why here?
It's level ground!
The Female Titan is approaching level ground.
We can't use our gear there!
Split into two groups and go around!
Yes, sir!
Why's a Titan—
Annie...
You always looked disinterested.
But, only when you were demonstrating your
hand-to-hand techniques, you looked lively to me.
You seemed like a terrible liar.
That's what I thought.
Hey, Annie.
What in the world are you fighting for?
What great cause justifies killing people?
Annie...
Annie!
At least know that Dad will be on your side.
I'll kill the Titans,
not sparing a single one.
Eren!
That's...
Stop!
We don't know if Eren can recognize you now.
Hey... What...
What, the wall...
She's climbing it?!
This is bad!
She'll get away at this rate!
Oh no you don't!
Annie...
fall.
Annie.
I was wrong.
I won't ask you to forgive me now.
But... I just have one favor to ask.
Turn the entire world against you if you have to.
I...
will destroy everything in the world!
Even if everyone in the world comes to hate you...
At least know that Dad will be on your side.
Oh, no! He'll eat her real body too!
Eren, stop!
Eren!
I'm...
free.
So promise me...
that you'll come back.
What happened?
What the...
They're fusing?
Eren!
Don't eat our valuable witness.
You idiot!
Erwin, we have quite a few concerns
about the plan this time around.
If you had a target confirmed, why didn't you
seek the Military Police Brigade's assistance?
District Chief, there was a need to carry out
the plan with only those who could prove
that they're not one of the Female Titan's allies,
who are known to be lurking about.
I see.
So, do you have some sort
of proof that you prevented
mankind's demise through
this extremely costly plan?
I don't believe you can get anything
out of Annie Leonhart as she is now.
Indeed.
I agree.
So in other words,
this was all for nothing?
Eren.
Are you feeling okay?
Yeah...
Okay enough to feel sick.
Annie's still sealed away, I hear.
Yeah.
Damn it.
We pull off such a large-scale
operation and gain nothing?
She went that far to withhold information.
Annie, I mean.
Yeah.
I failed at the end.
When I saw Annie, I couldn't move anymore.
Armin Arlert,
Jean Kirstein,
I'm here to question you.
Okay.
Us first, huh?
Well, see you later.
Yeah.
Back then, I thought it felt great.
It was as if I felt refreshed
to have my body torn apart.
Enough for me to think
I might as well die then.
Eren.
I'm not thinking that anymore.
I'm glad you... came back.
Eat.
However,
I believe I've grasped a great potential
with which to save mankind.
Compared to the time when we couldn't even
fathom humans transforming into Titans,
we've come a long way by
restraining one of our enemies.
Yes.
They're definitely out there.
Let us bring all of them to their knees—
all of the Titans within the walls.
Now it's our turn to advance upon them!
See it on the people's faces everywhere
The Survey Corps and Eren Jaeger's
summons to the capital were put on hold,
Black'n'blue but they won't throw the towel in
And let go of a dream
and custody of Annie Leonhart,
who is being held deep underground,
Man, women, child prepare to bleed
was given to the Survey Corps.
However...
for mankind to realize what
they're being caged by,
Were we born to lose and let Goliath win?
more time and sacrifices were still needed.
Heavy air and screaming as you pull the pin
Our world is collapsing but we can rebuild it
A 100 more years in the fire
Do you believe that we can just kill them all?
Do you believe that we can conquer this?
Can't delete all the mess that I have seen
Fall in the fire but these burns will heal you
Gonna take your knives and skills they must be honed
Show your mom your lives and give a dog a bone
Just wait for centuries
Man, woman, child long to be free
When we die we ask our brothers one more time
Hey, look!
If the meaning of our lives was worth a dime
What? Inside the wall...
Don't tell me...
Our world oxidizes but will surprise us
It's a Titan!
Squad Leader, your orders?
A 100 more years in the fire
Huh... What?
hold on just a second...
Do you believe that we can just kill them all?
Do you believe that we can conquer this?
Don't let daylight
shine on that Titan!
Can't delete all the mess that I have seen
Fall in the fire but these burns will heal you
Well, it's time you tell us
now, don't you think?
What is this Titan?
Coming down to show you what to do
Why is there a Titan inside
the wall in the first place?
And why have you people
kept quiet about it?
How to die with honor, dignity
We should delete all the mess out from our sight
I'm a busy man.
What is truth is for me and you
The church and my followers
are in utter chaos,
because of you guys!
I'll charge you on the
amount of damage later!
Don't mess with me!
Squad Leader...?!
Stay away.
Do you know why we,
the Survey Corps soldiers,
repeatedly shed our blood?
It's to get back the freedom
that the Titans stole from us!
Listen.
I'm not asking for a favor.
I'm ordering you. Start talking.
And if you can't,
I'll just go find another.
In any case, I don't think taking
only your life will be enough.
Let go... of me...
Are you sure you want
me to let go right now?
It's useless...
Kill me and learn this for yourself...
Do you believe that we can just kill them all?
We shall carry out our
mission till the very end!
So...
Do you believe that we can conquer this?
let go of me right now!
Can't delete all the mess that I have seen
Fall in the fire but these burns will heal you
Coming down to show you what to do
Squad Leader...
How to die with honor, dignity
Kidding, kidding.
I'm just kidding.
Say, Pastor Nick...
We should delete all the mess out from our sight
What is truth is for me and you
Are all these walls... full of Titans?
‘Shingeki no Kyojin - Movie 2: Wings of Freedom’
Raw Video: neko-raws
Subtitles Compiled by kBaraka
Translation: EveTaku
Translation of New Scenes: Mommoko
Editing, Typesetting, Styling, Timing: kBaraka