♪ If I could escape from fate's predetermined path ♪
♪ And touch the true essence of time and space, the ultimate secret ♪
♪ I'll awaken this extraordinary destiny ♪
♪ And awaken another version of myself ♪
♪ The clearest, most resilient eyes of yours ♪
♪ Crystals filled with infinite power ♪
♪ Unleash my true nature ♪
♪ Take every breath at lightning speed ♪
♪ Shining justice ♪
♪ The only truth in the duel ♪
♪ Now you guys are hearing my cry ♪
♪ My life was full of regrets ♪
♪ Restart ♪
♪ Striving, fighting, honing ♪
♪ Finding the future ♪
♪ Do not just dream it, have a try ♪
♪ Nothing can beat me, bravery's in my chest ♪
♪ I'll smash myself to protect your tenderness ♪
♪ Never bow down again ♪
[Super Cube]
[Episode 7]
Cube.
You detected seven opponents.
Logically, there should be two left upstairs.
Yes.
But just now, one of them suddenly disappeared.
Disappeared?
So... only one left?
As you said,
I'm your only opponent left.
And me, Shan!
Master, their combat power is 7.
Huh? Just a power of 7?
- It's an honor to meet you.
- We are
- Chu Mushan.
Cube, sure you're not mistaken?
His combat power is just 7?
Yes.
But the interior of that puppet is very intricate,
with an intermediate gem inside.
Don't be nervous.
You were on par with a Level-B warrior.
I'm afraid my head is as fragile as an egg to you.
However...
The Way of Nature: Excess is reduced
and deficiency supplemented!
Oh my god, what the hell was that?
Actually, aren't we destined to be archenemies?
You're a daredevil who relies solely on brute strength.
And I
rely on techniques.
Talismans, teleportation, puppetry—pure techniques!
I'm curious to know what will win: your strength
or my sophisticated techniques?
You're really growing on me.
[Eye drops]
Ou-Ou-Ouch! Let go! Stop! It really hurts!
Let go!
If he's an ordinary human,
then my full-force punch...
I can't believe I made the enemy worry about me.
Oops, how awkward.
What the heck? How are you still standing?
To think my Defensive Talisman would be exhausted by just one punch of yours.
You sure are strong.
If I don't get anything out of this fight with you,
I'd have spent all that money for nothing!
Temple of evil ghosts!
Anyone who sees this...
must die!
Shrink the distance!
Shrink! Shrink! Shrink!
So fast?
Dang it!
Having fun, aren't you?
The talisman stuck on your body... Any idea how much it costs?
Who the...
hell cares?
For one,
700 grand!
So heavy!
This is the weight of 3.5 million!
Not bad.
Job well done.
It's over already?
Warfare's really a money-burning game.
What? Where'd you get the damn shovel?
How did he block it?
Surprised, huh?
This is the strength of a locally-made farming shovel that costs a dollar!
Fine, let's play.
I'm gonna add 140 million
to kill you!
This is how we, the Ominous Menaces,
are different from those barbarians of the Million Alliance!
I get it now.
Did my punch give you a concussion?
What?
He can't even mobilize his internal power.
How does he know how to use the distance-shrinkage technique?
Forcing me to use my trump card!
You really are
quite a piece of work.
On you,
there are still five Weight Talismans.
Let's see how long you can hold on.
Why won't he budge?
Have you forgotten I'm now worth 3.5 million?
As they say, you reap what you sow!
Young Master. We should go.
I can't leave yet.
Uncle, I know.
You protect me because
if I, the third son of the Yans, suffer a tragic death,
it'll bring shame on the prestigious family name.
My duty
is to ensure your safety, Young Master.
Uncle.
Don't forget
I still have a trump card to turn the tables.
This is not some reckless revenge.
I risked everything I had
to seize this opportunity.
In that case,
I'll do my very best
to ensure your safety.
Goodbye.
No.
It's farewell.
Although my execution hasn't been perfect,
everything's still under my control.
Wang Xiaoxiu.
Go to hell!
Break!
Break! Break!
What's going on?
Screw you, bastard!
What?
You're beyond crazy, you fool!
Yao...
Yao!
Where is she?
Master.
The enemy's energy dissipated almost instantly.
Not bad.
You fled real fast.
Yao.
I'm coming to save you...
Wait for me!
Is everyone gone?
Shen Yao! Are you there?
You are...
Huo Huan!
Where's Shen Yao?
Don't kill me! Please! Don't kill me!
Tell me where Shen Yao is!
Speak! Where is she?
Yao! Yao! Yao!
I'm here to save you!
Yao, don't be scared. It's fine now.
Run, Xiaoxiu! There's a bomb on this chair.
Once I get up, it'll explode!
Xiaoxiu, save yourself.
You must go now.
Don't worry.
This is nowhere near
the biggest bomb I've met today!
This room's specially modified by Chu Mushan.
Master, you can't teleport in here.
I'm gonna stay here
and watch you two get blown up into mush!
Xiaoxiu!
Cube.
How can I defuse the bomb safely?
Master, cut the wires in order of yellow, blue, green, and red.
It'll just have to detonate in the cube.
Xiaoxiu!
I'm here, Yao.
You're safe now.
I won't... ever let...
Xiaoxiu!
Why?
Why didn't it explode?
Xiaoxiu!
Nothing will wreck my plan this time!
What's going on?
Damn it! I can't move!
I didn't expect it to blow up the intermediate gem in the puppet!
Young Master.
The dangerous one is here.
We need to leave.
Yao...
What on earth is going on?
My... Yao...
Yao!
Hang in there.
I'll get you...
to the hospital now...
You can't save her.
No!
We made a pact.
I'll protect her forever.
You can't even save yourself.
[Caution: Please do not try this at home]
Bastard! Give Yao back to me!
Yao!
You know nothing
about her and the superhuman world.
I was the cause of this.
I'll take care of it.
Yao.
Yao!
I can't... get Yao back.
[Next Episode Preview]
Wang Xiaoxiu, let's have a chat.
Boss, he's at least a Level B.
It's beyond our control.
What's your motive?
Kiddo.
I've been looking all over for you.
Why don't we compete?
Compete?
Help us complete three missions,
and you’ll know where Yan Luo is.
One for one.
One mission.
Besides Yan Luo,
I'm even more interested in info on Xigu Qin.
Deal.
Please make your choice.