Subbed by JackieD2
On that day, mankind received a grim reminder...
We lived in fear of the Titans
and were disgraced to live in these cages we called walls.
Squadron, prepare for battle!
There's only one target!
We will exterminate it and make this mankind's first outside base!
Target approaching!
Split into fives!
Remember your training!
We'll distract the target!
All attack teams, prepare to move up!
We'll close in on it from the sides!
Have a taste of mankind's strength!
Huh, Mikasa?
We should head back.
Why are you here?
Were you in a deep sleep and think you're still dreaming?
No, I think I was having a really long dream.
What was I dreaming about?
I can't remember...
Eren,
Why are you crying?
Attack on Titan Movie
Gekijō-ban
[ Zenpen ]  ー Guren no Yumiya ー
[ Part 1 ]  ー Crimson Bow and Arrow ー
Listen!
The walls were created with God's wisdom!
The walls are the work of God!
Not one soul shall dare desecrate the walls!
Don't tell anyone that I was crying.
I won't.
But if you don't know why you were crying,
Maybe you should talk to your dad about it?
Are you kidding me?
I can't tell my dad about that!
What were you crying about, Eren?
Hannes-san.
Is Mikasa mad at you?
What? Why would I be crying?
You reek of alcohol!
Nothin' wrong with that.
You're drinking again?
Wanna join us?
Hum... Aren't you on duty?
Yeah, we're watching the gates today.
We've been here all day. Started getting hungry and thirsty.
But it's not a big deal if we happen to drink something with a little alcohol in it.
But if you're drunk, how are you gonna fight?
Huh? When would we have to fight?
Do you really have to ask?
When they break the wall and come in!
Ouch.
Eren, don't say things like that out loud.
If it isn't Dr. Jaeger's son. You've got spirit, kid.
If they do end up breaking the wall, we'll do our jobs.
But you know what?
Not once in the past 100 years have they broken the wall.
Still! My dad said that it's times like these when we're in the most danger!
While helping in the maintenance of the wall, I see them out there, wandering aimlessly
But, speaking as a soldier, I don't think they can do anything about this 50 meter wall.
S-So... you don't even have the will to fight them?
Nope.
What?! Why don't you stop calling yourselves the Town Guards and call yourselves the Wall Menders!
Has a nice ring to it.
But Eren,
When people see soldiers fighting, they know something bad happened.
Everyone's much happier when we're doing nothing and getting called useless freeloaders.
Yeah, I know. We might not get out, but we'll live as long as we can eat and sleep.
But...
We're living like... like livestock.
This kid sure knows how to talk!
Not like you can do anything, right Hannes?
Uh, right.
Hey, Eren!
You're crazy, kid!
Does he... want to join the Survey Corps?
Eren,
I don't think you should join the Survey Corps.
What?
You think they're stupid too?
I'm not saying they're stupid or anything.
The Survey Corps are back!
The front gate is opening!
Let's go, Mikasa!
The heroes have returned!
Damn, I can't see.
Why are there so few of them?
A bunch of them were eaten.
This is what you get for going outside the walls.
Moses! Moses!
My son, Moses... I can't find him.
Where is my son?
It's her, Moses's mother.
Bring it here.
That was the only part of him we could salvage.
But... my son... was useful, right?
He might... not have been a hero,
but he at least died helping mankind fight back, right?!
Of course!
No... During this mission, we...
No,
Even after all of our missions,
we still haven't made any progress!
I'm a failure.
I've just gotten soldiers killed left and right!
And we haven't learned anything useful about the Titans!
Well, that was heavy.
Seriously. So all we've been doing is offering ourselves to them as free lunch?
What was that for, kid?
Hey! What are you doing, Mikasa!
Hey, get back here!
Mikasa! Fine, I get it!
What was that for?
Look at all the wood!
Eren
Have you changed your mind about joining the Survey Corps?
Help me pick this up.
There's not much.
We're back.
Welcome home.
Wow, Eren. I'm surprised you gathered this much firewood today.
Y-Yeah...
What was that for?
Your ear was red. You were lying.
Mikasa helped you, didn't she?
Huh? Dad, are you headed out?
For work?
Yeah, I have to go see someone in the inner walls.
I'll be back in two or three days.
Eren wants to join the Survey Corps.
Mikasa, you traitor!
Eren, what are you thinking?!
Do you know how many people die outside those walls?
I do!
You clearly don't!
Eren,
Why do you want to go outside?
I want to see and understand the world outside.
I don't want to die inside these walls without knowing what's out there!
On top of that,
If no one takes on their jobs,
Then those who lost their lives will have died in vain!
I see.
My ship's here, I must get going.
Wait, dear! Help me convince Eren!
Carla, nothing can suppress a human's curiosity.
Eren.
After I've returned, I'll show you the basement that I've been keeping you away from.
For real?
Have a safe trip!
I won't allow it.
You won't be joining something stupid like the Survey Corps.
Stupid?
People who are content living like livestock are more stupid!
Eren!
What's wrong, heretic?
Why don't you punch me if you want to prove me wrong?
Why would I do that?
I won't stoop so low.
What did you say?!
You're beating me up because you know I'm right and you can't prove me wrong.
Doesn't that mean you've admitted that you're wrong?
Enough with your crappy arguments!
Stop!
It's Eren.
What a moron. He's back again.
Does he want to get his ass handed?
We'll teach you a lesson!
Mi-Mikasa's with him!
Shit! Run!
Hey, they ran away after seeing me!
No, they ran away after seeing Mikasa.
Hey, you okay, Armin?
I can stand up by myself.
Oh, sorry.
So, after telling them that mankind needs to go outside eventually,
They beat me, calling me a heretic.
Dammit.
We just want go outside. Why does everyone hate us?
Well, it's been peaceful living inside these walls for the past 100 years.
Titans might be let inside when people leave the walls,
so the King's government banned people from showing interest to the outside world.
We're risking our own lives. No one has the right to stop us.
You can't do that.
No way.
Mikasa! How dare you tell my parents!
I don't remember agreeing to help you.
So how did it go?
Well, they weren't happy about it.
I figured.
People are crazy for believing that these walls will protect us forever.
Mama!
Even though the walls have been intact for the past 100 years,
There's nothing that can guarantee they won't be broken down today...
What was that?
Was it an explosion?
Over there!
Something fell?
I'm not sure.
Hey, Armin!
What happened?
What are you looking at?
You're kidding... That wall is...
50 meters tall!
It's them...
Titans!
One's coming!
The Titans are inside!
We need to get…
Eren!
My house is over there...
Mom is...
Mikasa!
It's over...
The Titans have invaded this town!
Our house is definitely safe!
Once I turn this corner, our
house will be there like always!
Mom!
Eren
Mikasa,
Grab that side.
We need to move this piece of wood!
Hurry, Mikasa!
I know!
The Titans are getting close.
Eren, take Mikasa and run. Hurry!
I want to run too!
Hurry up and get out!
My legs have been crushed by the debris.
I can't run even if I get out.
Do you understand?
I'll carry you and run!
Why can't you just listen to what I say for once?!
Please just listen to me! Just one last time!
Mikasa!
No... No!
At this rate, all three of us will...
Hannes!
Take the kids and run!
Don't take me lightly, Carla.
I'll kill the Titan
And save all three of you.
Wait! You can't fight it!
Hey, Hannes-san! What the hell are you doing?
Thank you.
Mom is still trapped in there!
Eren! Mikasa!
Live on!
Don't go...
Stop!!!
On that day, mankind received a grim reminder.
We lived in fear of the Titans,
and were disgraced to live in these cages we called walls.
The small, closed-off areas surrounding the walls, such as Shiganshina, were used as baits to attract the Titans,
fulfilling their roles of lowering costs of defense and military.
As a result of this design,
The people of Shiganshina could escape the assault of the Titans by traversing only one gate.
Toss all luggage!
We might even fit one more if you do that!
Armin, sit down.
But Eren and Mikasa aren't here yet.…
They're there.
Eren...
Don't just stand there! Hurry up!
What are you waiting for?!
Hurry up! They're coming!
This ship is full! We're leaving!
Please, let us on! Even just my child!
I'm sorry, but we can't do that!
Go!
Don't close it yet! Just wait a little longer!
We've still got people out there!
If they break through this gate, we'll lose much more than just this small district!
Mankind will be pushed back to the next wall!
That doesn't mean it's okay to just sacrifice all those people!
Hurry up and close it! The Titans are coming!
Hurry up and close the gate!
Stop!
Fire!
Shit! Run! Hurry!
The Titans are coming!
Close the gate!
Hurry! Close the gate!
This is the end...
It's over...
The Titans will eat us all...
It's over?
I'll never be able to go home again.
Mom is gone...
She's gone!
Why?
I... Us humans are weak.
Because we're weak, we can do nothing but cry?
I'll erase their existence from this world...
Eren?
What's the matter, Eren?
I'm going to kill them all.
Not even a single one of them will be left...!
Eren...
"The Holocaust" was the price of overconfidence and peace of 100 years.
At that moment, mankind was unaware of the existence of monsters such as the Colossus.
Wall Maria was lost and Wall Rose became humanity's last shield.
Always fearing that someday the Colossus would appear again and bring it down.
You have graduated from the Military Academy.
Soon you will become the wind of hope that will carry the dreams and hopes of mankind.
Hands upon your hearts!
Yes, Sir!
For you trainees graduating today, three paths now open before you.
You can be stationed at the walls and defend the cities as members of the Garrison!
You can put your lives on the line to fight the Titans in their own territory as members of the Survey Corps!
Or you can serve the King by controlling the crowds and protecting order as members of the Military Police Brigade!
Of course, only ten people with top scores we announced earlier are allowed into the Military Police!
Finally, I made it this far.
Now, it'll be our turn to devour the Titans!
Did it! I'm in the Military Police now!
We'll never worry about having food again!
Jean, do you know which division you will join?
Isn't it obvious? The Military Police.
That's why I strived to be among the top ten.
Yes, I too want to join the Military Police
There's no higher honor than working near the King.
C'mon, Marco!
Stop being such a goody-goody and just tell the truth.
You want to join the Military Police so you can live a simple, comfortable life within the Inner District.
You guys think the same, right?
Huh…
We would prefer not having to go beyond the wall…
You can say that again!
Nobody wants to die.
That's right. I will also enlist in the Military Police.
Me too.
But...
Don't lump me together with you.
So life on the interior is simple and comfortable?
Five years ago, this place was also part of the interior.
What's your point?
Jean, you're such a simpleton, you'd be comfortable living a life in blindness and ignorance.
Eren...
Do you even know how many people have been devoured?
Four years ago, when we had to leave the territory do to the forces of the Titans,
Humanity became enraged and decided to launch a final offensive in desperation,
but were annihilated as mere fools.
This was the answer they found:
Humanity can not cope with the Titans.
And because of that…
You're gonna give up without even trying?
We are mankind's last hope!
That's why we trained all these years.
We have made many sacrifices to obtain all this information on the Titans.
And now you say that we should just let ourselves be defeated?
Don't fuck with me!
I... will enter the Survey Corps and end the Titans!
Eren...
You're a deluded fool.
What did you say?
Who enlists the Survey Corps by choice?
If you're so eager to die beyond the wall, go ahead.
Eren!
Hey, there's a fight!
Stop it!
The instructor is coming!
What are you doing?!
Put me down!
Mikasa!
I told you to put me down! Hey!
Stay out of other people's business!
When you get angry, you become too foolish.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to join the Survey Corps!
Are you sure, Armin?
You're our top theoretician! Put that to better use!
I don't care if I die as long as I can be useful.
I'm going to the Survey Corps too.
You got the top score, didn't you? Go to the military police!
I'll go to the military police if you do.
If you go to the Garrisons, so will I.
You'll die an early death if I'm not there for you.
I never asked for that.
I don't want to lose what's left of my family.
What? You enlisted in the Survey Corps?
Connie, you were going on and on about joining the Military Police!
Yeah, I know, but…
Seems like he was listening to your lecture yesterday.
Shut up!
This is my own decision!
Don't be so shy about it.
You're not the only one.
Thomas... Are you serious...
Hum, guys...
I borrowed some meat from the officers' morning rations.
Sasha... You wanna get solitary confinement?
You're a real idiot!
Real idiocy's scary...
Let's all split it up together later.
We'll slice it up and eat it with bread!
Bring it back!
Yeah! Meat is a luxury now that we've lost so much land!
Don't worry about it.
Once we retake the land, we can keep pigs and cows again.
I'll take that meat!
Me too, so save my part!
That goes for me too.
Guys...
What do you say, Eren?
They'll find us out if we don't get back to work.
It's still a while before lunch.
Five years have passed since then.
Mankind's finally regaining its dignity.
We can win.
Mankind's counterattack begins now!
The hell?!
Samuel!
Sasha!
Samuel! Don't move!
That was close.
The gate's... broken...
Again... The Titans will get in again!
Every... fucking... one...
Ready the artillery! Four groups! Prepare for battle!
The target's right in front of us! It's the Colossal Titan!
This is our chance! Don't let it slip away!
Hello there. It's been 5 years.
It aimed for the cannons!
So it wasn't just a coincidence that he targeted the gate!
He's actually...
Intelligent!
Still, this is our chance.
This is the only one that can destroy the gates.
If I can just stop him!
There!
You're mine!
It burns!
Go!
Did I miss?
No... The Colossal Titan vanished...
Eren! Did you get it?
No! It's the same as five years ago!
He disappeared, just as suddenly as he appeared!
Bring only your most critical possessions!
Please remain calm and evacuate!
If they break through, the hell of five years ago will be repeated!
We must stop the Titans here!
You recruits have completed training and graduated into proper soldiers!
I expect you to actively participate in this operation too!
Don't worry, Hannah. I swear I'll protect you.
Franz...
Are you okay, Armin?!
I'm fine!
I'll pull it together.
But we're still in trouble!
We've got an eight-meter hole in the wall, and no way to fix it quickly!
We couldn't even dig out that giant rock near Zemo!
Then it's only a matter of time until they break through Wall Rose!
Armin!
Calm down! This time it's different.
Mankind won't lose to the Titans!
S-Sorry. I'm fine...
Why does it have to be today?
I'm supposed to go to the interior tomorrow!
Are you okay?
No! No! No!
Fuck off!
Hey, Jean! What's with you?
Don't give me that crap, you suicidal asshole!
Calm down!
Just chill out and accept my death?!
No!
Remember our three years of training!
We've been on the verge of death many times during those three years.
Some actually died.
Some ran away, and some were sent away.
But we survived!
Didn't we?!
We're gonna survive today too!
You'll survive today, and you're bloody well going to interior tomorrow!
Dammit!
Let's go, Daz!
You can't cower there forever!
Eren! If the battle gets too chaotic, come find me.
Huh? We're in totally different squads!
In the midst of the fray, nothing goes according to plan.
I'll protect you.
What are you going on about…
Trainee Ackerman!
You were specially assigned to rear guard.
Come with me.
I'd only be in the way there, sir!
The evacuation is going slow.
We need as many elite guards as possible protecting the civilians.
But I...
Get real, Mikasa!
It's so unlike you to panic!
Mankind is on the brink of extinction!
No one gives a fuck about what you want!
I'm sorry, I lost my head.
Just one thing. Please.
Please... Don't die.
I won't die.
I couldn't die even if I were killed here.
I don't know anything about this world yet.
Hey, Armin!
Don't you think this is a great chance?
If we prove ourselves here in this first battle,
before even entering the Survey Corps,
surely they'll promote us right up the ladder!
Without a doubt!
Not to burst your bubble,
But quite a few of us are aiming for the Survey Corps this year!
I lagged behind you earlier, Eren,
but I'm not losing this time!
That's the spirit, Thomas!
Let's have a contest to see who can slay more Titans!
No fudging your numbers!
Squad 34, advance!
Assist the frontline guard!
Right! Let's go!
Yeah!
The Titans advanced this far?!
The front guard's already been crushed?!
What are our glory-hound seniors doing?!
I expected the situation to be bad,
but this...
An abnormal one!
Watch out!
How dare you, motherfucker?!
Eren!
Stop! Don't go alone!
Stop, you bastard!
How dare you eat Thomas?!
You're not getting away!
Eren!
Stop! Please stop!
Why... am I...
Watching... as my comrades... get eaten?
Why... won't my body... move?
Eren! Eren! Eren!
What is it now, Armin?
Look at this book my grandpa was hiding!
It's all about the outside world!
The outside world?
But that's forbidden, isn't it?
What if the Military Police find out?
Who cares about that now?
According to this book,
Most of the world is covered by a huge amount of water called "sea"!
And it's all salty water too!
Salt? No way...
There's more than just mountains of salt!
Fire water! A continent of ice! Snowfields of sand!
The world out there must be far more vast than the inside of the walls!
The outside world...
Tell me, Eren...
It'd be great if we could explore the outside world too someday.
Eren!
You think I'm gonna die here?!
Hey, Armin... You told me about it...
So I'm going... to the outside world...
Eren! Hurry!
Hey!
Hey, what's wrong, Armin?
Get ahold of yourself! Hey! Armin!
Hey! Armin! Hey!
Are you with me now? Are you okay? Hurt anywhere?
Where's your squad?
My... squad?
Man, get it together already! Why are you alone?
And why are you so... slimy?
What the hell happened here?
I'm useless! Just leave me to die!
Calm down, Armin.
Where are they?
Just drop it already, Connie.
They're all dead... Everyone but him.
No way! Armin didn't say that!
Open your eyes and look the fuck around you.
We don't have time to babysit him.
Why is he unhurt then?
Who knows? Maybe the Titans mistook him for dead.
It was just bad luck their squad
encountered multiple Titans at once.
But to think this guy was the sole survivor?
Eren and the others didn't deserve this ending.
Hey, you heartless bitch, you want me to shut your mouth for good?!
Stop it, you two! Of course everyone's on edge!
Our friends are dying all around us.
It's only natural!
That's my Krista! After this mission ends, marry me, baby!
That's true... She's screwing around even more than usual.
Anyways, we can't stay here.
Can you stand, Armin?
Sorry for causing you trouble.
I'll go join the rear guard.
Hey... Armin!
We gotta go, Connie!
We've been ordered to move ahead!
This is hell...
No, this world hasn't become hell.
I just didn't get it up until right now.
This world's been hell all along.
The strong feed upon the weak.
It's such an obligingly simple rule.
Except in this world, my friends tried to be strong.
They helped me, though I was weak.
To the two of them, I was always someone to be protected.
I wanted to become strong like them,
So we could walk together side-by-side as we lived out our lives in this world.
Just look where that got me!
It's my fault that Eren...
Hannah, what are you doing?
Help me, Armin!
Franz isn't breathing!
I've been performing CPR over and over...
Franz!
Hannah, it's dangerous here! We should hurry...
And just leave Franz behind?!
That's not it, Hannah...
Franz won't...
Please stop... No more...
I can't... take this anymore...
Do you even understand the situation we're in?!
Withdraw!
Hey, Jean! What do we do now?
We finally received the order to retreat,
But we can't get over the wall because we're out of gas.
We're all going to die.
Thanks to those fucking cowards...
You mean the support squads?
What happened to them?
Are they all dead?
They probably lost their will to fight.
I understand how they feel.
But I doubt they've abandoned their mission and barricaded themselves away in the HQ.
I'm guessing the Titans have them surrounded,
Which is why they can't supply us with gas.
I had such a boring life.
If someone told me beforehand...
What now, Reiner?
It's not time yet.
We must group up first.
It's over...
No matter what we do, we'll be
dead before we make it out of here.
I mean, I'm prepared to die...
But what exactly am I going to die for?
Mikasa! Weren't you with the rear guard?
Annie! I think I understand the situation.
And I apologize for bothering you,
but have you seen Eren's unit?
No, and I haven't seen anyone climb the wall either.
Armin's over there, though.
Armin!
Mikasa?!
Crap! How can I look her in the face?
Armin, are you hurt?
Where's Eren?
Armin?
Our unit...
The 34th cadet unit...
Thomas Wagner.
Nic Tius.
Mylius Zeramuski.
Mina Carolina.
Eren Jaeger.
All five of them have fulfilled their duty
and died heroic deaths in battle!
No way...
So the 34th unit was nearly wiped out...
If we fight the Titans, we'll end up like them.
I'm sorry, Mikasa.
Eren died in place of me...
I couldn't do anything!
I'm so sorry!
Armin.
Take a deep breath.
This isn't the time to be emotional.
Stand up.
Marco, If we take out the Titans around the HQ,
we can replenish our gas supplies and climb the wall.
Does that sound correct?
Yeah... But even if you're with us, there's just too many...
We can do it.
I'm strong.
Stronger than all of you. Extremely strong.
I can kill all those Titans there.
Even if I'm alone.
You're either incompetent or you're spineless cowards.
How pathetic.
You can sit here and suck on your fingers.
Yeah, do that.
Hey, Mikasa!
What are you saying?
You want to fight all those Titans by yourself?
There's no way you can do that!
If I can't, then I'll just die.
But if I win, I live.
Unless I fight, I cannot win.
Hey!
Your oratory skills are what's pathetic.
Was the point of that to shock us into action?
It's all your fault, Eren!
Hey! Were we trained to let our comrades fight alone?!
At this rate, we're going to turn out to be spineless cowards!
I'm surprised I'd hear him say that.
Hey! Cowards! Weaklings! Retards!
They're nuts... Dammit!
Let's do it!
Hurry! Follow Mikasa!
Let's keep this fight short!
We need to kill them all before we run out of gas!
Mikasa's just amazing.
How can she move that fast?
She's using too much gas.
She'll run out right away.
I don't care how skilled she is...
Without our agility, we can't do anything!
If she keeps this up...
Mikasa!
Dammit!
Jean! You lead the others!
I'll go with Armin!
I'm coming with you!
What are you talking about?! There are more Titans left!
We need your skills!
Again...
It happened again.
I lost my family once again...
This pain is familiar.
Will I have to start fresh once again?
This world is cruel...
But it's also... Very beautiful.
You can have this.
Come on, let's go... Back to our home.
I lived a good life.
Why?
I thought I'd given up.
Why am I standing?
Why am I struggling?
Why?
My life has no meaning anymore.
What's keeping me going?
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Eren...
Fight! You must fight! Fight! Fight!
I'm sorry, Eren.
I won't give up.
I'll never give up again.
If I died,
I wouldn't be able to remember you.
So I'll win, no matter what!
I'll survive, no matter what!
What's going on?
A Titan... is killing... another Titan...
Please be all right, Mikasa!
Mikasa!
Mikasa, are you hurt?
Are you guys okay?!
Yeah!
We must get going!
Shit! There are two 15 meter classes!
No... That Titan's...
It finished the other Titan off?
It knew of a Titan's weak point?
We must get going before it comes this way!
No. It doesn't care about us.
It could've attacked us long ago.
It seemed like it had an idea of how to perform hand-to-hand combat.
What was that?
Just consider it an abnormal!
Anyway, we must hurry to the HQ!
Wait! I have an idea!
An idea?
Couldn't we take advantage of this Titan?
Open way!
Dammit!
How many of us made it?
How many died on my command?
You're part of the supply squad, aren't you?
Stop it, Jean!
These bastards abandoned us!
Do you even have a clue how many died?!
The Titans invaded the supply depot! What could we have done?!
It's your job to figure something out!
Take cover!
Dammit! There are too many people gathered here!
Hurry! Inside!
Run for your lives!
Where's Mikasa?!
She crashed back there! She's been eaten!
This is normal... This is reality, isn't it?
Was I just chasing a delusional dream?
Just thinking about it, it's obvious...
There's no way to beat these gigantic monstrosities.
What?!
What... is that?
Mikasa?!
It's empty... We did it!
We just barely made it!
You're... all alive?
We did it, Armin!
Ouch!
Your plan was a success!
Everyone! That Titan's an abnormality that slaughters other Titans!
It's not even interested in attacking humans!
If we play our cards right,
We can all get outta here alive!
We'd... use the Titan?
You'd rely on a Titan's help?
That's more delusional than any dream!
It's not a dream.
I don't care if it's an abnormal or whatever.
Just let it rampage here for as long as possible.
Realistically, that's our best option for survival.
We found some!
They're Military Police supplies,
Though they are covered in dust...
Will three bullets be enough?
Do these guns even work against the Titans in the first place?
It's better than nothing.
Even if there are still seven 3-4 meter class Titans in the supply room,
Blinding them all at once isn't impossible with this much firepower.
First we'll use the lift to lower a large number of people into the center of the chamber.
Next, they'll fire directly into the faces of all seven Titans at once.
We'll blind them.
The next instance will decide everything.
Seven other people hiding near the ceiling will swoop down to attack their weak spots while they're blind.
In other words... if we follow this plan, we'll be gambling everything on this single attack.
The whole point is for seven people to kill all seven Titans simultaneously.
The seven people should be the most physically capable ones.
You'll have to shoulder the burden of everyone's lives...
I'm sorry.
No problem.
Whoever fails, all of us will die.
The risk is the same.
But... I'm a nobody.
Is my plan really the best option?
We've got no other choices except your plan.
There's no time left to think. This idea's our only shot.
Now, we've just gotta give it everything we've got.
Don't worry. Be confident.
You've got a talent for reasoning out the best solution.
The lift's ready!
The guns too!
All of them are loaded!
You just aren't aware yet.
I'll tell you more later.
Okay...
We're all good. There's still only seven.
Follow the plan!
Calm down! Lure them in closer!
Hold!
We shouldn't fight at a disadvantage
if we want to keep casualties to the bare minimum.
We must end it in this one strike!
Wait!
Ready!
Fire!
I got it! The others?
Pardon me... for suddenly...
stabbing you... from behind...
It's Sasha and Connie!
Hurry! Help them!
I'm really sorry!
Mikasa! You saved me!
Are you hurt anywhere?
I'm safe, thanks to you!
Then stand! Now!
Sorry...
Never mind.
Geez. That was too close, Annie.
I'm glad you weren't injured.
We got them all!
Everyone stock up on supplies!
Hell yeah!
Are you all ready? Let's get outta here!
We've gotta bail now!
Go! Go! Go! We need to meet up with the main units!
Mikasa?
Mikasa!
We've gotta hurry!
That Titan...
They're eating it...
Its body can't regenerate?
I thought uncovering the truth about that Titan might be the key
to freeing ourselves from this desperate situation...
I agree.
If they just rip it to shreds like that, then we won't have learned a single thing!
We should get rid of those Titans currently devouring it,
And at least try to keep it alive.
Are you insane, Reiner?!
We can finally escape this deathtrap!
But what if that Titan could become an ally?
Don't you think it'd be a weapon more powerful than any cannon?
Our... ally? Are you for real?!
That's...
The abnormal that ate Thomas!
Hey...
What was that about helping it?
Looks like it burnt itself out.
Whatever. Let's get going!
There's no way that monster's on our side!
Titans are Titans.
What is it?
Mikasa!
It's Eren...
He's even got his limbs back...
Eren was eaten by that Titan back then.
What just happened here?
Then Eren... did all of this?
One of the reasons why the Titans' attack on Trost claimed so many soldiers' lives
Was that the elite Survey Corps were absent.
They'd left on a mission outside the Wall that very morning.
They're here! It's the main force of the Survey Corps!
Commander Erwin! Kick their Titan asses for me!
Look! There's Captain Levi!
They say in battle, he's as strong as a whole brigade!
Shut up already...
I bet they wouldn't worship you so much if they knew what an obsessive clean freak you are!
An expedition with the aim of exploring the outside and look for possible settlement.
When troops advanced into Titan
territory, casualties exceeded 30%.
That's just how great the power gap between Titans and men was.
Just... Just watch... You bastards...
Mankind will... survive...
You bastards... will all... Fall to Captain Levi!
One on the right...
Two on the left.
Captain, I've gathered the reinforcements!
Petra, look after that soldier down there.
The rest of you attack the one to the right.
I'll clean up on the left.
What a lovely bunch.
You all have such interesting faces.
Stay still.
Otherwise, I'll never get...
A clean cut of your flesh.
It got all filthy...
Captain, I can't stop the bleeding!
Captain...
What?
Was I... useful to... mankind?
Or will I die... useless like this?
You did great.
And you'll do even more.
Your spirit will stay with me and give me strength!
I swear to you,
I will exterminate the Titans!
Captain, he's gone...
Did he hear everything?
I'm sure he heard it all.
He's resting so peacefully now.
Good, then...
Levi! We're going back!
Back? We haven't reached our limit yet.
Did my men die in vain?
The Titans have all started heading north towards the city.
It's just like five years ago.
Something's happened in the city.
They might've even broken through the Wall.
All cadets are to ready their equipment and stand by!
So that's how we managed to refill our gas and get out of Trost.
Wait, then the people who aren't here are all...
Yeah.
Even Mikasa?
No... I thought Mikasa came back late with Jean and the others...
Jean! Don't tell me Mikasa was wounded?
Hey, what's wrong?
We were sworn to keep it secret.
Secret?
What the hell?
It's hardly something they can keep covered up though.
Soon all of mankind will know about it.
Although for that, they must pass this test and gain their survival.
Fire!
Eren! Armin! We're going up!
Cannon fire?!
But why just on shot?!
It can't be...
Is that smoke from a Titan?
Wait!
Did we get them?
No way...
Look at that! Stay back! It's too dangerous!
Stand by on alert!
Stand by!
Load the next round into the cannon!
Are you okay?
Eren, what is this?
I don't know.
All I know is I've got my arm and leg back as if by magic,
And that all the Garrison sees is a Titan who killed his comrades.
Earlier, when I transformed,
I did it unconsciously.
It's as if I wasn't able to control my body!
I did remember one thing, though...
The basement. The basement of my old house.
My father said I would understand everything if I went there.
Always keep this key with you. Never let go of it.
And when you look at it, remember!
You must go to the basement!
Understood? Retake Wall Maria and reach that basement!
This power will prove usefull then!
My father's the reason all of this is happening to me.
If I get to that basement, I'll probably find out the truth about Titans.
Dammit! Why did he hide this from me?
It's the intel the Survey Corps has been searching for,
at the cost of thousands of lives!
This is mankind's last hope!
He was just keeping it locked away in the basement?
What the hell was he thinking?!
Eren, your nose is bleeding...
You're really pale. Your breathing's heavy too.
Doing that clearly puts too much strain on your body!
I don't care if I'm in bad shape right now.
I've caused you enough trouble already.
From here on out, I'm doing this alone.
No! I…
Eren.
I'm coming too.
No.
If I can't keep up with you, then don't concern yourself with me.
But I don't have to do whatever you say either.
Cut the crap already, for fuck's sake!
I'm not your little brother or your kid!
I guess that even in my final moments, I'm still nothing more than a coward.
They've helped me out so many times,
Yet never once was I able to repay them.
After this... The three of us will never be together again.
No! I can't give up!
There has to be a way out!
I'll convince them.
Do your best to show them you don't intend to resist.
Something's been troubling me ever since I saw Eren fight as a Titan.
I haven't even sorted out my own
thoughts yet, but I've got to do this.
I'll have to think while I speak!
Stop!
You finally showed your true colors, monster!
I'll signal! I'll signal the cannon!
He isn't the enemy of mankind!
We're willing to share all the intelligence we've gathered!
Begging for your lives is useless now!
I've seen it with my own eyes!
A Titan came from inside of another!
And if that weren't enough, I also witnessed how Eren Jeager got out from that Titan's neck!
If you say he's not an enemy, prove it!
There's no need for further proof!
That's right! It's unnecessary!
The issue isn't how we see him!
What?!
You said everybody saw him!
Then they must've seen him fighting the Titans too!
And they must've seen all the Titans ganging up against him!
The Titans see him as prey, just like the rest of mankind!
Nothing you say can change that fact!
A Titan as an ally... That can't be...
That can't be...
Don't fall for this clever trap!
As a soldier, I swore to devote my heart to the resurrection of mankind!
There is no greater glory than dying for that belief!
If we added his Titan power to the might of our armies,
It might even be possible to recapture the town!
For the glory of the human race, I beg you! In my final moments before I die,
Permit me to explain his strategic importance!
Captain, we should consider wh—
Silence!
No matter how they plead for their lives, they're still rebels!
Those who break the rules must be eliminated!
That's what it means to be a soldier!
Cut it out already.
You haven't changed. As big as you are,
you've still got the guts of a scared fawn.
Commander Pixis?
Can't you see how magnificent his salute is?
I just arrived, but the situation has already been relayed to me.
You go organize the reinforcements.
I think it'd be worthwhile to hear what they've got to say.
Dot Pixis.
The Commander-in-Chief of the defense of the southern territories, including Trost.
A man entrusted with complete authority over the key area of mankind's defenses.
I see. So you believe that basement holds all the answers you seek?
Yes. Will you believe me, sir?
Since even you yourself can't say for sure, let's just say I'll just keep it in mind for now.
Cadet Arlert, was it?
Yes, sir!
Earlier, you said that by using this "Titan power"
We might be able to retake this city.
Do you really believe that,
Or were you just desperate to stay alive?
It was... both, sir!
I was trying to say that Eren could take on his Titan form,
Carry that boulder to the wall, and block the gap in the gate.
The thought just occurred to me...
But couldn't you look at Eren's power as a chance to turn this situation to our favor?
Of course, I was also desperate to save our lives...
Desperate to save... Those words are worth more than anything.
What do you say, Cadet Jaeger?
Sir?
Can you close the gap?
I...
I'm not sure.
I don't understand this any more than the rest of you.
It'd be irresponsible of me to answer as if I knew either way.
Oh right, sorry.
I asked the wrong question.
Will you do it or not? Which is it?
I'll do it. I will do it.
I'm not certain I can close the gap, but I'll still do it.
The elite team has commenced the operation.
I will now brief you about the operation for retaking Trost!
I shall now introduce him.
Eren Jaeger of the Cadets!
He can summon a Titan body and control it at will!
He will transform into a Titan, pick up that giant boulder near the front gate,
carry it to the breach in the wall, and block off the hole with it!
Your mission will be to protect him from the other Titans
...while he's carrying the boulder to the breach!
Eren Jaeger's protection will be entrusted to the squad leaders:
Ian Dietrich, Rico Brzenska and Mitabi Jarnach!
The fate of mankind is in your hands.
Yes, sir!
Ready? Let's go!
Since the Titans first appeared,
Not once has mankind won against them!
The Titans keep marching forth and we keep retreating,
Letting them take our land!
However, when this plan succeeds,
It'll be the first time we've ever reconquered land from the Titans!
And in that moment, for the first time, mankind will triumph over the Titans!
Compared to what's been taken from us,
It may be a small thing...
But it will mean mankind has finally managed an attack on the Titans!
By human standards, that rock is way too heavy to lift.
But I'm sure Eren has the strength to guide us.
Eren?
Ackerman!
Eren, don't you recognize me? I'm Mikasa!
I'm your family!
You must block the hole with that boulder!
Dodge, Ackerman!
What's up with him?
He's just a stupid Titan like all the rest!
Eren!
Squad leader Ian!
Two approaching from ahead!
One 10-meter and one 6-meter class!
Another is coming from behind!
It's a 12-meter class!
The operation has failed.
It was obvious from the start that no secret weapon existed.
Hey, look at that!
Look, what's that?
Did they... fail?
Why?
Armin! Where are you going?
Commander Pixis,
We should fall back to defending the gate.
Do you approve?
No.
Order the elite team to retreat.
No need.
Keep luring the Titans to the corner of the town.
As for the elite team, they have the authority to act as they see fit.
They aren't merely just skilled soldiers.
They are the elite among the elite that I entrusted with the future of mankind.
Giving up so easily would be unforgivable.
We cannot allow our comrades' deaths to be in vain.
We must struggle to our very last breaths.
I'm at home?
I need sleep...
This isn't good! Behind us!
A 13-meter class is heading for Jaeger!
More Titans are coming in through the gate!
Looks like four 10-meter class!
Ackerman, handle the one behind us!
Roger!
Don't let them reach Jaeger!
We'll stop them here!
Roger!
Even though they're the elite,
just two squads can't handle four at once...
Oh, no... Why are there so many Titans?
There are hardly any humans around here.
Don't tell me... They're drawn to Eren?
Mikasa!
What happened to the plan?
Armin?
What's wrong with Eren?
It's dangerous! Get away from there!
Eren can't control that Titan!
It didn't respond even when I tried talking to it!
There's no use in anyone else trying either!
And the plan?
It failed.
We can't leave Eren behind,
So everyone's fighting!
But with this many Titans,
We're bound to get wiped out!
Eren came out of the Titan's weak point before.
What are you...
This has to be related to the mystery of the Titan's true nature.
It'll be fine. As long as I avoid the middle,
It won't be fatal...
It's just going to hurt a bit!
Armin!
Armin, don't be a fool!
Mikasa! Right now, do what you can!
If you go, there are lives you can save!
Leave Eren to me and get going!
Eren, can you hear me?!
Get a grip, man!
If you don't come out of there, we're all dead!
Eren! Come out!
Hurry! Eren!
Eren!
What happened to avenging your mother?!
Weren't you going to exterminate all the Titans?!
Don't you hate those bastards for killing your mom?!
What are you saying, Armin?
My mom's right here.
Eren!
Eren! Wake up, please! Eren!
I know you're in there, Eren!
If you stay here, we'll be killed by the Titans!
Everything will end right here!
I told you, you're making no sense, Armin.
Why should I go outside?
That's right. Why should I...
Join the Recon Corps...
Gotcha!
Take that, you piece of shit!
Keep your distance!
Ackerman reporting in!
I'll join Mitabi's squad!
Huh?
Jean!
Hurry the fuck up!
I've had enough of people dying on my account!
Shit, it just had to break right now?!
Jean!
What's wrong? Why isn't he using his 3D Maneuver Gear?
Don't tell me it broke!
I'll sort this out myself!
Eren! Eren! Eren!
Eren!
Weren't we going to explore the outside world?
Far, far beyond these walls...
To the burning water and the land of ice.
To the snowfields of sand.
I thought you'd forgotten about it,
but you'd just stopped bringing it up because you didn't want me to join the Recon Corps.
The outside world...
Eren, answer me! Even though you knew hell was raging outside the walls...
Why did you ever want to see the outside world?
Why, you ask? Isn't it obvious?
Because I was born into this world!
Squad leader, this is all we can handle! We're the only ones left!
Let's fall back to the rock!
Report!
Five Titans incoming from the gate.
Dammit!
Jean!
It must be his Maneuver Gear!
What's wrong?
C'mon, you bastard! I'm in a hurry here!
Jean, calm down!
Marco, what are you doing?!
Jeez, what a drag!
Crap! Why is the trigger so hard to pull?
Jean!
What are you doing?!
That's my line! Fly away already!
You guys are insane!
My line again! I think I just died like three times over!
Look at that!
Eren...
Mikasa!
Armin!
Eren won! He's trying to do his job now!
If he can just make it to the gate,
We win!
Listen well!
We must defend Eren until he reaches the gate, even if it costs us our lives!
Don't let any Titans get near him!
Keep them all out of the way! We must support Eren!
You two, go to Eren!
This is an order! Got it?
Yes, sir!
Mitabi's squad? What are they...?
The Titans aren't paying us any attention! We've gotta get close enough that they can't ignore us!
Look! Over here!
Turn around, or I'll shove my sword right up your stinkin' ass and bleed you to death!
Now! Two of them are after us!
Run! Run to the buildings!
No way! Staying on the ground is suicide!
Without horses or buildings, we can't fight!
No... It's the only way we've got left.
Everyone follow their lead!
Armin, we're going too.
This way! Come over here!
My body... It feels like I'm being crushed...
Mikasa? Armin? What are you doing?
If you stay down there, the Titans will eat you!
Hey! What are you waiting for?
Come and get me!
Hey!
Mitabi!
Why did you ever want to see the outside world?
When we're born, all of us are free.
People who deny that, no matter how strong they are, don't matter.
The burning water, the land of ice... I don't care what!
Anyone who saw such things would be the freest person in the entire world!
Fight! Who would value their life over something like that?
However terrifying the world may be... It doesn't matter!
However cruel the world may be... It doesn't matter!
Fight!
Watch out! Titans!
I'll handle this!
Out of the way!
Go, Eren!
Fight!
Everybody... didn't die in vain.
Today, for the first time, mankind triumphed over the Titans.
Part of his body is still fused with the Titan.
I can't pull him out!
We'll have to cut it then!
Hey, you kids...
What's the situation here?
The Wings of... Freedom...
Do you have any questions?
Hum...
Where... am I?