♪ If I could escape from fate's predetermined path ♪
♪ And touch the true essence of time and space, the ultimate secret ♪
♪ I'll awaken this extraordinary destiny ♪
♪ And awaken another version of myself ♪
♪ The clearest, most resilient eyes of yours ♪
♪ Crystals filled with infinite power ♪
♪ Unleash my true nature ♪
♪ Take every breath at lightning speed ♪
♪ Shining justice ♪
♪ The only truth in the duel ♪
♪ Now you guys are hearing my cry ♪
♪ My life was full of regrets ♪
♪ Restart ♪
♪ Striving, fighting, honing ♪
♪ Finding my future ♪
♪ Do not just dream it, have a try ♪
♪ Nothing can beat me, bravery's in my chest ♪
♪ I'll smash myself to protect your tenderness ♪
♪ Never bow down again ♪
[Super Cube]
[Episode 8]
Yao's gone, and Cube's not responding.
My microwave vision and teleportation still works,
but with how weak I am now...
I...
How can I...
get Yao back?
Wang Xiaoxiu.
Let's have a chat.
I know where Yan Luo is.
Where is he?
Come with me.
Welcome.
One Americano
and one Mocha.
Thanks.
Where's Yan Luo?
Before I answer you,
I have a question.
What is it?
Cultivators, superhumans, mutants,
and other paranormal beings.
Why
do you think they aren't exposed to the public?
Because they're good at disguise?
Imaginative guess, but reality's cruel.
The truth is
there are people taking care of it.
I don't care.
You must care, because...
I've been protecting you in secret.
Or else, you wouldn't be alive.
Protecting me?
How do you explain
the three men behind me, ready to shoot me anytime?
Don't move.
You...
If you don't touch the gun under your skirt,
this discussion can go on.
Leave me out of your protection racket.
Listen.
I'm only interested in Yan Luo.
Start talking, or we're done.
Mu Yuqian,
task force leader of Superhuman Management...
Boss, I told you superhumans are uncooperative.
So you don't believe me?
No, I do.
It never crossed my mind,
but come to think of it,
those fighters I've met...
A corresponding order must exist.
But...
What's your motive?
A newly-awakened superhuman like you
is at risk of obliteration.
I'm sorry.
Focus.
Since we keep you safe,
we hope you can return the favor.
I see.
Be your mercenary
just like them?
But their energy waves are miniscule.
At most, they're fighters beneath Level C.
Boss, he's at least a Level B.
It's beyond our control.
I'll get to the point.
Three missions.
Help us complete three missions,
and you’ll know where Yan Luo is.
One for one. One mission.
Apart from Yan Luo,
I want info on Xigu Qin too.
Deal.
Wait, so quick?
It's simple. Be a bodyguard.
I'm a student with classes to get to.
I can't skip any more classes.
It won't affect your studies.
It'll take one day,
in State H on Earth.
[Bodyguard Employment Contract]
With a pay of 50,000 in Earth Coins.
And how can I trust you?
We've just had an amicable talk.
Isn't that proof enough?
Besides,
you have to pass an assessment first.
Let's see if you're qualified.
It's a huge risk,
but I have no other choice.
To rescue Yao,
on top of powers,
I need intel.
Even if it was all just a lie,
her identity's real.
So, if I can use her to get into the bureau,
I can get more intel I need.
Then...
Boss, why'd you make a deal with him?
We never harbor dangerous individuals.
Mu Liang.
Remember what the old man always says?
Wealth comes with risks.
People like us can't be conservative,
or we'll stay being small fry.
I've investigated.
He's quite innocent.
In less than a month with his powers,
he fought off Level-B fighters.
When this was classified as a Level-B case,
I had a hunch...
This is our chance.
You sure things aren't getting out of hand?
You think too much.
Remember, wealth comes with risks.
Wealth comes with risks, huh?
Way to sugarcoat your greed.
Who cares, it's easier to control
such money grubbers.
Are you really gonna tell him where Yan Luo is?
I think
if people know how much intel we have,
it could be disastrous.
Don't worry.
He clearly knows nothing about the family.
He's clueless about us too.
We'll just settle it with
some Level-D intel.
No wonder you were so vague during the negotiation.
Seriously? Taking advantage of me?
I'm not that naive!
Let's see who's the real fool!
Anyway,
[Caution: Please do not try this at home]
they'll still be of help to me.
My only way to get intel.
[The next day]
Dang it.
Is this a joke?
Why did the GPS bring me here?
This is Singular Mansion.
Welcome.
Are they all here for the assessment?
They all look so different.
What's the deal with this?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm Xu, and I'll oversee this recruitment of Mr. Piao's bodyguards.
As we all know,
aside from loyalty, a bodyguard
must excel in three aspects:
discernment, responsiveness, and combat.
As such,
you'll be assessed according
to these three aspects.
For the first test,
the Discernment Room.
Please follow me.
[Discernment Room]
Discernment Room?
Here are the rules of the test.
Each of you will get five free chips to begin with.
You can play anything you want.
But take note that violence
and stealing's forbidden.
To pass the test, you'll have to accumulate
ten chips.
[Rules of the Discernment Room]
There's a quota of 30 in this round.
That's it. Good luck, everyone!
Just racking up chips?
Pssh. Easy peasy.
I was itching for a fight.
Something feels off.
Forget it. It's better than fighting.
They say to have fun.
But with only five chips,
there aren't many options.
We have to rule out stuff like roulettes
and slot machines.
Machines and equipment must be rigged.
There's no winning.
On the surface, Hi-Lo seems more fair.
On the surface...
My chips!
Oh no!
It must be rigged!
I knew it.
Is he talking to me?
There's still a way to win.
Young fella,
it all depends on how brave you are.
Where'd he go?
Time to find a new target.
Where are my chips?
I didn't use them!
Find the Coin!
Placing a bet?
- This looks interesting.
- Hey!
Kiddo, I've been looking all over for you.
I was looking forward to making a friend,
but you chose to go solo.
Then why don't we compete?
Compete?
For fun. It's just a game.
With that!
You sure?
What are you plotting?
He's quite cautious, huh?
But what does a kid like him know?
Sorry, buddy.
Kiddo, are you scared?
No way.
It's on.
All in?
You've got guts.
I like it.
Let's begin.
Alright.
Here we go!
So fast!
Got it.
Make your bets.
I've got it. The cup on the left.
The left cup!
And you, sir, which cup would you like to bet on?
I'm betting
on your right hand.
- What? Is he stupid?
- What the hell's wrong with him?
Huh? What is he up to?
Do you mean this hand of mine?
When did she shift it?
How agile.
No, I meant your left hand.
Just in case,
please place both hands on the table.
Go on. No more tricks.
Congrats! You've doubled your chips!
No way!
How'd he know?
None of the three cups have coins.
How'd she do it?
I'm sorry, sir.
But this doesn't violate any rules.
Could it be... she actually...
had two coins prepared?
One was in her palm,
and the other coin under a cup
fell into the table.
It's rigged.
I can't tell you how the coin ended up
in my hand.
The table isn't rigged, sir.
There's always been just one coin.
You lost,
sir.
Damn it.
Even I was fooled by it.
This guy...
Seriously...
Who the hell is he?
Five chips.
Let's go.
Chop-chop!
After several rounds of eliminations,
the assessment's finally over.
Here's the last member.
You've all officially
made the cut.
Congrats on passing the rigorous assessment.
[Next Episode Preview]
Let's welcome Mr. Piao.
These are the rewards for the warriors.
Though that crocodile's speedy,
his attack range is short.
Adios!
Where's our next warrior?
Just you wait, Yan Luo.
I will find you!
Let's skip the boring opening speech
and get right into it.
I hope you have a wonderful time.
♪ It's like a dream ♪
♪ I want to touch you but I plunge ♪
♪ Into the swarming crowd ♪
♪ Like being pushed into a boundless whirlpool ♪
♪ I'm excluded from your light ♪
♪ How can I get close to you? ♪
♪ I need to convey my yearning to you ♪
♪ It's too late ♪
♪ At this chapter of our story, I'm all alone ♪
♪ Swirling petals ♪
♪ Mirroring the regret of disappointment ♪
♪ Before the starry sky dims ♪
♪ Can I catch a last glimpse of you? ♪
♪ It doesn't matter if you don't notice me ♪
♪ Memories of us stranded in my chest ♪
♪ Suddenly plunging me into an abyss ♪
♪ I shut my eyes ♪
♪ Can't bear to see yesterday replay ♪
♪ Say goodbye ♪
♪ My feet are still lingering ♪
♪ How can I ♪
♪ Let go and get over it? ♪
♪ Say goodbye ♪
♪ Leave with nothing ♪
♪ Where is my light? ♪
♪ All that's left is a void ♪