What?
No way.
Whatever. I just need to get to the camp on time.
Whatcha doing?
Huh? Um...
I'm lost.
What? Are you from another town?
Yeah.
Is that fun?
What?
Not really.
This is just a time waster.
Oh.
Do you play volleyball?!
Huh?
Those shoes!
They're volleyball shoes!
Oh, yeah.
I play volleyball too!
My name's Hinata Shouyou!
Kozume...
Kenma.
Um, do you like volleyball?
Not really.
I play it 'cause it's there.
I don't mind it, I guess, but I don't like getting tired out.
But a friend of mine plays it,
and he probably needs me to play with him.
I think once you start to like it, you'll find it's way more fun.
That's okay.
I'm only doing it for the duration of high school.
Kenma, wake up!
Everyone's gone for breakfast already.
Get a move on, man.
Get up, damn it!
Morning! It's finally time! Isn't that super exciting?!
Get a text from Shorty?
Kinda funny he'll just text someone he's about to face off with.
He's gonna come at you with all he's got.
I mean, isn't it natural to want to win?
No, I mean that he's gonna go all-out on you.
What's that supposed to mean?
Send
Sent
Jaybird Inn
Inbox
Kozume Kenma
Yeah.
Inbox
Kozume Kenma
Yeah.
Inbox
Kozume Kenma
Yeah.
Inbox
Kozume Kenma
Yeah.
Inbox
Kozume Kenma
Yeah.
Inbox
Kozume Kenma
Yeah.
Inbox
Kozume Kenma
Yeah.
Kenma probably won't care if they happen to lose.
Huh?
But I have to beat him!
Battle of the Garbage Dumpster
Haikyuu
!!
The Movie
Tournament Day Three
Third Round
Nekoma
Tokyo
First Match
Miyagi
Karasuno
Senju
Aomori
First Match
Saga
Morita Girls'
Hisamatsu
Tokyo
First Match
Ishikawa
Kanei Business
It's finally time for the Battle of the Garbage Dumpster, Coach Nekomata!
Yes.
But we didn't come here just to beat Karasuno.
There are quite a few people with a bit of an interest in this match.
Starting at 10 a.m.
Volleyball Nationals
Karasuno vs Nekoma
Holding a small watch party
Please order a drink
Including me, of course.
Let's go!
Yeah!
These kids don't aren't here for our old rivalry.
Coach Nekomata.
Hey.
May the best team win.
We've brought our all today!
We accept your challenge.
Well, well, well, if it isn't Karasuno, the diving drill pros.
We do our best.
We're here watching matches two days in a row.
National High School Volleyball Championship
I'm starting to think you're secretly rooting for Nekoma.
N-N-No way!
I just wanna be here when they lose!
Come on, just admit it.
N-No, really...
Tokyo Municipal Nekoma High School
Let's have a good match!
Lemme hear you!
We absolutely cannot let them out-cheer us!
Go, go, Nekoma!
Push it, push it, Nekoma!
Fly
Go, go, Nekoma!
Connect
No fair! I wanna play Karasuno and Nekoma!
Same here.
Yamamoto, go get 'em!
Yeah! You just wait!
The Tokyo teams have plenty of people cheering for them.
Stinkin' locals.
All right, Kenma!
Let's stop the monster and his team!
Our blockers getting split up would be a real pain.
Kenma's not very interested in winning or losing.
Words like that won't change that.
He just analyzes if something is possible or not.
Can we do this or not?
I don't know.
All right! You know the deal!
We're like the blood in our veins.
We must flow without stopping.
Keep the oxygen pumping...
and your minds working!
Let's tear these guys up!
Yeah!
We will now introduce both teams' starting lineups.
First up, we have Karasuno High School, who defeated the tournament favorite Inarizaki the other day.
Wearing number one, captain and support pillar of Karasuno, the wing spiker Sawamura Daichi.
I want to hear you!
Yeah!
R-Right.
Wearing number three, wing spiker and Karasuno's main offensive power and ace, Azumane Asahi.
Wearing number five, the up-and-coming secret ace,
second-year wing spiker Tanaka Ryuunosuke.
Wearing number nine, first-year setter Kageyama Tobio,
who's suddenly in the spotlight.
Wearing number ten, another guy in the spotlight,
a middle blocker and the smallest player in the tournament, Hinata Shouyou.
Weaning number eleven, the tallest on the team and their key defender, middle blocker Tsukishima Kei.
Wearing number four is their libero, Nishinoya Yuu. He's the team's guardian angel and spark plug.
They'll be led by Head Coach Takeda Ittetsu.
And since he doesn't have volleyball experience,
Coach Ukai Keishin will be giving out the actual directions.
That's my grandson.
What? That's amazing!
He's so young!
Mr. Ukai Ikkei
Mr. Morimori Morio
He looks just like you.
Connect
Next up, we have Nekoma High School.
Wearing number one and captain, Kuroo Tetsuro,
an all-rounder playing middle blocker.
Wearing number two, the well-rounded and cool-headed third-year wing spiker, Kai Nobuyuki.
Wearing number four, the second-year ace, Yamamoto Taketora. He's their main scorer.
Shut up, Tora.
Wearing number five, the brains of Nekoma and their setter, Kozume Kenma.
We've all seen that there's more to him than meets the eye.
Wearing number six, with hard-to-read attacks, second-year wing spiker Fukunaga Shouhei.
Wearing number eleven,
his height and wits see him becoming a star player,
it's first-year middle blocker Haiba Lev.
Give me all the sets, please!
How stupid are you?
Playing libero and wearing number three, Nekoma's ace defender, Yaku Morisuke.
They're being led by Coach Nekomata Yasufumi.
Hey!
This guy's your rival, right?
Coach Nekomonster!
It's Coach Nekomata!
Didn't you want to be at this match?
Not really.
My name might not be in the tournament pamphlet,
but my student is there.
And my own flesh and blood.
What else do I need?
This is about here and now.
It's their battle.
But we wouldn't have made it here on our own.
I'm sure those guys know that.
So sit back and enjoy, gramps!
He got it up on the first serve!
Nice receive!
Someone get that!
That packed a punch!
We can score here!
Send it left!
Watch this spike!
Nice one, Taketora!
In the air too long...
Nice, Daichi!
Lately, I've been thinking...
Thinking what?
You're fun to play against,
so I'd like to face you in a real match.
Huh?
A match where losing means an instant game over.
Let's do it.
Holy crap!
That was so fast!
This is our match where there's no extra lives, Kenma!
It's on now!
Shouyou's changed since we came to nationals.
We can't assume he'll always come jumping first.
Yeah!
He still does come up fast sometimes, though.
Sure does.
Shorty's trying to lure us out with those minus tempo attacks.
When did we last practice with them? October?
They've already changed things up?
Ugh, gimme a break.
But the cat caught the snake.
Catch and releasssse.
Right. They're not the only ones who've improved.
Synchronized attack!
I touched it!
Nice call!
Get it!
A synchronized attack...
...with the whole team!
Five attackers?!
Nice one, nice one, Kuroo!
You bastard...
Nekoma also did a synchronized attack, didn't they?
Come on! Focus!
Looks like the cats and crows are both omnivores.
Real cats are carnivores.
Thanks for the info.
That's the first time we've used the five-man attack on them, right?
Didn't slow Kuroo down one bit.
Remember, Kuroo taught Tsukishima how to do those annoyingly persistent blocks.
The ball's getting by you because your still have your hands up.
Didn't I tell you that you gotta reach forward, Mr. Clubb?
Must be feeling confident if you're dishing out advice.
Nope. Just egging you on.
Don't let him beat you, Tsukki! Get him back for that!
I bet Kuroo's saying something to piss off Tsukishima again.
Nekoma
Karasuno
Make it good!
Move up!
Left!
You call that a receive?
It's gonna go over the net.
Send it back, Hinata!
Got it!
Yeah!
Did you hear that?
Yuu! You're better every time we play!
Thanks, Morisuke!
Not too long ago, he couldn't time it right at all.
This goes without saying, but they play like a completely different team than last time.
Scary, huh?
Like true omnivores.
They've taken down beasts bigger than them.
Now, then...
How do we beat 'em?
Nekoma
Karasuno
Go!
Here's their chance!
It's coming back!
What?!
Wow...
Keep it going!
Okay!
These guys have never played the same twice.
So just like always,
we gotta watch, adjust, and figure 'em out!
Left, left!
Yeah!
How many times am I gonna jump today?
You show 'em, Tsukishima! Don't let Kuroo beat you!
You hear me?! Don't you dare lose to him!
Suga is as heated as ever.
He gets way more fired up than you'd think, huh?
Are you listening, Tsukishima?!
That's not gonna happen.
Back already.
I'd never dream of beating someone who's better than me.
Me beat you?
No way! Never!
I never thought for a second that I could win on my own.
A certain someone seems to think he might.
Maybe.
He is always one step ahead of me.
You got this, Yamaguchi!
C'mon, c'mon, c'mon!
Bring it!
Got it!
Yeah!
Yes! Yes! Yes, yes, yes!
The ball went all flop mid-air!
That was a nice serve!
Shifted just at your fingertips, huh?
Don't sweat it.
Tadashi... He's all grown up...
Sure is!
You his dad?
Go for one more!
Get 'em!
Nekoma doesn't give "one more"!
Nice receive!
All we needed.
Didn't I tell you that you gotta reach forward, Mr. Clubb?
Yeah!
That's what our Tsukki is made of!
Tsukishima's not on our team, Bokuto.
Nice block!
Nice serve.
That's on you!
Ow!
How was that on me?! Tsukki just played it right!
That jump was so high...
Maybe the crows can fly.
Tsukki, how're you enjoying this these days?
Thankfully,
it's fun, every now and then.
Never thought I'd see the day you'd say so!
You could learn a thing or two, Kenma!
Give us another good one, Yamaguchi!
Nice receive!
Right!
All right!
Nekoma
Karasuno
Damn it.
You should feel good about that.
Guess I woulda wanted to score more too, though.
All right! Bring it on!
Yamamoto! Make it count!
Sorry!
Now's our chance!
It's long!
Asahi!
Yeah!
Keep your hands on the ball and you'll get your chance.
We don't need a perfect pass if you're just getting it over the net!
Sorry!
It's not a perfect pass if it goes over the net anyway.
True.
All right already!
Kageyama's something, huh?
You don't need to get it to the net.
Get it up to the attack line and I'll handle the rest.
Damn him for being so cool!
You hear that, Kenma?
Man, that guy says some cool things.
I heard him.
We have our rules, they have theirs.
Okay, Mom.
We don't need to compete every step of the way.
Hinata, you got this!
Fukunaga!
Center!
Got it!
Sorry!
The other side?!
Nice spike!
What?! No way!
All right! That was close!
Yeah!
So close!
We thought it was a done deal,
but they didn't think it was over yet.
Nekoma always plays like that, so stay alert!
Kageyama was going hard right, but he set that perfectly to the left.
Yeah.
And the guys on offense were fully ready for it.
Nice stuff.
Intrigue and respect rather than fear.
The joy of facing off against a tough opponent held in high regard.
You gotta love it.
But he's a little different.
This is the big event. A long-awaited clash.
Bring it!
Could be the last match for the third-years.
But he's not interested in all that.
All he wants to do is pluck the feathers from those crows.
Asahi!
Karasuno's offense is ridiculous.
They're actually doing pretty well, though.
Who is? Nekoma?
Yeah.
Nekoma
Karasuno
Even though they aren't winning?
Nekoma are down early a lot of the time.
Nekoma
Nohebi
But they spend that time learning their opponent's moves.
Nekoma's style is to come clawing back.
They're up against some heavy-hitters today, though.
And they're still hanging on this close from the start.
This is a pretty amazing show from them.
Daichi!
Too much air!
Give it to 'em, Kageyama!
Hold your ground, Lev!
You got this, Lev!
You can't outplay him...
Definitely can't!
But you've got height on him!
Figures.
Kenma!
Whoa!
He can move!
Hell yeah!
Levochka!
That height!
That was a little low!
Sure.
Kozume...
You can actually move.
I mean... I am alive.
Kageyama doesn't have you beat at all!
Do you hear yourself?
Huh? Was that bad?
It's rude to compare me to someone who's clearly working hard.
But when I see something that amazing...
I can't help but feel like maybe I can do more too.
Shoulda figured, huh?
They're not the same as before either.
Nekoma
Karasuno
Make it count!
Got it!
Nice receive!
Like that wasn't an easy serve!
Left!
Hinata's not an easy target when it comes to receives anymore!
Right through three blockers!
Don't you dare get cocky just from bumping the damn ball!
I-I'm not!
Nekoma
Karasuno
Center!
I touched it!
Fukunaga!
To the left!
Kageyama!
Sorry! Back me up!
Asahi!
Whoa now, we're only in the first set!
That's rough.
Sorry! That was wide!
He's gonna lose an arm!
All yours, Kenma!
All right!
Hell yeah!
Wait.
Huh?
A reaching foul?
He made it look like a dump to draw the foul?
I might actually be good at this.
Just one more point!
Nekoma
Karasuno
Nice receive!
Go for it!
Synchronized attack!
Not this again.
There!
What?!
Here's our chance!
Karasuno's consistently attacking with their whole team.
They sure are making Nekoma's defense move.
Get it over!
He'll be lucky to even get that over!
Go again!
Here it comes!
One more go!
Room to run...
Secured!
I can hardly believe my eyes!
The entire Karasuno team misread that play!
This will cost Karasuno the first set.
Nekoma
Karasuno
Which means Nekoma takes the lead!
Well, that misread was a part of it, sure.
Huh?
On Kozume's return there,
he saw the spikers all moving in for the attack and aimed just between them.
It was also right along the path that Kageyama took to be ready for the set.
Right where their positions cross, and opposite the libero's side.
That was on me!
More than most teams,
Karasuno is built around its offense.
And that focus on the attack is what pushed them to mess up just now.
Their greatest strength is their weakness.
We certainly saw Kozume make use of it.
The whole Karasuno team is turning into Shouyou.
May Shorty always be in good health.
What do you mean?
Like, "Why him?"
I'm not all that athletic.
I see.
So, is your high school's team good?
Um, I'm not so sure.
They said it used to be good, but then it went downhill.
But only recently...
I'd say it's a pretty good team.
What school do you—
Kenma!
Kuro.
Gotta go.
Oh, hey! Kenma!
See you later, Shouyou.
"See you later"?
Imagine that.
What?
You don't know that kid, right?
Never seen you acting all friendly like that.
Took me by surprise.
That's...
Why is that, actually?
Go, go, Nekoma! Go, go, Nekoma!
Gotta be rough for Karasuno.
No doubt.
Racking up points with powerful serves would be great and all.
But we're not really at that level.
If you can get points by serving, go for it.
Here you go.
Thanks.
'Kay.
That sounds as wimpy as
"Anyone who wants seconds, feel free."
It's like you said, Kuro.
There's no perfect strategy to any play.
If Shouyou always scores ten points,
we just need to take two or three of those away.
Wow, Kenma's way more into this than usual!
Nekoma
Karasuno
Time to regroup!
Now we strike back!
Bring it!
Are they targeting number ten again?
Got it!
He has no room to run!
They forced him to receive it up front so he can't do the fast attack!
Wow, he cut across the court!
With a broad jump...
Nice, Hinata!
He didn't need to use Shouyou for that play.
But...
Gonna take more than that to stop our fast attack.
Gave him too much room.
Guess so.
I thought it looked good, though.
Shouyou.
Huh?
Stay full of surprises.
Let's get one!
Wh-What happened, Hinata?
Nekoma
Karasuno
If we lose one more set, it's all over.
Nice receive!
"What if they lose?"
Left!
Quit throwing a wet blanket on 'em before it's even over.
All right!
Did I use that phrase right?
More or less.
Forget what's to come. Watch them now.
See how much better we all are.
Take it in.
All right!
Good eye!
Bokuto, you're getting overbearing.
Thanks!
Huh?
Sorry about him.
It's fine.
It's hard to look at things in a new way,
but it feels good!
Nekoma
Karasuno
Long-awaited Face-off!
Volleyball Nationals Third Round
Nekoma (Tokyo)
Karasuno (Miyagi)
Sets
Score
Nekoma digs their claws in and are just one point behind yet again.
Weren't they ahead?
Hinata is entering the court.
I go to take a crap and when I get back they've lost the first set!
Let's see if he'll be able to score once again like earlier.
Yeah...
Hilarious!
Why don't people watch on their own tablets?
Long-awaited Face-off!
Volleyball Nationals Third Round
Nekoma (Tokyo)
Karasuno (Miyagi)
Sets
Score
That was a short serve!
Are they aiming for Hinata again?
Nekoma, was it?
Tanaka comes in from the left!
Nekoma connects!
Definitely never wanna play a team like them,
but they make for great entertainment.
Yamamoto takes advantage of their space!
Karasuno receives!
Long-awaited Face-off!
Volleyball Nationals Third Round
Nekoma (Tokyo)
Karasuno (Miyagi)
Sets
Score
They dig it out again!
What tenacious defense!
Sucks to be Karasuno!
Bet they're pretty pissed they can't score.
Think they are? Think it hurts?
Bet it does.
Good luck, boys!
Not that I care.
Karasuno's back with their synchronized offense!
Hinata comes in from the middle!
But right behind him is Azumane with a lightning-fast back row attack!
But look at that persistence!
Nekoma continues to persevere!
They make it sound like the kitty cats are the only ones trying.
Nekoma has its persistent defense,
Fukunaga keeps it going!
and Karasuno's got persistent offense.
Yamamoto jumps in and returns the ball!
Again and again, they have all their spikers play decoy.
The only difference is whether they're holding the ground or the air.
And Karasuno has another opportunity! Will they finally be able to score?
Doesn't he get it already?
Tendou's tough on the commentators.
But taking to the air over and over like that the way the crows do is gonna take its toll.
And worst of all...
the kitty cats know it.
All right...
Time to drag the crows back down to the ground!
Here it is! Here it is!
Synchronized attack!
Sometimes what looks like the hardest route is actually the easiest.
Hell yeah!
Wow, that was rough! Well played by Karasuno!
That's why I hate those guys.
Nekoma
Karasuno
How long have we been at this?
Feels like the fifth set already.
Is it not?
It's only the start of the second!
Plenty more of the match to play!
Still got a ways to go.
Get lost! You guys are like furnaces!
Damn. They keep attacking together.
I think this is still better than the interhigh qualifiers.
You forget we're playing Karasuno or something?
No, that's not what I meant.
Don't worry.
Also, there are only three sets in a match,
so it couldn't possibly be the fifth.
We're wearing them down.
No one has unlimited stamina.
Oh, I guess you're right.
That goes for us too, though.
Kenma.
Stop. I don't want to hear it.
Let's show 'em what we're made of!
Enough already!
They've still in good shape.
Make it good, Tsukishima!
Fukunaga, move up!
Here's our chance!
Go for the broad jump!
All right!
Huh?
Scared of me, are ya?
What?! Yeah right!
Lev.
He's right.
Chill out, moron.
I'll get the next one!
You just get me the ball!
Long-awaited Face-off!
Volleyball Nationals Third Round
Nekoma (Tokyo)
Karasuno (Miyagi)
Sets
Score
They're aiming for the front again,
but the libero Nishinoya has it covered!
Yes!
Get 'em!
The ball goes left.
A powerful straight spike!
Will they be able to get it up?!
Shou isn't having much luck today.
Long-awaited Face-off!
Volleyball Nationals Third Round
Nekoma (Tokyo)
Karasuno (Miyagi)
Sets
Score
Get it!
Nice backup!
Karasuno gets it up, but now they're out of position!
Like that ever stopped them before.
All right!
Nice, nice, Haiba! Nice, nice, Haiba!
Connect
Do it again!
Wow.
They saw it coming.
There were three blockers.
They're climbing their way up!
Nekoma
Karasuno
Lev.
Next time the ball's on their side,
if Shouyou is open and running to position,
I want three of you blocking him.
It's probably about time.
How did you know we should put everyone on Hinata?
You're scaring me, Kenma.
Notice how he hasn't been on the attack as much?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
When we hit him with a good serve.
That's not all.
They're not just making him receive.
They're using me too.
At the start of the set, Shouyou bumped it up and then ran for the broad jump, yeah?
But next time on that rotation, and again now...
They used me to get in the way and keep him off the right side.
I thought it was just a fluke at first.
But it's definitely intentional.
Working hard to keep him down...
Shouyou loves to jump, so when he can't,
he'll get frustrated and panic.
That overpowered spike out of bounds is proof.
And like any good setter, he doesn't want to have that hang around in a spiker's mind.
So I knew the next time he was ready,
Shouyou would get the ball.
You're really scaring me, Kenma.
Me too.
And me.
That's all we need.
Like I said, there's no perfect way to stop an attack.
With Karasuno, we just need to steal a few points they'd normally get.
That'll stress them out enough to see them start to slip up.
One slip-up turns to two, then three.
It's about paths, not points.
We block him from moving.
Stop his approach, and we clip his wings.
Kenma!
What now? You hungry or something?
Your mom gave me some shrimp crackers. Want some?
Beating a game feels worse than getting a game over in it.
Huh?
Let's go!
Let's do this!
Kageyama.
Give us another good one, Fukunaga!
Left!
All right!
Nice one, Asahi!
Don't sweat it!
Once they can't use him as a decoy anymore,
it gets much easier for us to block.
Even if we don't make him receive or block his path,
we just need him second-guessing.
"Should I get the ball or leave it for them?"
He's much more focused on the receive than ever.
I touched it!
Shorty's never seemed so out of the play before.
He's going to try and do it all.
Receive. Get a running start.
Let's score here!
But trying doesn't mean doing.
Don't forget about me!
All right!
Nice spike, Haiba!
Connect
They can pull off back row attacks?
Nice, nice, Haiba! Push it, push it, Haiba! Do it again!
I mean, it's Lev.
Make a mental note and get back in position!
All right! Here comes another!
That's going out!
Yeah!
Nekoma
Karasuno
Dammit!
Hinata ended up in the back row without scoring a single point.
Give us a good serve, Hinata!
Wow.
I'm impressed.
All right!
You're fun to play against.
Let's get this point!
Nice receive!
This is our match where there's no extra lives!
Yeah! Go!
Go!
This is just a time waster.
It was just the same old thing.
Stay full of surprises.
Shouyou!
You're up.
R-Right!
All right! Let's hype things up!
Wow... I didn't see this coming.
Big events like this don't happen every day.
We can't go packing it up after just two sets!
Nekoma
Karasuno
Fukunaga!
Nice receive!
All right!
The setter stepped back!
Five attackers?!
Got the run-up I need!
His troublesome speed...
Got the run-up—
His jumps that get him up there with 190-cm tall blockers...
Dammit!
Got the run-up I need!
Once he's one step behind,
it's too late, and he's all but out.
Giving it 99% isn't enough.
It's coming over!
Let's score here!
Got it!
Got the run-up I—
Because if he can't jump with 100% effort...
Kageyama isn't interested.
Nice, nice, Haiba! Nice, nice, Haiba! Do it again!
Connect
All right!
No way...
They tried so hard too...
Just bad luck.
Why did this have to happen right now?
You okay?
I'm fine!
Sorry!
Everything's going according to plan,
so what's with the face?
You're telling me you wanna see him fly while you rip out all his feathers?
You're a real pain in the butt.
Is it too risky?
Is it worth a shot?
Is Hinata even up for it?
I need to break down the walls in front of our spikers.
That's a setter's job.
Without that setter, Kageyama,
I can't say that I sense any worth in you.
Hinata!
Nice receive.
Keep that up for me.
Uh, yeah, sure.
What's number ten on the black team in there for?
He's tiny and doesn't really get many shots in.
Why do they keep him in?
He was pretty good in the first set.
Really?
He can't do anything 'cause our team's making sure he can't!
Give us a good one!
It must be tough, Shouyou.
Kenma's trying to make my own receives keep me down.
The more he thinks about it, the more he wants an answer.
How can I receive the ball and still get room to run up?
The more frustrated he gets,
the more shortcuts he'll look for.
What now?
What can I do?
Go on and flail around.
Give us a good one!
Up front!
Going for the receive is keeping me down.
Game over.
I guess this is it.
But even still,
I can't just go for one or the other!
No receive means no spike!
We can't play volleyball if we don't keep the ball up!
If we want to score...
there aren't any shortcuts!
Kageyama.
Be brave out there.
I will.
Thanks.
Pave the way for him!
High ball!
Go on, then!
Jump!
High to the middle?!
Got my run-up!
Did he set it that high on purpose?
While we have three blockers?
Plus, this isn't an in-sync fast attack, and high sets are hard for most people.
Shouyou has always worked with a technically-sound setter and only pulled off quicks, so there's no way...
I know that you can jump higher.
And when you make those jumps,
you hear the sound of your feet kicking off the floor.
Yeah!
Fly
Nice, nice, Shouyou! Push it, push it, Shouyou! Do it again!
So that was on purpose?
Even when Shouyou's biggest strength is speed?
Did I just see you jump higher than ever?
And he can hit those high sets too?
I'm right in the middle of perfecting the "bam" jump!
Did you see that jump?
Talk about height.
Not a bad jump.
That set was amazing.
I was complimenting you!
Over the
blockers...
Right, in the
air longer
Shouyou
can hit
high sets
too
Shouyou
can hit
high sets
too
That wasn't
like the blocks
that barely
keep up...
That wasn't
like the blocks
that barely
keep up...
The timing's
totally different
That's right.
If magic and status effects are blocked and don't work,
you just have to go all-in on physical attacks, huh?
He doesn't need me to say a thing.
Kageyama, you got this!
It's out!
Close one.
It's Inuoka!
It's their quick number seven!
They're putting up defenses already.
Double shields: equipped!
So ready for this!
Their defense was solid enough already.
And now they put up even bigger walls?!
Shouldn't that be against the rules or something?!
If Shouyou gets another set like that again,
hold back on your block a bit.
Right!
He gets more air time than us.
'Kay!
Captain!
Daichi!
On it!
Nice receive!
They worked it out.
Huh?!
Gotcha!
Here comes another in the middle!
Again?
Hold back a bit...
And...
In the back!
Yeah!
Hinata was aiming for their fingertips!
Yeah, defenders must hate him for it.
That was awesome, Hinata!
What comes next?
All right!
Nekoma
Karasuno
Just one more point!
Get 'em, Hinata!
Move up!
Will it be Kuroo?
Center!
No!
I touched it!
Go for it!
Full-team synchronized attack!
I touched it!
Here's our chance!
Synchronized attack!
I knew it.
We face a new Shouyou every single time.
In the back!
Shouyou!
Nice job!
Nekoma
Karasuno
I thought that was a damn good straight spike!
It was.
What's up with your number ten?!
I'm not sure either.
Akane, we're just getting started!
Yeah, I know. It's just frustrating.
I know that doesn't make sense, but it just is!
They scored on the receive.
That's one set each.
Nekoma
Karasuno
But the team who wins the second set has the advantage.
And now number ten is back to normal.
I thought Kageyama wouldn't want anything to do with Shouyou not at 100%.
But if Shouyou's not at 100%, he'll set him up so he is.
Like a pair of monsters.
Quit acting all smug over dumb luck.
Ever try saying something nice?!
You weren't focused out there again, were you?
Let's give it to 'em! C'mon!
I'll get us 20 points!
You guys go ahead and get the other five.
Lemme tell you something.
When you're working out...
Instead of doing 100 normal sit-ups,
it's better to use weights that leave you barely able to do ten.
The hell are you talking about?
What?!
It's not the number that matters?!
Which means... what?
One heavy points is better than 20 normal ones?
Nod.
Don't "nod" out loud.
What the heck's a "heavy point"? Get 20!
Hey, did you know? When you work out...
Hey!
You gotta be more excited than that!
What, Shibayama?
That straight spike was awesome, yeah?
No, it's nothing.
When'd you master that?
Thanks, man!
All right!
He's good.
Yep.
Watch your timing with Shorty out there.
The last one was good.
I already told them.
Did you, now?!
What?
Just thought you sure talk a lot.
Talk about a sucker punch.
Kuro is good at motivating people.
Always has been.
That was close! Put your arms like this.
Hit it here and you'll be good.
Why not find someone who plays already?
It's gotta be boring playing with a newbie.
It's not!
You pick it up quick! And you're smart!
Y-You think?
Kuro moved in next door and invited me to play for the first time.
I was doomed the moment I let his compliment go to my head.
H-Hey, you free on Saturday?
Hiya. Come to watch?
Wanna play?
Yeah!
Here!
Dang it!
Here it comes!
Wow, nice work!
That's way cooler.
You're not gonna do that?
That's called a spike!
Super cool, right?
Can't do that unless you're tall, though.
You could always lower the net.
Don't you think it's better to get a taste of it first?
Easier to get good when you're having fun, you know.
Ow!
I hit it!
It was the most minor of things.
Nice spike! That was perfect!
But he would never forget that day.
Thank you very much!
Want another go?
I could just tell.
Yes!
Kenma! Let's play volleyball!
Kenma! Volleyball time!
Kenma!
Yeah, okay.
Brazil
vs. USA
Dang it!
All right!
Did you see that? Did you?!
He looked right, but just when you thought you knew, he sent it to the left!
It stopped raining, so can we stop watching and go out?
You're the one who brought this.
Bring the one from last week again next time.
Why?!
Kenma, you gotta be a setter!
You'd be like the team mastermind. It'd be cool!
Mastermind
The mastermind...
The setter doesn't have to move as much, either.
Well? Well?!
That was a lie.
Hurry up or someone will get the field first!
Hey, Tetsu!
I was just wondering if you might bring Kenma with you to play soccer sometimes.
I don't think he'd want to.
I know how it feels to not want to.
I'd bring him if he wanted to, but I don't think he does.
But he goes all-out for the stuff he likes, so don't worry!
Yeah, huh?
If you were just some socialite jock,
I wouldn't play with you.
Huh? What's with you attacking me all of a sudden?
If I didn't have to, I wouldn't work up a sweat.
I'd rather game than practice.
And I probably like watching volleyball more than playing.
But...
In the end, I guess feeling obligated to play isn't all that bad.
All right!
Call me Straight-striker Tora!
The whole team is a bunch of weirdos.
More?
More!
Go, go, Nekoma! Push it, push it, Nekoma!
Connect
The hard part is over.
It's time to have fun!
Woohoo!
Dunno what that's about, but...
And after our fun...
...one of our teams...
...will be out for good!
Karasuno High School Volleyball Team
Left!
Yeah!
Got somethin' to say?
You lookin' for a fight, city boy?
All right!
I'm Nekoma's ace.
Up front!
Nice receive!
High ball!
Center!
Ready, and...
I'll jump even higher, to the very top!
All right!
He was on that fast!
Damn it, damn it, damn it, damn it, that was so cool!
Number three, your receives were amazing!
Nice receive!
All right!
You've been terrifying ever since that day...
Yuu!
Can you block some balls for us?
Oh, actually, I'm done for the night.
Wanna come help us with spike practice again?
Sorry, but I'll pass.
Blockers, try not to jump horizontally if you can!
If you can make it in time, come to a stop...
...and then jump straight up.
Nice block! Let's score here!
I touched it!
Nice deflection! Let's score here!
Sorry!
I'm genuinely curious about this.
Why do you try so hard?
Tsukki, no need to play that hard.
It's exhausting when the rally goes that long.
I'm pretty sure this'd be over quicker...
if you stopped trying so hard!
I guess Tsukki's also the type to lose it when he gets tired.
You and Bokuto take the blame for him, y'know!
I oughta thank you.
Yeah, same.
Did you know watermelon seeds will sprout in your gut if you eat 'em?
Grow so big they burst—
Yeah? I'll be careful, then.
Hey, did you know Bokuto's—
Probably not, but that's fine.
Bokuto.
Kuroo!
Hey, hey, hey!
Focus your strength in your fingertips so
that they won't be blown away by the ball.
When you're going against a spiker one-on-one, you generally don't stand in front of their body.
Center yourself on their dominant arm instead.
Listen up, kiddo!
Read blocking takes persistence and endurance, but it's also...
the style of blocking where you get the last laugh.
All right!
Nekoma
Karasuno
No worries!
That impenetrable block of yours really ticks everyone off, yeah?
Well, I'm glad. Shows we did it right.
All right!
If I say so myself.
Get it!
Left!
Dammit! I can't beat him!
Center!
The net's the only place I stand a chance!
Here's your chance!
They're terrifying.
And because we're scared...
There's no time to think.
In the end, it's going to be a quick battle of heights in the middle.
How're you enjoying this these days?
Nekoma
Karasuno
Kenma!
Shouyou.
Remember when we met on the street the other day,
and you said you really didn't like volleyball that much?
Oh... yeah.
Kageyama, give us another good serve!
We can score here!
Get it!
Nice save!
All right!
Nice, nice, Kozume! Nice, nice, Kozume! Do it again!
There's something weird about you guys.
Like... you're rivals or something?
What? We're just...
friends.
We'll swap Lev out when he's up to serve.
Yeah!
Up for it, Tamahiko?
No, I don't think I'm ready.
Maybe not.
That honesty is what I like about you.
Nice receive!
The levelheadedness and courage it takes to say that is your strength.
All right!
Get in there.
Make it good, Tamahiko!
If they're putting a setter like me in as a pinch server,
Tamahiko, we're counting on you!
You got this!
the plan must be to let Kozume play setter till the end.
Normally, he'd be out of gas by this point.
Nekoma
Karasuno
Give us a good one!
On it!
All yours!
Sorry!
Azumane!
Ready, jump!
Yes!
Whoa!
See that?
It's headed over. Will they spike it? What now?
Do I make them reach over? Take the rebound? Send it back?
Yeah!
Bring it!
A tip?!
He knows!
It's mine!
Huh?
How about today? How did you like winning?
Next time,
I'll make you desperate to win,
And then I'll make you say,
"I hate losing!" or "That was a blast!"
You'll start talking differently about the match!
Hey, Kenma! You okay?
Did you hurt something?
This is fun.
Yeah!
Yes! Yes!
Nekoma
Karasuno
Fly
Connect
When the hero's dying, I heal him and make him fight.
Sometimes he goes down and I revive him to fight.
But from now on, I think I might at least feel sorry for forcing him to fight.
Still to the brink of death?
Don't worry.
People don't usually die in volleyball.
Fly
Connect
On it!
Full-team synchronized attack!
I touched it!
Nice receive!
I think I know exactly how Shouyou feels.
Even on the brink of death,
he pushes himself to beat the boss.
Always thinking contradicting thoughts.
"Don't die on me!"
Left!
Kenma!
"Not yet."
All right!
Nice receive!
Go get 'em, Kageyama!
Taketora.
Sorry!
Kenma?!
Idiot! The ball!
It's still up!
Nice, Daichi!
I'm worn out...
Exhausted...
Finish it off!
And I don't want it to end!
We can score here!
Left!
Go for it!
Too much sweat...
That was from the sweat.
You could see the ball slip.
That's what did it?
The sweat from everyone in that rally is on that ball.
That was awesome.
Tanaka, give us a good serve!
Wait, what?
Nekoma
Karasuno
It's over, you dumbass.
Nekoma
Whether we win,
or whether we lose,
no one dies.
No one comes back to life.
Evil doesn't prevail.
The world doesn't end.
A vast world doesn't await.
The Spring Tournament Begins!
But here we are in a 9x18 meter rectangle, giving everything just to keep a ball in the air.
Man, that was fun.
Kuro.
Thanks for introducing me to volleyball.
Uh, sure...
Huh?
Wait, wait, wait! Hang on now, you moron!
What? Why are you mad?
Line up!
Ugh. I guarantee I'll have a fever after this.
I wanna be on that court.
You were.
Really be on it.
I wanna play volleyball like that.
Thank you very much!
Never knew you could get through blocks like that.
No, yeah!
Which is it?
Bet you'd hit 'em like home runs outta the court if we played the kitty cats.
Wh-What?! No, I wouldn't!
Never knew the little demon crow could attack a high set, though.
I won't be beat!
Thanks, Tsukki.
You were awesome!
Thank you very much!
Tokyo
Nekoma
We'll save the nitpicking for later.
You boys played well. Thank you.
Thank you very much!
Man, it's over already? Sure doesn't feel like it.
It's all over,
but I'm glad I was with you guys these past three years.
Don't you gimme that, Kai! Seriously, stop!
Jeez! What's with all of you?!
Could you at least crouch?
I'm floating over here!
People are gonna think I busted my leg again!
Kenma!
I look—
I look forward to playing again.
Hey! That was my line!
What? Who cares?
Kenma.
Let's play again next year!
Yeah, let's.
Kenma! We're leaving!
Yeah, right.
See you around, Shouyou.
Yeah, catch ya around!
We won't say goodbye
Don't need a promise
Because we will see each other again
A horizon like a bite out of an orange
A bittersweet light so dazzling
Sweat pouring out and voices bellowing
Shoulders bumping as we laugh and cry
As we head for tomorrow and an orange sky
Our wings are spread wide
One more second, just one more second
For us to savor our most irreplaceable moment
I'm sure
Our backs were small
Yet they carried our big dreams all this way
The future we've reached didn't go exactly as hoped
But it was a hell of a time all the same
We ran out of breath but we kept running
What we were chasing was the fire in our hearts
We've all been tied to this one moment, never to be repeated
What did we envision? What did we hope to accomplish?
All you can do is try to imagine
I'm sure
So sure
I'm positive you'll come to understand it one day
So don't be afraid to make mistakes
You're fine being you
Like a slightly bitter orange the aftertaste lingers
One more second, just one more second
Don't be torn by regret as you go
You might unexpectedly start yearning again for these treasured times
Don't stop in place, don't look back
Keep on forging your path and you'll be fine
I'm sure
So sure
Looks like the match on Court A won't be long.
Yeah, that's tourney favorite Itachiyama for ya.
Wow! He's even taller up close!
He's faking most of his height with that hair.
I'm not deaf, you know.
Sorry, babe. Can I have a sec?
Yeah, sure.
I'm gonna check out the shop.
Thanks!
Losers
Welcome to the other side!
Someone snap a pic of that face!
We're gonna show it to Mika!
Listen. Don't let it get to you.
Every team here save one is gonna wind up losing.
Only difference is when. It's no big deal.
Don't tell me you really thought you could win the whole thing.
Sure, most of us don't absolutely 100% believe we'll win.
C'mon. You're not even gonna get mad?
Where's the fun in that?
It doesn't really even matter whether we can win or not.
We don't stop because we can't win, nor do we play because we can win.
I'm well aware, dumbass!
Watch the language now, Daishou. I'm gonna start recording.
Rich of you to get mad over a fight you started!
Screw off and shut your face!
All set?
Y-Yeah!
How long were you there?
What should we have for lunch?
Maybe omelets?
Nice choice!
What's his deal?
He's a riot.
Bet there's lots of great food around here.
Most of us don't absolutely 100% believe we'll win.
And maybe it's not about "believing" for them,
but there are definitely guys who are focused on winning.
Kamomedai
Takagiyama
They'll be up against Kamomedai High School in the quarterfinals.
Thank you very much!
The quarterfinals...
Are you paying attention to me because I'm small?
Even though being smaller puts you at a disadvantage in volleyball,
it doesn't make you completely helpless!
I caught your second and third matches.
Nice work.
It's about time we see who's the real...
Little Giant!