It's no good!
The fire has spread to the forest in District Three!
Can't we get more fire choppers?
At this rate, the entire mountain will be destroyed!
Damn it. Why is it spreading so fast?
Wh-What happened here?
The trees are all uprooted.
Did something crash-land here?
No, we haven't had any reports like that.
Mont Blanc... Mont Blanc...
Professor Reinhardt!
My Mont Blanc!
Professor!
Let me go!
No, Professor! It's too dangerous!
His signal is dead...
I've lost contact with Mont Blanc!
What's the matter, Gesicht?
Oh, no, it's nothing.
You seem tired lately.
Are you overworking yourself?
Maybe you should take some time off...
I'm fine.
No need to worry.
Switzerland: Forest Fires in the Canton of Lucerne Continue
As you can see, white smoke is still rising after two days,
and scattered fires are visible.
According to investigators on the scene,
the robot assigned to
the Swiss Forestry Service, Mont Blanc,
was found in pieces at the site of the forest fire.
Mont Blanc was a world-renowned mountain guide
known for befriending scores of
children and mountain climbers alike.
He also poured himself into programming a tree-clearing
strategy that allows us to coexist with nature.
Condolences for the beloved Mont Blanc
are coming in from all over the world.
Yes, this is Gesicht.
Understood.
I'll be right there.
It's work.
I've got to go.
Huh? But what about your breakfast?
Helena.
Shall we take a trip when I can take time off?
I should be getting more rest, right?
I never expected to hear you say that.
The victim resided in this apartment.
Bernard Lanke, 42 years old.
He was a leader of a group
that defends the Robot Rights Laws.
Was he human?
Yes, he was.
Man, this is awful.
You there!
I'd appreciate if you didn't just
walk all over my crime scene.
Inspector, he's the one sent from Europol.
Nice to meet you.
I see. Pardon me.
I'm Inspector Wallace with the city police.
Nice to meet you.
As you can see, the place has been turned upside down.
It'll take us a while to figure out if anything has been taken.
Actually, I don't believe this is the work of a thief.
Huh? How can you be sure?
There's no sign anything is missing.
Come on. The room's been trashed. How can you tell?
I just can.
This room was merely damaged.
Then what do you make of this?
Why are things shoved into the
victim's head to look like horns?
Yes, it's me.
Right.
What?
Someone broke through a checkpoint!
Get an ambulance right away!
Were you the only one attacked, patrolman?
R-Robby was also at the checkpoint...
My partner...
I mean, a patrol-bot...
Model PRC-1332.
I can't believe a patrol-bot was destroyed so easily.
Inspector!
A male suspect in his twenties in
a red cap with tattoos on both arms
seems to have fled toward
the old city's redevelopment zone.
Got it. Pair up and search—
Hey! I said to pair up!
Damn it! Europol, my ass!
Stop resisting!
I didn't do anything!
There are traces of paint from
the patrol-bot on that steel pipe.
A drug addict, huh?
You're high on a drug called "noi."
Ingested about 40 minutes ago.
Is that about right?
Who's your dealer?
A guy named Shultz on Karl-Heinz Street.
What time did you meet him?
A-Around five this morning.
If the dealer corroborates your account, you have an alibi.
That's around the time when Bernard Lanke was murdered.
M-Murdered?
You only attacked the patrolman
with a pipe to avoid arrest for illicit drugs.
And you destroyed a patrol-bot, aka Robby.
I can read you your rights and arrest you quietly...
Please don't shoot me!
Relax.
This gun only shoots sleeping gas.
I'm made in such a way that I can't hurt humans.
I'm a robot.
Yes? Who is it?
My name is Gesicht. I'm a special investigator from Europol.
How can I help you?
You're Robby's wife?
Yes, I am.
I'm afraid I have bad news.
Would you like some tea?
Being a robot as well, I'm sure you'll just
go through the motions of drinking.
By living as humans do, they say we robots
can upgrade our human-like senses.
I suppose that's true.
But it's difficult to understand the joy of drinking tea.
Especially for an outdated model like me.
I work as a maid for this family.
And they have a little boy.
A human boy, of course.
The family had adopted a dog before the boy was born.
The boy and the dog grew up like siblings.
But the dog died.
Would you like me to erase a portion of your memory data?
Please don't erase the memories of my husband.
This is horrible.
The victim is Bernard Lanke.
One of the leaders of a group defending the Robot Laws.
I see.
There must be tons of people who think badly of a scholar
who insists on protecting the rights of robots like he did.
And this is how the body was found.
What's with the horns?
I'm not sure.
However...
This is...
This is the site where Mont Blanc
of the Swiss Forestry Service was destroyed.
Horns.
Are you saying the same person
is responsible for both incidents?
Breaking a sturdy robot like Mont Blanc
into pieces is impossible for humans.
In addition, at the time of his murder,
there was no trace of any other
human presence in Lanke's apartment.
"No trace of any other human presence"...
Hold it, Gesicht.
Lanke was human!
Yes.
Article 13 of the International Robot Laws says,
"A robot may not harm or kill a human being."
If there's a robot out there that can kill a human,
it'd be the first time since the case eight years ago.
I'll find the perpetrator.
Whether they be a robot or
a human, there is a devil inside them.
A strange pedestal, isn't it?
Originally, the plan was to build
a bronze statue of Mont Blanc on it.
However, Mont Blanc objected to it.
He said it would be wrong to ruin the scenic view
of the Alps with a bronze statue of himself.
Not only that, he insisted
he would one day become scrap iron.
He wanted to be chopped up, melted down, and recycled.
But he was still in his prime.
Mont Blanc was a true hero.
He joined the 39th Central Asian War as
a member of the peace-keeping forces.
He not only helped the Kingdom of Persia
restore peace from the chaos and turmoil,
but he also managed to apprehend
terrorists in hiding without bloodshed.
Without him, Asia could never have
reached the state of peace it has now.
He was also a poet.
He was able to sing with birds and
converse with the trees of the forest.
Those people over there volunteered
to do this work with no compensation.
They all loved Mont Blanc, my son.
Mont Blanc was the guardian angel of the mountains.
In three days, tens of thousands...
no, hundreds of thousands will come to
the memorial to mourn the death of Mont Blanc.
Detective, this was no accident.
They say Mont Blanc was destroyed because of
the huge tornado that happened just before the forest fire,
but that's not true at all.
Detective, please catch the person responsible for this.
If you do, then I swear I'll use these hands to...
He was the pride of Switzerland,
nay, the entire human race.
May he remain forever in our hearts...
Are you awake, Gesicht?
Your maintenance check is finished.
Thank you, Professor Hoffman.
So, how did it go?
Oh, nothing out of the ordinary.
Except...
Yes?
Many people think robots don't get tired,
but when you're this similar to humans,
a robot can feel exhaustion.
To put it another way, the human body
itself is nothing but a mechanism.
With too much use, any mechanism can become fatigued.
Fatigued?
Looks like you're dealing with rather difficult cases.
I saw Mont Blanc's memorial on TV,
but I had to turn it off to keep from crying.
Some media have reported a theory that he self-destructed
from an electromagnetic anomaly in his body.
But as an expert on the subject,
I don't believe an advanced robot like him
could experience such an elementary problem.
Think you'll track down whoever killed
a robot that was loved by everyone?
I guess it can't be that easy.
On the other hand, the other case
you're investigating looks complicated too.
The victim named Lanke...
I saw him several times on TV debates,
and it's not surprising he was targeted.
He wasn't necessarily doing anything wrong,
but he had a sharp tongue.
It's like he was looking down on everyone.
That was bound to make some enemies.
The complete opposite of Mont Blanc.
A robot and a human.
One with no enemies and the other with too many enemies.
No wonder you're exhausted,
juggling two cases at once like that.
Can I ask you a question?
What is it?
Is it possible for a human to infiltrate
a room without leaving any biological traces?
You mean traces so minuscule that
your sensors cannot detect them?
Yes.
That's an interesting question.
I wonder...
That's my homework for next time.
Sorry about all that.
This is supposed to be a place for you to relax.
No more shop talk.
I've been talking to my wife about taking time off for a trip.
Oh, how nice.
We have to consider her schedule too,
so I don't know when it will happen.
Traveling is good.
Data shows that seeing the world yields
positive results for artificial intelligence.
How about doing something bold and going to Japan?
Japan?
Yeah, I went there once at the invitation
of one of my research buddies.
Tokyo is exotic and interesting.
Japan, huh?
I'll talk to my wife about it.
By the way, Gesicht, are you still having
the dream you told me about before?
Yes.
I'm not trying to put you on the spot or anything,
but I'm quite intrigued by dreams
generated by artificial intelligence.
It's been academically proven that
artificial intelligence also carries a subconscious.
Even so, it's rare to find a robot that actually has dreams.
When you feel up to it, could you tell me about it?
Sure.
Twentieth-century psychiatrist Freud
once said something to this effect.
"Dreams are expressions of reality,
not just products of our imagination."
Excuse me.
Is this a patrol-bot?
Yeah, seems like it.
The crime lab said they're done,
so I'm supposed to get rid of it.
Robby...
May I take a look?
Yeah, sure.
Feel free to take whatever parts you want.
They're junk, after all.
You can have the whole body for 500 ZEUS.
Something wrong?
Oh, no.
It's nothing.
Nothing at all.
This is your husband's memory chip.
I may be overstepping, but I thought you might want it.
Oh, not at all.
I'm sincerely grateful.
Thank you.
I should be going now.
Wait!
Would you mind inserting it into me?
The memories could be painful.
They might cause you to malfunction.
If that happens, I'll take it out right away.
He's... right here.
Ma'am, you have to stop!
Memories of his last moments are also stored there!
I'm taking it out!
What could this be?
I wonder what it is.
What do you see?
Let me project it.
This was when Robby stopped a car
at the checkpoint with his partner.
This is the suspect.
I'm so sorry.
I shouldn't have brought this to you.
I don't know how to apologize.
It's not that.
My husband reacted to
the criminal's steel pipe immediately.
He had his stun gun at the ready.
I understand.
It was odd that your husband,
a patrol-bot, was attacked so easily.
This is definitely an unusual case—
That's not what I mean.
Take a closer look.
I can see it because the memory chip is inside me.
His partner was attacked.
Up until this moment, my husband had
registered the criminal's movements.
But in the next moment,
he was distracted by something.
That's the apartment where Lanke was murdered!
Pause it, please!
What is that?
I'll zoom in.
It's not a bird.
Why didn't the forensics team notice this?
You would've never spotted it unless
you had this memory chip inserted.
My husband caught sight of this shadow in an instant,
and his identification system analyzed what it was.
But if it could jump from building to building like this...
Yes.
But this...
isn't a robot.
A murder in a room with no trace of human activity.
The death of a robot loved by everyone.
Horns.
Identity confirmed.
Please enter.
Are you a robot, Detective?
Yes.
Wow, I sure couldn't tell from your appearance.
If you get too close to him, your artificial intelligence
could be compromised by his electromagnetic waves.
Use this protective gear.
I'll be okay.
I'm impervious to electromagnetic waves.
What?
I'm made of a special alloy, although I may not look like it.
That so?
Well, if you say so, but do be careful.
So far, four robots have fallen victim to him.
It's a laughably desperate barricade, isn't it?
At the end of the day, humans can't control
their fear without pitiful measures like this.
Brau-1589.
Welcome, Robot Model HRS-0288, Inspector Gesicht.
So you are the most advanced detective robot?
It seems your identification system is still functioning.
It is indeed. Thank you.
It's actually more sensitive than before.
Being deprived of the mode of locomotion, I can't help
but be curious about what's happening out there.
I came here today because I wanted to ask you something.
What is it?
What crossed the mind of a certain robot
when it killed a human eight years ago?
A legal scholar named Bernard Lanke was murdered,
but there were no traces of human presence at the scene.
Was the killer a human—
Or a robot?
And if it was a robot, why would it do such a thing?
The humans have already examined the deepest
recesses of my murderous artificial intelligence.
They believed there must've been a defect,
but they couldn't find a thing.
My artificial intelligence had no flaws at all.
Can you imagine how terrified
the humans were when they found that out?
That's why they keep me locked up in a place like this.
If they're that afraid, they can just
pull out this spear. Then I'd die.
But they can't even do that.
Inspector Gesicht.
If you want to know more about
someone who's committed a murder,
why don't we exchange memory chips?
You might learn something new.
Here are some images I printed of Mont Blanc's
destruction and Lanke's murder scene.
What do you think these horns mean?
Among the ancient myths of Europe,
the god of death had horns.
Herne the Hunter, who takes the souls of warriors,
was also called the "Horned King."
In Greek mythology, Hades is the king of the underworld.
Or perhaps, the lord of the
underworld in Roman mythology,
Pluto.
Whoever did these will strike again.
Mont Blanc, among the most advanced
of all robots, was destroyed so easily.
The answer should be clear to you by now.
The top-class robots created with
the best technologies in the world.
Robots who can also be weapons of mass destruction.
You know the answer already, do you not?
Including you, there are six more.
I'm working.
Don't just stand there. It's distracting.
I'm sorry to have entered without your permission, sir.
The security seems to have been disabled.
It's not safe, considering your blindness.
No burglar would come all the way
to this wasteland to steal from me.
But, Sir Duncan—
That's enough.
Are you the new butler?
Yes, sir.
Bet they sent over yet another good-for-nothing.
Your name?
My name is North No. 2, sir.
What a dull and tasteless name.
The staffing agency told me
you have a military background.
Yes, sir.
During the 39th Central Asian War,
I was a butler for the commander-in-chief
of the British Army.
A butler for a soldier, huh?
You must be a rather boorish sight.
I wear a cape in the presence of others.
I see.
So your whole body is a weapon.
Make me some tea, will you?
Certainly, sir.
As for the type, I want...
Please rest assured.
All of your data is already downloaded.
My data, huh?
Before I came here, I had the chance to see a film.
The Queen on the Satellite Orbit.
I was deeply moved by how the music
and images came together as one.
Is that from your "data" as well?
No, I was profoundly moved from the bottom of my heart.
That film is over ten years old.
Here you are.
Every score I composed was a huge hit,
sweeping all the film music awards.
I was lauded as a blind musical genius.
Reviews from the media must
surely be in that skull of yours too.
"Even the genius Paul Duncan has run out of talent."
Am I right?
What a load of bollocks.
If I felt the urge, I could compose
as many scores as I want.
My genius is alive and well.
I write the notes, and the people burst into applause.
They would leave the theater in tears.
It's not that I can't compose. I won't.
Not for such stupid films.
But you were working just now.
It was a beautiful piece.
It's not for a film.
That piece is for me.
Only for me.
This is just like your name.
Sir?
Dull and tasteless.
A beautiful piece?
Don't make me laugh.
A rubbish military weapon like you
has no right to talk about my art!
My apologies, sir.
How many did you kill?
Sir?
I'm asking how many people
you killed in the Central Asian War.
The Robot Laws forbid me from harming humans.
I see. So you killed your own kind.
How many robots did you destroy?
Too many to count?
Go away.
A tasteless meal becomes even blander with you around.
I will take my leave, sir.
What are you doing?
Don't touch my piano!
My apologies, sir.
You compose with your piano only, I see.
What about it?
You have so much cutting-edge
musical equipment available to you.
That stuff is just like you.
A fake violin, a fake trumpet, a fake orchestra.
Pretend as they might, they're nothing but machines.
That's why I don't put in artificial eyes.
Anything I could see with the help of machines is fake.
I have no need for it.
The real scenery is in my memories.
The real scenery...
The landscape of my hometown,
captured when I was able to see.
When you were a child in Bohemia.
Is that from the data too?
There's nothing that truly matters in such nonsense.
The scenery of my hometown...
The green fields...
The gentle breeze...
And...
that golden glow.
I will turn that scenery into music!
I told you not to touch my piano!
My apologies, sir.
If a machine like you were to play from a score,
any notes produced would be fake!
Sir Duncan.
Please pardon my imposition, but I heard you
moaning as you slept in your bedroom last night.
But it also sounded like you were humming.
And I believe that melody would fit perfectly
within the piece you are composing now.
At the section where you always stop midway.
It's not precise, but it went like this.
Get out!
I have no need for a robot like you.
Leave this residence!
But...
That's an order. Leave!
I'd...
I'd like to learn how to play piano.
What did you say?
As you say, no matter what I might play,
it may always be fake.
But I'd like to get as close as possible to the real thing.
A weapon like you could never play the piano!
Stop it!
That's nothing for a tool of mass destruction to touch!
You belong on the battlefield!
That's exactly why.
That's exactly why I'd like to learn to play piano.
Because I don't ever want to go to a battlefield again.
Mom!
Wait, Mom!
Mom, don't go!
Mom!
Are you there, North No. 2?
I told you not to come into my bedroom.
Sir Duncan, your breakfast is ready.
I thought I fired you.
Are you still there?
How many times do I have to tell you?
Don't touch my piano!
Sir Duncan, please listen.
I think I've gotten a little better.
"Gotten a little better"?
The only improvement a machine can
make is to play with more precision!
I will try to play the melody you hum in your sleep, sir.
The sounds you produce are not music!
These bloody things!
"Just input the data, and you can create infinite melodies"?!
That's not music at all!
You're breaking the instruments.
Are you trying to protect your fellow machines?
Tell me, then. How many of your own kind did you destroy?
Take off your cape and show the world
the hideous weapon that is your body!
With that body of yours,
how many of your kind did you kill?
Even a weapon of mass destruction is programmed
to behave obediently in front of its master, huh?
Very well.
I'll give you some genuine and accurate data about me.
The reason I moan in my sleep...
I've been tormented by a nightmare for so many years.
No, not a nightmare. It really happened.
My real name isn't Paul Duncan.
It's Paulo Holy.
I was born into a poor family in Bohemia.
My father died before I was old enough to remember.
I was struck by a serious illness from birth,
and my eyesight was poor,
so my only joy was singing songs.
My mother was a beautiful woman.
Even in rags, she would turn the heads
of men when she walked down the street.
That's why that parvenu approached her.
And my mother became blinded by her greed for his money.
She must've felt burdened by me.
I was sickly and stood in her way.
So she abandoned me!
I was sent to a boarding school in England.
I had no friends, and my weak
body left me bullied year-round.
But I was desperate to continue my study of music.
I must've strained myself continuously because,
at one point, I developed a persistent fever,
and even my music studies could not continue.
I was sent around from hospital
to hospital, but my condition worsened.
The doctors gave up on me,
and I never heard from my mother.
I thought I was going to die.
What a fitting last moment for an abandoned child.
That's when a Japanese doctor appeared.
Technically, he wasn't a doctor because he was unlicensed.
I will save your life.
But you might go blind as a result.
The surgery was a success.
But just as the unlicensed doctor said,
my eyesight deteriorated day by day.
With the little time I had left,
I threw myself even more into the study of music.
Music was all I had.
More music!
More!
And finally, the darkness came.
A few years later, I was informed of my mother's death.
She never was able to marry that parvenu.
I heard she died all alone.
Serves her right for abandoning her child.
But you know what? This castle belonged to that parvenu.
From Paulo Holy to the genius Paul Duncan.
I became a maestro of the music world
and made the castle mine.
Mother!
This is what you wanted.
This is what you sought at
the cost of abandoning your child!
Now, Mother, I will show you what is truly important.
The landscape of our hometown that you deserted!
I will turn that magnificent scenery into music!
And I'll show you that there are some
things people should never abandon!
Sir Duncan.
Your mother—
Silence!
I'll write you a letter of recommendation.
Leave this place tomorrow.
I'd like to learn how to play piano.
Because I don't ever want to go to a battlefield again.
I guess he improved a little.
Blasted machine must be recharging himself
in preparation for tomorrow's departure.
Is he having a nightmare?
Robots have dreams too?
"It's not that I can't compose. I won't," huh?
Hey.
North No. 2.
North No. 2! Hey!
He really left, huh?
Maybe I really can't compose anymore.
How long are you going to make me wait?
When is the replacement butler coming—
Hello, my name is Marshall from MCM Pictures.
Oh, you're just a movie guy.
Is something wrong, Sir Duncan?
No, I just fired a butler robot the other day.
So, what do you want?
Well, I'm actually calling about a film score.
A job offer, huh?
Tell me the details. I might be interested.
Thank you, sir.
I was wondering if you would consent
to the reuse of one of your old scores.
What? You're not asking for a new piece?
Oh, no, not at all!
It was my understanding that you had retired, sir.
Use it however you want.
Oh, Sir Duncan—
There is a new message.
This is Russell from the Planning Office
at the British Philharmonic Orchestra.
This is in regards to the performance
of your suite we discussed before.
Unfortunately, we have decided
to cancel it due to various circumstances.
We are very sorry about this.
If another opportunity arises, we will...
I heard you moaning,
and I believe that melody would fit perfectly.
Sir Duncan.
I have returned.
What now?
I thought I told you to leave.
I went to Bohemia.
To your birthplace.
What business did you have there?
I went to collect songs.
In the process of collecting many
folk songs from that region,
I found it.
The melody you hum in your sleep.
I will sing it now.
Stop!
I don't want to hear a machine sing!
Don't intrude on my nightmare any further!
Humans have things we would rather forget!
But, sir, your dream is not a nightmare.
It's not something that should be erased like my dreams.
Just as you said, I'm nothing but a weapon.
In the 39th Central Asian War,
I neutralized many enemy robots...
No, I destroyed tens of thousands of my own kind.
Those memories—the memories
of killing countless of my kind—
are played back again and again in my artificial brain.
I met an old man in Bohemia.
He was very knowledgeable about folk songs,
and he knew that particular song as well.
He also remembered that there was
a wonderful singer of that song.
Your mother.
The data I have in my mind about
you includes that of your mother.
Your mother did not abandon you
when you were suffering from illness.
She approached a multimillionaire,
Jonathan Thorn, to attain treatment.
That's how she afforded the astronomical fee
for the doctor who saved your life.
You were never abandoned.
Your mother was right by your side when you went blind.
But sensing your hatred toward her,
she couldn't extend her hand.
No.
That can't be.
It's true.
When you remember your hometown,
are you not excluding a very important memory?
The old man in the village told me how you and
your mother held hands and sang this song together
as you watched the sun setting
into the fields of your homeland.
Mom...
I apologize.
It's only the song of a machine.
Your dream isn't a nightmare.
Not like mine.
North No. 2...
don't ever go back to the battlefield.
Let's practice the piano.
Yes, sir.
North No. 2!
Hey, North No. 2!
Yes, sir?
It's finally finished. Give it a listen.
I would love to listen to it, sir.
However, right now...
Huh? What's the matter?
Something is approaching this direction.
"Something"?
Is it a friend visiting you, perhaps?
Did you hear the news from Switzerland a few days ago, sir?
The news from Switzerland?
Oh, about the robot called Mont Blanc
getting destroyed in a tornado?
A tornado occurred about 100 km
from here just a moment ago.
Some sort of threat is approaching.
H-Hey!
I shall return soon.
North No. 2!
North No. 2.
North...
What in the world...
What is happening?
North No. 2...
This is...
that song.
The song is spreading across the entire sky.
North No. 2 is...
North No. 2 is singing.
Stop singing out there and come home soon.
North No. 2,
it's time for our piano practice.
It's really awesome!
Really?
Is that a snail?
Yes.
Nice to meet you.
You must be Atom.
Yes.