Special!
The Spring Tournament of Their Youth
Next, we have a special segment.
Chisaka, have you heard of the spring volleyball tournament?
Of course.
It's essentially nationals for volleyball, am I correct?
Yes.
Recently, Miyagi Prefecture held
their qualifiers for the tournament.
This year's matches seems to have had more drama than in previous years.
Indeed.
There are first-years who are making their debut on the national stage,
and third-years who are fighting their final battle in high school.
Each of them must have their own story.
Today, we want to introduce to everyone these high school students who bet their youth on volleyball.
This is a stage for fierce battle.
Shiratorizawa
Ariagawa
Kaji
Hakusuikan
Midorikawa
Mine West
Sakui
Kesenuma West
Jouzenji
Karasuno
Ougi Business
Waku South
Shirato
Date Tech
Niiyama Tech
Aoba Jousai
A place to bet one's youth on—a place to start a challenge.
All three years of high school are encapsulated here.
Japanese National High School Volleyball Tournament
The National High School Volleyball Tournament.
The spring tournament.
The stage where those who dream of making it in volleyball play.
October. It's the beginning of the
qualifiers for the spring tournament.
Koganegawa Kanji is a first-year at Date Tech High School.
He's also one of the challengers aiming to win the spring tournament.
Although he has just started playing volleyball,
he's blessed with being 190 cm tall and having good reflexes.
Serving as the team's on-court playmaker and setter,
he is taking on the spring tournament for the first time.
Mine West              Date Tech
Date Tech's specialty is undoubtedly...
their blocking!
Yeah!
The Iron Wall of Date
The so-called "Iron Wall of Date" terrifies other schools.
In the interhigh qualifiers taking place in summer,
everyone has high expectations for the giant setter Koganegawa because the third-years have retired.
Q: Are you stressed?
Date Tech High School
Setter Koganegawa Kanji (first-year)
Right now, I'm basically a baby as a setter!
But since this important task is
entrusted to me, I will try my best!
As a first-year and a starter,
he will take on nationals for the first time.
We can hear some tension in his words.
The Miyagi Prefecture qualifiers for the spring tournament.
Only one school can advance
through the strait gate to nationals.
Date Tech has demonstrated their tough defense and started off strong.
Shirato                            Date Tech
They have also won the first round of the 16-team tournament.
Then comes the quarterfinals.
Their opponent is the talented Aoba Jousai High School.
Maybe it's because he was nervous for his first spring tournament,
but Koganegawa's movements
became even stiffer than before.
But with the help of his seniors,
he slowly returned to his usual form.
However, in the end,
Koganegawa's block was broken through by his opponent, and the match was over.
Date Tech             Aoba Jousai
It's my fault for messing up!
But next time,
I'll make sure to become the third section
of the Iron Wall so that we can return here!
His first attempt at the spring tournament ended so swiftly.
However, his story is just getting started.
The world of competition is ruthless.
If there is a loser, there must be a winner on the other side.
Date Tech High School was defeated by one of the
favorites for the tournament, Aoba Jousai High School.
As Miyagi Prefecture's best setter,
Oikawa creates a style of volleyball based on combo attacks with his diverse sets.
This is Aoba Jousai's strength.
Team A               Team B
All right, come here for a moment.
During practice, Coach Irihata hardly speaks.
Instead, the third-years, led by their
captain Oikawa, actively drive the team.
The qualifiers are only two weeks away.
Q: Thoughts on the spring tournament?
Aoba Jousai High School
Setter Oikawa Tooru (third-year)
We know exactly what we need to do.
And who we need to defeat.
It's now past 8 pm.
And yet, they keep practicing.
Where does their passion come from?
Unstoppable Force
The persistence needed to take down Shiratorizawa Academy.
Rule the Court
Although Shiratorizawa are the undisputed champions,
Aoba Jousai            Shiratorizawa
Aoba Jousai never stops challenging them.
In the interhigh qualifiers in the summer, the two sides met in the finals.
But that wall was too thick.
Now here in the spring tournament qualifiers,
for the third-years, it's their last chance for revenge.
The semifinals approach.
Their opponent is Miyagi Prefectural Karasuno High School.
Karasuno                    Aoba Jousai
They defeated Karasuno in the third round of the interhigh qualifiers.
As long as they win this match, they can play Shiratorizawa.
However, in the first set, under the onslaught of Karasuno, they could only defend passively and lost.
Karasuno                    Aoba Jousai
Despite this, due to their extensive experience, Aoba Jousai did not become anxious.
They never doubted what they believe in and kept playing their own style.
The match seesawed back and forth.
Then, they reached the third and final set.
After an endless deuce, the levy finally broke.
The dream of taking on nationals ended.
Oikawa's best attempt at setting up a play was shut down.
They lost.
They were unable to challenge Shiratorizawa,
and Oikawa's challenge for the spring tournament ended here.
Yet he kept his head held high and looked straight forward.
It's unfortunate that we lost,
but I have faith our juniors will avenge us next year.
The Japanese National High School Boys' Volleyball Tournament Miyagi Prefecture Qualifier
Finals
Shiratorizawa
vs.
Karasuno
Shiratorizawa
vs.
Karasuno
Then comes the match that opens up the path to nationals: the finals.
Facing Karasuno, who keep on winning,
are the undisputed champions, Shiratorizawa,
known all across the country after racking up
countless victories via their overwhelming strength.
No one doubted that Shiratorizawa would be victorious.
But within the match, there was a twist in the story.
After the fierce battle in the final set, the champions, Shiratorizawa, were defeated by Karasuno.
First it was Aoba Jousai.
Now Karasuno High School has upset Shiratorizawa,
punching their ticket to nationals.
They were once called "the fallen champs" and "the clipped crows."
What is the secret that let them take flight?
Karasuno High School,
who qualified for the spring tournament,
is an extremely ordinary public high school.
They were once called "the fallen champs" and "the clipped crows."
Where can the secret to their newfound flight be found?
Nice spike!
There are currently 12 members on the team.
Here it comes!
Although it can't be called a big team,
after watching their practice, the first thing that can be noticed is their excellent teamwork.
No matter how difficult the moment, Captain Sawamura shouts louder and clearer than everyone else.
Use your voices!
I can't hear you!
Yessir!
Let's continue!
And then there is Sugawara,
who assists the sometimes harsh Sawamura.
Nice spike!
Don't lose to Daichi!
Right!
Then there's the life of the party, Tanaka.
And Nishinoya, who uses his energetic
performances to motivate his teammates.
Ryuu, are you afraid of the cameras?
That was weak!
I'm not afraid!
Q: Why has Karasuno taken flight?
Karasuno High School Coach Ukai Keishin
Well, the first-years all have spunk.
Oh, three of the four first-years are starters.
Maybe the team can make the most of their abilities because the upperclassmen paved the way for them.
Surprisingly, they have three first-years as starters.
It seems the key to the crows taking flight lies within these four spunky first-years.
One of them is Kageyama Tobio,
starting setter despite being a first-year.
His amazing setting skills have been well-known since his time at the famous Kitagawa First Junior High.
And in the match against Shiratorizawa, his sets were just as clean.
Q: Any reflections on the Shiratorizawa match?
Karasuno High School
Setter Kageyama Tobio (first-year)
Uh, well, they were really good.
Um, can I get back to practice?
The second first-year is Tsukishima Kei,
the tallest member of the team and a middle blocker.
He's usually rather reserved and doesn't like having to deal with other people.
Q: Are you always that reserved?
Karasuno High School
Middle Blocker Tsukishima Kei (first-year)
Yeah. I mean, uh... yeah.
However, his performance in the match was full of passion,
in complete contrast to the attitude he shows on the surface.
He kept jumping up to block, over and over.
Until his fingers became scarred.
And then...
It was a block bet on the will of his teammates, as well as his own pride.
All right!
The third first-year is Yamaguchi Tadashi.
His position is pinch server.
He plays a critical role in turning the tables
during a set where the opponent has momentum.
Q: Do you feel nervous?
Karasuno High School
Middle Blocker Yamaguchi Tadashi (first-year)
Uh, yeah, I do.
But when I stand in position to serve, I tell myself that it's now or never.
A body that can't move freely,
afraid what will happen if he fails.
Even so, Yamaguchi overcame the fear...
by believing in himself!
Yes!
The last first-year is Hinata Shouyou, a middle blocker.
Although he's only 163 cm tall,
he's shown he can put in the work to play that position.
He says he started playing volleyball because he admired the Little Giant.
Even so, outside of volleyball,
he's just your average high school student.
Okay, Hinata. Your turn.
Fill in the parentheses with a vegetable you hate and read it out loud.
R-Right!
The vegetable that I don't like is piiman!
That's called a "green pepper" in English.
What you said sounds like "pee man."
But once he appears on the court,
Give it to me!
he takes flight!
He flies!
Fly!
And what crushes the idea; of the undisputed champions of Shiratorizawa is his right hand.
Shiratorizawa
Karasuno
Q: Any thoughts on the final point?
Ushiwaka's cross-court spike was sick!
When planning that final attack, I waited patiently at first, and then rushed forward with everyone with a "bam"!
Where they cultivate teamwork isn't limited to the court or the clubroom.
Foot of the Slope
Hurry home after eating.
Yes, sir!
Q: What about dinner?
Of course, I'll eat dinner when I get back!
This is just a snack!
Let's take a look at how Hinata scarfs down his food.
Q: Is it delicious?
He truly is a Little Giant.
Wow! The meat buns that the
captain treats us to are awesome!
Hey, I didn't say anything about paying for them!
In that case, today it'll be my treat.
Daichi, can you cover me too?
Didn't I say to eat after paying?!
Coach, please treat us this time to celebrate our victory!
The key to Karasuno High School's flight seems to be the relationship between the seniors and juniors—
an environment where you can play together happily.
In this way, Karasuno High School set off a whirlwind
in the tournament and printed their ticket to nationals.
In their hearts, there is a dream that needs to come true.
Nekoma
Metropolitan
High School
Nekoma Metropolitan High School.
A powerhouse school in the tough division of Tokyo, they've advanced to national numerous times.
They're led by Coach Nekomata,
who was rivals with the former Karasuno
coach that led them to nationals, Ukai Ikkei.
The two teams have always been rivals and held a training camp together during summer vacation.
But despite having such a long relationship,
the two schools have never played
against each other in an official match.
May they one day face off against each other at nationals.
Q: Can you say a few words to Karasuno?
Nekoma Metropolitan High School
Captain Kuroo Tetsurou (third-year)
Congrats on advancing to the spring tournament.
We'll definitely win the Tokyo qualifiers and make the Battle of the Garbage Dumpster a reality.
Will the goddess of battle let these
two fated schools meet on the court?
The Tokyo qualifiers start in November.
We're gonna win the spring tournament!
Yeah!
Ever eager to improve, the players have a passionate soul.
That's the reward for their diligent efforts.
The spring tournament's orange court—
the stage where dreams of youth are made or broken.
The rivals who fight hard on the court
are also buddies who share the same dream.
With that dream on its wings, the crow now takes flight!
Man, your youth really is a special time.
It reminds me of my high school days.
Yes, me too.
I hope that Karasuno High School can work hard on behalf of their defeated opponents.
We hope you were satisfied with today's special.
We look forward to your feedback.
It's over?!
We will draw a name from among those who provide feedback to win a special sticker made for—
I was barely in it at all.
I was just mentioned in passing when they were introducing our team.
My name wasn't even mentioned.
Don't let it get to you, Asahi.
He's right.
Your job is to spike the ball.
Kageyama, you looked so unfriendly. It creeped me out!
Huh?! What'd you say, moron?!
C'mon. Let's get back to practice.
Right!
Goodbye!
Special! The Spring Tournament of Their Youth
Karasuno High School vs. Shiratorizawa Academy
!!
Haikyuu