Carve it.
Carve it into your flesh.
Carve it into the land.
Carve it into the sea.
Carve it into your enemies.
Carve it into your spoils.
Carve it.
Carve what you feel into me.
Slave
Einar!
What are you doing?
I could ask you the same thing!
Why're you attackin' that tree?
You tryna crush the house?
Are you gonna be a woodcutter, Einar?
No.
I'm training for battle.
Behold my power.
You're a big lad,
but you'd be useless in battle.
Get ready for lunch.
I'm so hungry...
You don't have to throw a knife at me.
You're holding dishes and spoons.
You wouldn't mind a dish?
They say bears have to
eat lots before winter.
Huh.
So, why are you trainin' again all of a sudden?
Thankya.
Well, because I gotta protect this place.
After it was all burnt to ashes,
it's finally been rebuilt.
I'm not letting that happen again.
I'm sure Dad would—
Mister Guthmur's milk is so good.
Right? That man knows his way around a teat.
What are you doin'
with your hands? It's so creepy.
Hey, listen to me.
Gross!
Don't bother.
Don't poke your nose into warrior stuff.
Doesn't it frustrate you,
always being on the losing side?
Dad died protecting us.
That's right.
And you're alive.
You've rebuilt this village,
and you're eating a delicious meal
with two beautiful ladies.
We haven't lost at all.
Hey.
Hey, how are you?
Hurry up.
Listen closely. Once we enter
the woods, I want you to run.
Follow the river, and...
Lotta.
Mom.
Don't think. Just run straight ahead.
Your brother and I will be with you.
Mom!
You ready? Let's get you up.
Einar, run. Leave me.
I'm not...
Come on. Stand, damn it.
Mom?
Mom!
Mom...
Silly girl...
There are still people over there.
Hey, they've got women, too!
We're on our way, girls!
Stand up, Einar.
Take Lotta and go. Hurry!
Mom...
Even a dying old hag can still manage.
Live.
As long as you're alive, you can...
Ei...nar...
Lotta...
Why aren't they running?
Hey, she's pretty cute.
Your mom's dead, isn't she?
Lotta!
Let go! Einar!
Let go of her!
Einar!
How dare you!
Einar! Einar!
You'll pay for—
What the hell are you doing?
She freakin' stabbed me!
Aw, man. What a waste.
Nothing we can do about it.
Let's sell the kid for beer money.
You're such a dumbass.
I'm sorry, okay?
Come on. Let's go, beer money.
A fir on a barren land withers
With neither bark nor leaves
So too does the man loved by none
Why should he live a long life?
A fir on a barren land withers
With neither bark nor leaves
So too does the man loved by none
Why should he live a long life?
— Hávamál
How is she?
She's not gonna make it.
Shit. Fine, let's move her.
Heave-ho!
Hey!
Hey, what the hell was that for?
You didn't need to throw her overboard!
All right, you're not swollen.
We're handing out blankets.
Keep yourselves warm.
We paid a fortune for you lot.
Don't go getting sick without our say so.
At the very least, stay healthy
until we find a buyer for you.
Got it?
Come on, hurry up!
Take in that sail!
That's right. I have to live.
Don't skip the liquor.
It'll improve your color.
Clean every nook and cranny,
especially your heads.
Check each other for lice.
How's this?
Hair's good.
Could you do her makeup
so she looks a little younger?
Well? Pretty good selection
this time, don't you think?
All second-rate crap.
There you go again.
You won't find anything better than ours!
That's right. I can't stay there.
I'll run away.
As long as I survive, I can try again.
Hup...
Thief!
Sorry!
Hey, Einar.
You still don't get it.
Listen closely, slaves.
Your homes are far, far away.
No matter how much you struggle,
you're never getting back to them.
And naturally,
nobody's gonna help you escape.
Because you're outsiders
and penniless slaves.
Find a good master
and serve him as best you can.
You'll eat way better than if you
run away and end up a beggar.
Before you go running off on adventures,
think real hard about which is better.
You got that, Einar?
I have to live...
Well, he's not bad, but have you
got any boys with a cuter face?
Ah, I see.
In that case, we've got some
special products for you to look at.
Oh, really? How exciting.
I'm sure you'll find them satisfactory.
They're right.
Even if I blindly ran away,
I wouldn't know where I was going.
And besides...
I don't have anywhere to go back to.
As long as I obediently serve
some master somewhere...
I'm telling you, you sure are lucky.
We just got a huge batch in.
Look, that's him.
Isn't he the one you're looking for?
He looks nothing like him!
He's not blond or small!
Huh? Now that I get a better look,
I guess that's not him.
That aside, what do you think?
He's strong and tough. If you buy him now—
I told you, I'm not here to buy a worker.
All I want is to free my relative.
I'm certain he came to this town.
Blond and small...
His name is Thorfinn.
You really have no idea where he is?
I'm sorry.
And sorry to have bothered you.
No problem. Come again soon.
He's never gonna find him.
So he's walking around
looking for his relative.
Whoever he's looking for is one lucky guy.
You there.
Can you speak? Let me see your teeth.
What's your name?
Einar.
Where are you from? What did you do before?
I was a farmer in Northern England.
Oh?
What do you say, Einar?
Would you like to help out on my farm?
A farm...
Einar, over here.
All of my people are at work now.
I'll introduce you to them at dinner.
Yes, sir.
But first, take a look at my farm.
Hey, Mom. Was that really true?
Live or die, I'll never be free again.
You still think I haven't lost?
My family was taken from me.
I lost my home. I lost everything.
I didn't even know
what the point of living was anymore.
Thorfinn, it's me. Come here.
"I'll be bought by a good master
and do my best to serve him."
"As long as I'm an obedient slave,
I won't starve."
I was beginning to think that way.
Thorfinn...
That was...
how Thorfinn and I met.
Ketil's Farm
"Ketil's Farm."