I'm Wang Xiaoxiu.
I was just an ordinary student.
This girl is Shen Yao.
She's...
She's my girlfriend.
We've been friends since forever.
An embarrassing accident...
brought us closer together.
I thought
it was the start of
our "happily ever after."
However...
the Horadric Cube
disrupted my peaceful life.
Becoming one with the Cube,
I'm stronger than ever.
I realized
I'm now empowered to protect Yao.
[Caution: Please do not try this at home]
I even left my hometown
to cultivate in the mountains.
Although Yao noticed my changes,
I didn't want her to worry.
So I chose to hide it.
But I never imagined...
that would be our last interaction
before we parted.
Due to my negligence,
Yao was kidnapped by Yan Luo.
He's an irredeemable bastard.
To take revenge on his nemesis Xigu Qin,
he even kidnapped the innocent Yao,
holding her hostage,
in hopes of luring Xigu Qin out.
I'm not interested in the feud between Yan Luo and Xigu Qin.
All I know is
no one is allowed to hurt my Yao.
So I came to this battlefield
with the Cube's powers
to challenge the masters hired by Yan Luo.
No matter how they try to stop me...
no matter how powerful they are...
No matter how many there are,
I will...
I must save my Yao!
♪ If I could escape from fate's predetermined path ♪
♪ And touch the true essence of time and space, the ultimate secret ♪
♪ Awakening this extraordinary destiny ♪
♪ Awakening another version of myself ♪
♪ The clearest, most resilient eyes of yours ♪
♪ Filled with the crystallization of infinite power ♪
♪ Releasing my true nature ♪
♪ Extracting every breath at lightning speed ♪
♪ Shining justice ♪
♪ The only truth in the duel ♪
♪ Now you guys are hearing my cry ♪
♪ My life was full of regrets ♪
♪ Restart ♪
♪ Striving, fighting, honing ♪
♪ Finding the future ♪
♪ Do not just dream it, have a try ♪
♪ Nothing can beat me, bravery's in my chest ♪
♪ I'll smash myself to protect your tenderness ♪
♪ Never bow down again ♪
[Super Cube]
[Episode 6]
Awesome! You're finally here!
Sure took you long.
An EF wavelength of zero?
Not superhuman?
Not a cultivator either.
Internal power's near zero.
No systematic fighting skills.
Purely fighting with physical strength.
Something like...
A body refiner? He'll totally boost my powers!
Oops, excuse me.
I got too excited. Where are my manners?
Hello, I'm Kui Jialin.
You can call me Dar-lin.
I'm Wang Xiaoxiu.
How...
are... you?
What a psycho!
Fine! Thank you! And you?
His energy sure is clean and pure!
No threat of internal injuries
nor the dullness of mere physical collision.
Purity that melts upon entering my body.
His power is like...
like... an unadulterated gem!
I've never met such a body refiner before!
Pervert...
This woman must be a pervert!
Let go of me!
But...
More, more, more!
I haven't had enough!
Would you cut it out already?
So gentle. Put your heart into it!
Is that all you've got?
Seriously, what's wrong with you?
You're no match for her.
Leave your last words and meet your end,
Wang Xiaoxiu.
Fine. You asked for it.
Wow, that felt so good!
Too gentle!
Take this! Take this! Take this! Take this! Take this!
Give me more!
Kui.
Too gentle.
Is that all you've got?
Kui, calm down!
Don't activate your power!
Stay out of it, Stone.
I told you he's a great tonic.
I must become stronger.
So Stone and I can finally go somewhere where we're free.
Kui...
She's both strong
and speedy.
It's as if she's possessed.
If I don't wanna die here,
I'd better get my head in the game!
I'm no pushover either!
Huh? No way!
I'm in paradise!
Wait...
Kui! No!
What did I just see?
That woman's a monster!
Kui leveled-up just from a lick of his blood!
How could his energy be so pure?
What's going on?
She's reverted back!
This monster alone is already a problem.
If that old man joins in too...
No matter what,
this is a rare opportunity.
Damn it!
I was blown away just by his palm?
How'd he do that?
I never thought
Kui would level up here.
Time's running out for Kui.
Let's make it quick.
You're quite strong, mister.
Be my next victim.
Cut the crap.
Master, dodge!
Dang! That was close!
I missed.
This is bad.
He's done?
Young fella.
Aren't you here to rescue that lady upstairs?
Go along then.
I'll let you off.
Are you admitting defeat?
Won't your boss kill you?
You...
If you're really giving up,
you'd better not launch a sneak attack when my guard's down.
I'm from the Million Alliance.
Millions never give up!
What a nuisance.
I'd never call a truce if she had more time.
This benefits me.
He's probably busy healing her.
But there's no guarantee they won't come at me once she's better.
That'll be bad.
Since you won't give up,
that means our fight's not over.
Are kids these days all so paranoid?
Fine. I'll never admit defeat.
But I can make a blood oath
to quell your worries.
This is the token of my Alliance,
the Million Coin.
The blood oath is the greatest promise a cultivator can make.
I, Million Stone of the Alliance,
swear with my blood
that this truce is sincere.
If I break the oath,
I'll turn to dust!
What... What are you doing?
Nothing. For memory's sake.
Breathe. Stay calm.
Take it and go!
This isn't fake, is it?
Can I pawn it for money?
Give it back if you don't believe me!
Of course I trust a man of integrity like you.
Nothing but trust here, my man.
I hope you'll mend your ways
and behave yourselves.
I'm off to save a life.
This is a critical moment.
I must keep my cool.
Be still like a mountain.
Ye-Yes.
So long, Mr. Stone.
Kids these days are so scary.
Misha, are you there?
Our training mission's been suspended.
Going back so soon?
Kui had an accident.
We have no other choice.
What happened to her?
It's inconvenient right now.
Let's talk in person.
Misha!
Are you there?
Misha.
Misha!
Who are you?
Mr. Chu Mushan!
Where are you going?
Young Master, don't you know?
All your assassins have been wiped out.
What?
Uncle, is this true?
Young Master. Change of plans.
You must evacuate right now.
What the hell's going on?
It must be Xigu Qin!
Forget Xigu Qin.
I've found an even more interesting target.
What... What on earth...
Young Master.
The Million Alliance called a truce with the intruder.
What?
Unfortunately,
your plan must be terminated.
What matters now is—
I'm not leaving!
Mr. Chu Mushan,
you can help me finish my plan.
I'll pay you double.
No!
Triple the pay!
Deal?
Bastard!
Watch out!
What...
I've warned you many times
not to use money to order me around!
He's an erratic oddball.
We can't afford to provoke him now.
The youngest and proudest of the Ominous Menaces,
Chu Mushan.
[Next Episode Preview]
It's an honor to meet you.
We're called Chu Mushan.
Cube, sure you're not mistaken?
His combat power is just 7?
Actually, aren't we born to be archenemies?
I'm gonna stay here and watch all of you get blown up into mush!
I was the cause of this.
I'll take care of it.
Uncle.
Don't forget
I still have a trump card to turn the tables.
Anyone who sees this... must die!
♪ Could it be that gravity also tilts toward you?♪
♪ You start to shine brightly in the crowd ♪
♪ Why do I suddenly feel this way?♪
♪ Why is it that whenever I need you most ♪
♪ You always appear?♪
♪ Can you sense all of my emotions?♪
♪ Sharing every little thing, all day long ♪
♪ You've listened to all the songs I like ♪
♪ The story has reached this point, just one step away ♪
♪ Confessing ♪
♪ Can you say the words you've been meaning to say to me?♪
♪ Let impulse bloom like cherry blossoms ♪
♪ My heart is fluttering ♪
♪ A little bit of confusion, sweet but helpless ♪
♪ A single gaze, and a happy surprise ♪
♪ Can you tell me the answer I'm looking forward to?♪
♪ Looking at me, you're being naughty ♪
♪ Like a child ♪
♪ Another glance, and the starry sky lights up ♪
♪ Time slows down, but my heartbeat speeds up ♪