They're the prey, and we're the hunters.
S
ie sind das Essen und wir sind die Jäger
ie
sind
sind
die
Jä
ger
...and we're the hunters.
U
nd wir sind Jäger
nd
wir
sind
Jä
ger
...and we're the hunters.
U
nd wir sind Jäger
nd
wir
sind
Jä
ger
Ignorant of the
F
umareta hana no
trampled flower's name,
N
amae mo shirazu ni
the bird that fell to the earth
C
hi ni ochita tori wa
waits impatiently for the wind.
K
aze wo machiwabiru
Even if you pray,
I
notta tokoro de
nothing will be changed.
N
animo kawaranai
But that which can alter the present
I
ma wo kaeru no wa
is the resolution to fight.
T
atakau kakugo da
Trampling over corpses,
S
hikabane fumikoete
swine who mock the will to advance.
S
usumu ishi wo warau buta yo
Peace of the cattle,
K
achiku no annei
and the prosperity of deception.
K
yogi no hanei
The freedom of the dead, hungry wolf.
S
hiseru garou no jiyuu wo
Our caged humiliation
T
orawareta kutsujoku wa
signals the start of our retaliation.
H
angeki no koushi da
Beyond the ramparts,
J
ouheki no sono kanata
we're hunters that slaughter our prey.
E
mono wo hofuru Jäger
As these surging urges
H
otobashiru shoudou ni
burn away our bodies,
S
ono mi wo yaki nagara
we ignite the dusk with
T
asogare ni hi wo ugatsu
a crimson bow and arrow.
G
uren no yumiya
...and we're the hunters.
U
nd wir sind Jäger
nd
wir
sind
Jä
ger
...and we're the hunters.
U
nd wir sind Jäger
nd
wir
sind
Jä
ger
...and we're the hunters.
U
nd wir sind Jäger
nd
wir
sind
Jä
ger
Shining Dimly in the Midst of Despair
————— The Recovery of Mankind Part    —————
①
You there!
Sir!
Who the hell are you?!
Armin Arlert from Shiganshina District, sir!
That so? What a ridiculous name!
Did your father name you that?
My grandfather did, sir!
Arlert, what did you come here to do?
To contribute to mankind's victory, sir!
How commendable of you.
We'll use you as Titan bait.
Third line, face backwards!
Who the hell are you?
Sir!
Thomas Wagner from Trost District, sir!
I can't hear you!
Thomas Wagner from Trost—
There they go again.
Still no good!
Go work on it in the stables!
Next!
You went through that first thing
when you were in training too, right?
Sir!
It brings me back.
Wrong!
You're from a pigsty—worse than cattle!
Sir!
I'm worse than cattle, sir!
What's the point of intimidating them?
Wrong!
It's a rite of passage.
Sir!
You reject the you up until then,
Next!
Sir!
in order to be shaped into capable
soldiers, fresh from a clean slate.
Go home, right this instant!
This is a necessary process to accomplish that.
Why the hell are you here?!
To devote my flesh and blood to humanity, sir!
Fourth line, face backwards!
But he just skipped past that girl over there.
The rite of passage is unnecessary for
those who've already been through it.
They're likely to be the ones who
witnessed hell two years ago.
It shows on their faces.
Now, let's be off.
Who the hell are you?!
Jean Kirstein from Trost District, sir!
What did you come here to do?
To enlist in the Military Police Brigade
and live within the inner walls, sir.
I see.
So you want to live within the inner walls, huh?
Sir.
Who said you could sit?!
Someone who can't succeed here won't
make it into the Military Police Brigade!
Who the hell are you?!
What did you come here to do?
Marco Bott from Jinae Village in
Wall Rose's southern district, sir!
I've come to enlist in the Military Police Brigade,
and devote myself to serving the king, sir!
Really?
That's all fine and well.
Endeavor for it.
However...
The king has no desire for your body.
You're next!
Who the hell are you?!
Connie Springer from Ragako Village
in Wall Rose's southern district, sir!
You have it backwards, Connie Springer.
It should've been the first thing you learned—
that salute is a symbol that openly declares
your determination to offer your life.
Is your heart on the right side?
Hey, you.
What are you doing?
You, I'm talking to you!
Who the hell are you?!
Sasha Blouse from Dauper Village
in Wall Rose's southern district, sir!
Sasha Blouse,
what the hell is in your right hand?
A steamed potato, sir.
I happened to see it in
the kitchen, so I took it, sir!
In other words, you stole it.
Why...
Why did you take that potato out now?
It's best to eat it before it gets cold,
so I decided now was the time to do so, sir.
No, I still don't understand...
Why did you eat the potato?
Are you asking me why people eat potatoes, sir?
This half's for you, sir.
Half?
Hey, the potato girl's still running.
Wow, she's been at it for five hours.
But she didn't seem to mind
the "run till you drop" part
quite as much as being told
she'd have to skip dinner, huh?
Dauper Village is a small village of
hunters deep in the mountains, isn't it?
What's that?
The dropouts.
They opted to be transferred to reclaimed land.
What?
But it's still only the first day.
It's only natural.
The powerless have no choice but to leave.
Choosing to go back to picking
up rocks and pulling weeds...
That reminds me.
You weren't asked to state your
name and birthplace or anything.
I'm from Shiganshina District, just like this guy.
I see. That's...
So you were there on that day, right?
H-Hey!
Did you catch a glimpse of it?
The Colossus Titan.
Y-Yeah.
Like I said, I saw everything.
Whoa.
Really?
Just how big is it?
Big enough to stick its head over the wall.
What?
I heard it's big enough to straddle!
Same here.
That's what I heard in my village too.
No, it isn't quite that big.
What does its face look like?
It's mostly skinless and has a huge mouth.
How about the Armored Titan that
smashed through Wall Maria?
That's what people are calling it, but it
looked like an average Titan to me.
Th-Then what's an average Titan like?
Everyone, let's stop questioning him.
I'm sure there are things he'd rather not recall.
Sorry for—
That's not it!
Titans really aren't that big a deal.
Once we master the use of the
three-dimensional maneuver device,
they won't stand a chance!
I can finally train as a soldier.
My emotions just got the better of me earlier.
I'll enlist in the Survey Corps and
exterminate the Titans from this world.
I'll slaughter them—
Whoa there. You crazy?
Did you just say you're going
to enlist in the Survey Corps?
Yeah, that's right.
If I'm not mistaken, you're aiming to live
it up in the Military Police Brigade, right?
I'm an honest guy, you see.
I'd say I'm a lot more pleasant to be around
than someone who puts on a brave face,
despite being terrified deep down inside.
Are you implying something?
Q-Quit it, guys.
Hey now.
I wasn't really...
Whatever, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to dismiss your opinion.
Let's call it even with this.
Yeah, I crossed the line too.
Excuse me.
Um, well, I've never seen
anybody like you before is all.
S-Sorry.
Your black hair looks beautiful.
Why, thank you.
Who cares? Leave me be.
You're quick to act impulsively
when you get angry.
That again?
Anyway, don't you think your hair is too long?
It might be a safety hazard during
three-dimensional maneuver training.
All right, I'll cut it.
But how long do you think it should be?
H-Hey!
What do you think you're doing?!
What did you wipe on me?!
My trust in others.
This is...
Bread!
This was all I could save.
But, well...
You should have a drink of water first.
Are you God? Are you...
God!
Hey, what're you two doing?
Well, this girl has been
running all day until now.
You...
You think you're doing
the right thing, aren't you?
Are you doing it for potato girl?
Was what you got out of it worth the effort?
Well, whatever.
At any rate, let's carry her to her bed.
Are you acting out of kindness too?
I'm doing this to put her in my debt,
so I can take advantage of her.
I can count on her stupidity.
First off, we'll test your aptitude!
Those incapable of this aren't
suited to even be used as decoys!
We'll have you transferred to reclaimed land!
Though this is but the most basic of tests,
you can perceive one's aptitude for
three-dimensional maneuvers at this point.
Look.
She's not wavering in the slightest.
She likely understands what
to do and how to do it.
That's what I call aptitude.
It appears we have a lot of talent this year.
Um, what about him?
That's another example of aptitude.
Even if you have the will, there can be
cases in which you greatly underperform.
What are you doing, Eren Jaeger?!
Raise your upper body!
What is this?
How am I supposed to...
No way.
Currently
Disclosable
Information
Three-dimensionsal Maneuver Device Training①
Three-dimensional maneuver device training is a
rigorous process that allows humans, which are
limited to two-dimensional movements, to adapt
to movement in the third dimension.
Three-dimensionsal Maneuver Device Training①
Three-dimensional maneuver device training is a
rigorous process that allows humans, which are
limited to two-dimensional movements, to adapt
to movement in the third dimension.
Currently
Disclosable
Information
Three-dimensionsal Maneuver Device Training②
Great physical and leg strength, coupled with spatial
recognition abilities, as well as the mental strength
to not waver in the midst of panic, are crucial qualities.
Follow the basics and you should be fine.
Don't think about doing it well or anything.
Pay attention to your front and rear balance,
and gently rest your weight upon the belts
on your waist and the back of your legs.
Take it slow and you'll be okay.
Even I could do it, after all.
Okay, I think I can do it this time.
Raise me up, Armin.
Okay.
Hey, Dazz.
Isn't that the guy who said he'd
slaughter all the Titans yesterday?
Well, he'll probably be on
reclaimed land by tomorrow.
There's no food for the useless, after all.
Eren.
Don't pay them any mind.
You still have tomorrow to get the hang of it.
How pathetic.
At this rate, exterminating them is...
You shouldn't aim for that anymore.
What did you say?
I said you shouldn't aim to be a soldier.
After all, throwing away your
life isn't the way to fight.
Look here.
On that day, I witnessed
everything that happened.
Do you think I'm gonna give up
because of something like this?
But your resolution has nothing to do with it.
What? Why?
Because the one that decides whether
or not you can become a soldier...
isn't you.
It's not like I'm telling you to return
to reclaimed land by yourself.
Let's go, Armin.
O-Okay...
Don't worry.
At that time, I'll go with you.
Um, so...
Are you saying I can have that?
A trick to posture control?
Sorry, but since I'm a genius,
all I can say is "feel it".
Actually, I'd like you to teach me something.
The secret to keeping your sanity after
completely embarrassing yourself, that is.
You guys, I just begged you for your help.
But yesterday, didn't you say
"The powerless should just leave"?
Oh, maybe I'm mistaken.
Or was it "The talentless have
no choice but to leave"?
Which was it again?
Please!
I heard you two were naturals, Bertolt, Reiner!
Sorry, but I can't think of a trick to hanging.
I don't think I can give you any helpful tips.
I see.
I guess all we can do is hope
for the best tomorrow.
You two are from Shiganshina District, right?
Yeah, we are.
Then you must be familiar with
how terrifying the Titans are.
So why are you trying to become soldiers?
Unlike Eren, I wasn't personally
stricken by the threat of the Titans.
It's just that whenever I thought of the monarchy
that implemented such a reckless recapture plan,
I felt like I couldn't sit still and do nothing.
I see.
Where are you two from?
Reiner and I are from a village deep in
the mountains, southeast of Wall Maria.
That's...
Yeah.
Unlike the flourishing villages along the
river, news didn't get to us very quickly.
The Titans came before we
heard anything, after all.
It was in the dawn.
The cattle were strangely excited
and I heard unfamiliar tremors
gradually growing louder.
Eventually, I realized they were
the footsteps of something.
Then, when I hurriedly opened the window...
I don't... um...
remember much after that.
Everyone was in a dire state of disorder.
Hey, why are you suddenly bringing that up?
Sorry.
Basically, what I'm trying to say is...
You guys are probably different from them.
Them?
The people here who know nothing
about the fear the Titans bring.
Hey.
The main reason they're here is to
abide by the expectations of society.
Swayed by public opinion that people who become
producers after turning twelve are cowards,
they enlisted in the Training Corps.
Despite what I say, I'm no different from them.
I became a soldier aiming to work
for the Military Police Brigade
within the inner walls where it's safe.
If that doesn't seem possible,
I might abandon training.
I don't have a will of my own.
Valuing your life is nothing to be ashamed of.
I'm...
going to return to my lost homeland.
That's the only drive I have.
I'm going back, no matter what.
And you?
What might your goals be?
I...
thought to myself that I have to kill them.
That I have to slaughter them
all with my own two hands.
That's what I thought.
Are you saying that, even after encountering
the Titans, you weren't overcome by fear?
Yeah.
Well, at this point, it's uncertain whether
or not I can even become a soldier.
Check your equipment and readjust your belts.
You'll do fine tomorrow.
I'm sure you can do it.
Eren Jaeger, was it?
Yeah, thanks.
Reiner Braun, right?
Eren Jaeger, are you prepared?
Sir!
I'll do it.
I'll do it!
I may not have the aptitude,
but my guts are second to none.
Begin!
Forget reason.
I don't even have a basis.
But this is all I've got!
This is...
my weapon!
I did it.
I can do it!
I-I... I can still...
Let him down.
I-I...
Wagner, switch belts with Jaeger.
S-Sir!
You had defective equipment.
The metal fixtures on your belt were damaged.
Though this is the first I've
heard of faulty fixtures...
It seems there's a need to start
checking them during maintenance.
Then that means he... managed to stay
upright with faulty equipment for a bit...
Wow!
Th-Then what about my aptitude evaluation?
I see no issues.
Devote yourself to training.
I did it!
I pulled it off!
How's that, Mikasa?
I can do it!
I can fight the Titans!
There's no need for me to depend on you anymore!
Looks like it worked out somehow.
His eyes are saying, "How's that?".
No.
He's relieved that he won't
have to be separated from me.
Grisha, today, your son has become a soldier.
Your dream is where my heart belongs.
sono yume wa kokoro no ibasho
It's more fragile than a life.
inochi yori kowareyasuki mono
Constantly abandoned, and constantly found.
nandodemo sutete wa mitsuke
Now, sleep in peace.
yasuraka ni saa nemure
My pulsing urges
myakuutsu shoudou ni
mya
kuu
tsu
shou
dou
ni
trample upon my wishes.
negai wa okasare
As often as I sadly forget,
wasureteshimau hodo
I remember once again.
mata omoidasu yo
In this cruel yet beautiful world,
kono utsukushiki zankoku na sekai de wa
I endlessly question the reason for my survival.
mada ikiteiru koto naze to tou bakari de
Oh, with this strength and weakness,
aa bokutachi wa kono tsuyosa yowasa de
I wonder what it is we'll protect,
nani wo mamoru no darou
when a reason ceases to exist.
mou risei nado nai naraba
Eren, after graduating from the Training Corps,
bears witness to mankind,
which has regained its dignity.
"I can defeat the Titans."
The moment he became confident of that,
mankind was reminded once more.
The Night of the Dissolution Ceremony
————— The Recovery of Mankind Part    —————
②