(JUJUTSU KAISEN THE CULLING GAME, PART 1)
Nice to meet you, the son of Zen'in.
the descendant of Michizane,
the Death Painting Womb,
and…
Sukuna's Vessel.
Aren't you going to greet me?
- Tengen.
- This guy is...
- This is...
- This person is…
Is he human?
Tengen.
This isn't our first meeting.
Yuki Tsukumo.
Why did you shut off
the Tombs of the Star Corridor?
To prevent Kenjaku from
synchronizing with you.
After all, I can't read minds.
Kenjaku?
The sorcerer who once possessed
Noritoshi Kamo,
and now resides in Suguru Geto's body.
Kenjaku, as in a sacred rope
to save all living things?
That's not even ironic.
Why do you look like this, Master Tengen?
This kid dares to interrupt now?
While I'm immortal, I'm not ageless.
If you live for 500 years,
you'll age like this too.
(SERIOUSLY?)
Seriously?
12 years ago,
after I failed to assimilate
with the Star Plasma Vessel,
my aging accelerated.
My individual
self-consciousness disappeared.
Heaven and earth itself
became my self-consciousness.
So there wasn't another
Star Plasma Vessel at that time.
No wonder your "voice" didn't increase.
Excuse me.
We're here to ask about Kenjaku's purpose
and how to unseal the Prison Realm.
Could you please tell us what you know?
Of course…
That's what I'd like to say,
but first, let me make a condition.
Yuta Okkotsu.
Yuki Tsukumo.
Death Painting Womb, Choso.
Two of you three must stay here
to serve as my guards.
Guards?
Aren't you immortal?
Are you worried
about the seal or something?
That's not fair.
Aren't you going to explain
the duration and reason for this task?
Well then,
let's talk about Kenjaku.
(KENJAKU'S PURPOSE)
That child's purpose is
to force humans across Japan to evolve.
(EVOLUTION OF HUMANS ACROSS JAPAN)
We've heard about that.
So what exactly does he intend to do?
Back then, why didn't Kenjaku use
Master Tengen's barrier
(IDLE TRANSFIGURATION)
but Idle Transfiguration
to turn everyone in Japan into sorcerers?
(IDLE TRANSFIGURATION)
(EVOLUTION OF HUMANS ACROSS JAPAN)
He didn't do that,
simply because he lacked cursed energy.
The cursed energy
(INSUFFICIENT CURSED ENERGY)
produced from Uzumaki
can't be restored to jujutsu sorcerers.
It's too inefficient to evolve humans
one by one with cursed techniques.
(METHOD? ASSIMILATE HUMANS WITH TENGEN)
Kenjaku's method of evolution
(REASON, UNKNOWN)
is to assimilate humans with me.
(ASSIMILATE HUMANS WITH TENGEN)
What? But to assimilate--
You can only assimilate
(TENGEN, STAR PLASMA VESSEL, CIVILIAN)
with a Star Plasma Vessel.
(STAR PLASMA VESSEL, CAN ASSIMILATE)
(CIVILIAN, CAN'T ASSIMILATE)
I used to be like that.
(STAR PLASMA VESSEL, DEAD)
(STOP TENGEN FROM ASSIMILATING WITH SPV)
But I have
(TENGEN)
evolved
(THE EVOLUTION OF TENGEN)
since 12 years ago.
It's no longer impossible for me to
assimilate with non-Star Plasma Vessels.
(HUMANS ASSIMILATING WITH TENGEN)
But you're just one person, right?
How can you assimilate
with multiple humans?
Even now…
I'm not the one standing in front of you.
After I've evolved, my soul is everywhere.
Like I said earlier,
Heaven and Earth are my egos.
Humans who assimilate with me
can even surpass the barrier
called Jujutsu Sorcerers
and become a new existence
between existence and non-existence.
Thanks to my barrier technique,
I've evolved to maintain my form
and rationality.
However, if humans evolve,
if even one of them goes berserk,
then the world…
(GO BERSERK)
then the world...
will be doomed.
Why?
Because the boundaries
of individuals no longer exist.
(GOES BERSERK)
Malice only takes a moment to spread.
A hundred million people's worth
of impurities will spread.
The situation in Tokyo will
be repeated all over the world.
Why is Kenjaku doing this?
(KENJAKU'S PURPOSE)
Who knows?
(THE EVOLUTION OF HUMANS ACROSS JAPAN)
Didn't I just tell you?
(METHOD? ASSIMILATE HUMANS WITH TENGEN)
I can't read people's minds.
(REASON, UNKNOWN)
But with this method,
can't Master Tengen
simply refuse to assimilate?
That's the problem.
Now that I've evolved, my composition
(GETO DIES, ATTAIN "CURSED MANIPULATION")
is closer to cursed spirits
(ATTAIN "IDLE TRANSFIGURATION")
than humans.
(STAR PLASMA VESSEL DIES, TENGEN EVOLVES)
So I…
(ATTAIN TENGEN)
So I...
have become the target
of cursed manipulation.
Considering Kenjaku's strength
as a sorcerer,
he might be able to absorb me
as soon as he touches me.
Therefore, my true form here at the Tombs
of the Star Corridor rejects everything.
And you still need guards?
That's right.
Kenjaku is second only to me
when it comes to barrier techniques.
I don't know when the seal of the Tombs
of the Star Corridor will be broken.
Why now?
(STOP TENGEN FROM ASSIMILATING WITH SPV)
Stopping you from assimilating with SPV,
(TENGEN'S EVOLUTION)
making you evolve,
attempting
(ATTAIN TENGEN)
to absorb you
and control you with cursed manipulation.
Kenjaku also seems to be
related to Sukuna.
He's been a sorcerer
for at least 1,000 years.
Why now?
(TENGEN, STAR PLASMA VESSEL, SIX EYES)
I, "Star Plasma Vessel", and "Six Eyes",
these are all linked by cause and effect.
(KENJAKU'S PURPOSE)
Kenjaku was defeated by
(STOP TENGEN FROM EVOLVING)
a Six Eyes sorcerer twice.
The second time,
Kenjaku was quite thorough.
The Star Plasma Vessel and the Six Eyes
were both killed within
a month of their birth.
Even so, on the day of assimilation,
Six Eyes and SPV still appeared.
After that, Kenjaku stopped
assassinating the Six Eyes.
Instead, he changed his strategy
to sealing them.
He began to search for the Prison Realm.
Because two people with the Six Eyes
can never appear at the same time.
(KENJAKU'S PURPOSE)
However, 12 years ago,
something unexpected happened.
It was Toji Zen'in's intervention.
(SOMETHING UNEXPECTED HAPPENED)
It was
(TOJI ZEN'IN'S INTERVENTION)
Toji Zen'in's intervention.
Heavenly Restriction granted him
(TOJI ZEN'IN'S INTERVENTION)
physical prowess.
He was quite special even among them.
(TOJI ZEN'IN'S INTERVENTION)
He was an existence completely
free from cursed energy.
(KENJAKU'S PURPOSE)
Due to the Heavenly Restriction,
(TOJI ZEN'IN'S INTERVENTION)
a human that is
freed from causality
coincidentally disrupted
(STAR PLASMA VESSEL DIES)
our fate.
And at that time,
(CURSED MANIPULATION)
a boy with cursed manipulation appeared.
All the pieces, except the Prison Realm,
coincidentally fell into place.
And six years ago,
the Prison Realm also fell
(PRISON REALM)
into Kenjaku's hands.
(THE CULLING GAME)
So what 's the purpose
of holding the Culling Game?
It's to adapt before assimilation.
(HUMANS, TENGEN)
It's not that
I can't assimilate with others
(ASSIMILATION)
other than Star Plasma Vessels.
But at this stage,
(INCOMPLETE)
an incomplete existence is highly likely.
(THE CULLING GAME)
Using the player's cursed energy
and a realm formed by connecting colonies,
(HUMANS, THE CULLING GAME, TENGEN)
the Culling Game is a ritual to send
(HUMANS, THE CULLING GAME, ADAPT, TENGEN)
humans of this country to Higan.
(ASSIMILATE)
He probably intends
(SUCCEED)
to make humans adapt first,
(THE EVOLUTION OF HUMANS ACROSS JAPAN)
before assimilating them with me?
However, for such a large-scale ritual
to be established,
Kenjaku himself must also
(ABOUT THE CULLING GAME)
bear a "Binding Vow."
(7. IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE PREVIOUS RULE)
One of them is that
(THE GAME MASTER MUST ACCEPT)
the Game Master
(ANY PROPOSED NEW RULE UNLESS IT HINDERS)
of the Culling Game is not Kenjaku.
(THE PERMANENCE OF THE CULLING GAME)
But that's a disadvantage for you.
Because even if you kill Kenjaku,
"the Culling Game" won't end.
(PLAYERS, DEAD)
Unless all players die,
(PLAYERS REFUSE TO PARTICIPATE, DIE)
or all Players refuse
(7. THE GAME MASTER)
to participate and die.
If not, the Culling Game will never end.
(7. THE GAME MASTER)
The "permanence"
in the Culling Game's general rules
(PERMANENCE)
is to prevent any interruption.
In that case…
Yes.
(6. PLAYERS MAY EXPEND 100 POINTS
TO NEGOTIATE WITH THE GAME MASTER)
(TO ADD ONE NEW RULE TO THE CULLING GAME)
We have no choice but to participate
to add a new rule,
(EXPEND 100 POINTS)
so passive participants
(TO ADD A NEW RULE)
like Ms. Tsumiki
can leave the Culling Game.
And at the same time,
we must break Gojo Sensei's seal.
As long as he's here,
he can handle everything himself.
(PURPOSE OF ITADORI AND THE OTHERS)
(ADD A NEW RULE TO LEAVE THE CULLING GAME)
(UNSEAL SATORU GOJO)
(HELP US)
Master Tengen…
Before that, let's decide who will stay.
- I will… stay.
Yuji needs the help of Okkotsu
or this woman.
If Noritoshi Kamo…
Kenjaku barges in and attacks Tengen,
that's all the more reason for me to stay.
Because ending his life
is salvation for my brothers.
I still have a lot
to talk to Tengen about.
Is that okay, Okkotsu?
Yes.
Because I don't want to be
separated from everyone anymore.
Thank you so much.
This is…
what we need to free Satoru Gojo.
Prison Realm: "Back Gate."
(PRISON REALM "BACK GATE")
"Back Gate"?
This is the first time I've heard of it.
So, the so-called rear gate?
You could say that.
Before Kenjaku found Prison Realm,
it was outside my barrier.
I'm afraid it's overseas.
(PRISON REALM)
I wanted to seal this rear gate
to suppress the aura
(SATORU GOJO)
of the front gate.
Unfortunately, it didn't work.
(PRISON REALM: BACK GATE)
Satoru Gojo is sealed in the Back Gate.
So we just need to open this?
No.
The right to open the gate is ultimately
with the holder of the Front Gate,
which is Kenjaku.
To pry open Prison Realm: Back Gate,
you need something
(PRISON REALM "BACK GATE")
to forcefully undo all cursed techniques.
(THE INVERTED SPEAR OF HEAVEN)
The "Inverted Spear of Heaven"
or the "Black Rope," which can disrupt
the effects of all cursed techniques.
(BLACK ROPE)
We need to get
one of them.
(THE INVERTED SPEAR OF HEAVEN)
However, 12 years ago,
the Inverted Spear of Heaven was either
sealed overseas by Gojo or destroyed.
What was Gojo Sensei thinking?
(THE BLACK ROPE)
And last year, the "Black Rope"
was completely eliminated by Satoru Gojo.
What was that man doing?
Miguel and I
went to Africa to search for
remaining "Black Rope" pieces.
So that's why you went abroad.
But in the end, it was all for nothing.
(I HEARD THERE'S NONE LEFT)
I heard there's none left.
There must be another way.
There is.
Among the Players participating
in the Culling Game,
(UNKNOWN, ANGEL)
there's a thousand-year-old sorcerer
who calls herself "Angel."
(ANGEL)
Her cursed technique can
eliminate all cursed techniques.
(THE CULLING GAME, PLAYER, HANA KURUSU)
(EPISODE 50 ABOUT THE CULLING GAME)
(SATORU GOJO, PRISON REALM
PRISON REALM: "BACK DOOR", ANGEL)
She can eliminate…
all cursed techniques?
That's right.
With Angel's cursed technique,
we can open Prison Realm: Back Gate.
Do you know where that person is now?
In the colony on the east side of Tokyo.
Since the Culling Game's
barriers reject me,
I have no further information.
Let's start by clarifying this part.
There are ten colonies nationwide.
They are connected to each other.
These connecting colonies
that "send humans to a realm of Higan"
Crossing the river or moving
(YASOHACHI BRIDGE'S RIVER)
a realm to Higan
(HIGAN)
has great significance in jujutsu.
(THE REALM OF COLONIES)
Back at Yasohachi Bridge…
Hokkaido wasn't included.
Is it because
of the Jujutsu High's barrier?
That's right.
That place was originally
a huge sacred ground.
It has already adapted completely.
(HOKKAIDO GOV SLOGAN IN 1999) (LAND OF TRIALS)
As expected of the land of trials.
(THE CULLING GAME)
"Send to Higan" may sound grand,
(ADAPT)
(ASSIMILATE HUMANS WITH TENGEN)
but it's actually placing a curse on all of Japan's humanity
(EVOLUTION OF HUMANS ACROSS JAPAN)
to prepare them for assimilation.
(ADAPTION COMPLETE)
(THE CULLING GAME)
How long will the ritual take
from start to finish?
It depends on the Culling Game's status.
But it should be completed
within two months?
(1. AFTER AWAKENING A CURSED TECHNIQUE)
It's now 9 a.m. on November 9th.
(PLAYERS MUST DECLARE THEIR PARTICIPATION)
A sorcerer who is a player
(IN THE COLONY OF THEIR CHOICE)
must awaken around
(WITHIN 19 DAYS)
12 AM on October 31st.
The grace period for Tsumiki to join
the Culling Game is about
10 days and 15 hours.
(THERE'S STILL TIME UNTIL
A CIVILIAN LIKE TSUMIKI JOINS THE GAME)
(EXPEND 100 POINTS TO ADD NEW RULE)
(ALLOW CIVILIANS TO LEAVE THE GAME)
(2. ANY PLAYER WHO BREAKS)
Master Tengen just said
(THE PREVIOUS RULE SHALL BE SUBJECT TO)
if you refuse to participate,
(CURSED TECHNIQUE REMOVAL)
you'll die?
Yes.
Cursed technique removal?
This rule applies to sorcerers
who join later too, right?
In that case, I don't think it'll be
removed by "Idle Transfiguration."
Because it's not "prohibited from use".
It's "removal,"
so it's not a "Binding Vow" either.
In that case, it's forcing
some kind of effect on the brain.
I think, according to the rules,
if your technique is removed, you'll die.
Otherwise, everyone would
refuse to participate.
It's just as Shoko predicted.
But a sorcerer
without a cursed technique like me…
There's no risk, right?
By the way, what about Panda?
Does he even have a brain?
(3. NON-PLAYERS WHO ENTER THE COLONY)
About that…
(BECOME PLAYERS AT THE MOMENT OF ENTRY)
What about civilians who were inside the barrier from the start?
(AND IS DEEMED TO DECLARE PARTICIPATION)
They get one chance to leave the colony.
Really?
That's pretty friendly.
There's nothing in the general rules
about entering or exiting the colony.
It must be to give the players
a clear objective of "leaving the colony"
to make the Culling Game more active.
To trap the players inside,
the key premise is that the players
"voluntarily enter the colony."
Is this the balance of the barrier
that Ino mentioned?
(4. PLAYERS SCORE POINTS
BY ENDING THE LIVES OF OTHER PLAYERS)
(ENDING LIVES)
(5. POINTS ARE DETERMINED
BY THE GAME MASTER)
(BASED ON THE VALUE OF THE PLAYER'S LIFE)
There are general rules and principles.
(GENERAL RULES, SORCERERS 5 PTS)
It's confusing.
(NON-SORCERERS 1 PT)
Fushiguro?
(GAME MASTER)
It's nothing.
Master Tengen.
(GAME MASTER)
Who is the Game Master here?
It's a shikigami that follows
each Player one-on-one.
(KOGANE, NOT THE GAME MASTER)
"Kogane."
But to be precise,
(KOGANE, NOT THE GAME MASTER)
Kogane is not the "Game Master,"
but rather an interface "window."
You can think of the Game Master
as the Culling Game program itself.
I see?
(6. PLAYERS MAY EXPEND 100 POINTS
TO NEGOTIATE WITH THE GAME MASTER)
(TO ADD ONE NEW RULE TO THE CULLING GAME)
"Add"?
(100 POINTS)
Can't we remove existing rules?
(ADD ONE NEW RULE)
It might be possible if we negate them
in a roundabout way.
(7. IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE PREVIOUS RULE)
Is that possible?
(THE GAME MASTER MUST ACCEPT)
Exactly.
(ANY PROPOSED NEW RULE)
They get to call the shots.
(UNLESS IT HINDERS THE PERMANENCE)
No.
The judgment should maintain
a certain degree of fairness.
Since the players are already forced
to accept the general rules,
from a jujutsu perspective,
the advantage won't lean towards Kenjaku.
(8. IF A PLAYERS' SCORE REMAINS THE SAME)
(AFTER 19 DAYS,THAT PLAYER SHOULD)
(BE SUBJECT TO CURSED TECHNIQUE REMOVAL)
Will I have to take lives again?
(REMAINS THE SAME)
No, I have a few ideas.
(CURSED TECHNIQUE REMOVAL)
(THE CULLING GAME)
Anyway, we've finished
going through the information.
Now, for our respective roles.
(NEXT STEPS)
(CHOSO, YUKI TSUKUMO)
Ms. Yuki and Choso will stay here.
(TENGEN'S GUARDS)
They will guard Master Tengen.
(MAKI ZEN'IN)
I'll go back to the Zen'in family
(RETRIEVE CURSED TOOLS AT ZEN'IN HOUSE)
to retrieve the cursed tools.
Not long after Satoru was sealed,
the Kamo and Zen'in families took
all the cursed tools
from Jujutsu High's cursed warehouse.
But Megumi is now the head
of the Zen'in family.
I'll explain it to you later.
Thanks to that, we can take whatever
we want from Zen'in's cursed warehouse.
But before that, Master Tengen,
(MAKI ZEN'IN, RETRIEVE CURSED TOOLS)
I know.
You mean
(JUZO KUMIYA'S ATELIER)
Juzo Kumiya's atelier?
Thank you for your understanding.
Once I'm done with this,
I'll go find Panda
and help pacify the Culling Game.
What about you, Yuta?
(OKKOTSU)
I'll enter the colony to join
the Culling Game.
(JOIN THE CULLING GAME, MEET PANDA)
Before Tsumiki and Fushiguro
(JOIN THE CULLING GAME)
join the Culling Game,
I'd gather as much intel as I can.
I'm really sorry.
I'll be on my own again,
but this is to prevent
our own people from killing each other.
And also,
in case something happens to Tsumiki,
I'll avoid the colony near nearby.
The barrier might block the signal.
I might not be able
to contact you for a while.
If Sukuna takes over me again,
please don't hesitate to kill me.
(FUSHIGURO WILL BE SAFER
WITH OKKUTSU BY ITADORI'S SIDE)
(BUT IN TERMS OF COMBAT POWER)
(OKKOTSU IS MORE EFFICIENT ON HIS OWN)
There's no time for that.
I'll be fine.
If I die,
you can ask Yuta to kill you.
No, that's what I want to prevent.
Maki.
(MEGUMI FUSHIGURO, YUJI ITADORI)
Yes.
Stick to the plan.
Go find Kinji.
(MEET UP WITH KINJI HAKARI)
Kinji?
(KINJI HAKARI)
Kinji Hakari.
He's a third-year student
who's currently suspended.
The biggest problem right now
is the lack of manpower.
Do whatever it takes to get him here.
Is he strong?
He's unstable,
but on a good day, he's stronger than me.
That's not true.
(EVOLUTION OF HUMANS ACROSS JAPAN)
(THE PURPOSE OF THE CULLING GAME)
(ASSIMILATE HUMANS WITH TENGEN)
(ITADORI AND THE OTHERS' TASKS)
(ANGEL IS IN THE COLONY EAST OF TOKYO)
(RESPECTIVE TASKS)
(MAKI, OKKUTSU, ITADORI, FUSHIGURO)
(JOIN THE CULLING GAME)
(TSUKUMO, CHOSO)
(REMAIN IN THE TOMBS OF STAR CORRIDOR)
Choso.
Thank you, you've been a huge help.
Don't die.
Are you crying?
Shush.
Thank you.
Takaba!
How long are you going to be depressed?
That's enough. You're depressing me too.
Yes…
How old are you now?
I'm 35.
Then you should quit.
Some people have worked
in this industry for a long time.
There are countless people who suddenly
rise to fame.
But they didn't suddenly become funny.
They were always funny.
It's just that
they were previously overlooked.
But you're not cut out for it.
Tokyo is like that now.
I'm saying this for your own good.
Find a job that you can do and suits you.
Takaba, I don't dislike your jokes.
Mr. Ken…
He's wrong, and so are you.
Funny or not, those who make it, make it.
You mean the one-hit wonders?
No.
There are two types of people
who stay popular.
Those who are always funny.
And those who always believe
they're funny.
Which one are you?
It was supposed to be 50-50,
but maybe it's 70-30?
It was supposed to be 50-50.
It was supposed to be 50-50,
(THE CULLING GAME PLAYER, FUMIHIKO TAKABA)
but maybe it's 70-30?
Mai, get ready.
Why are you here?
Do you want me to bully you like before?
Then go ahead.
You are me, and I am you.
Make me glad that I gave birth to you.
How ridiculous.
(NEXT EPISODE, THE PERFECT PREPARATION)
Destroy everything.