Yaga.
What is that thing?
Compared to other cursed techniques,
artificial cursed corpses have
the ability to move on their own.
However, a sorcerer must supply
and consume cursed energy
for them to move.
But that thing's cursed energy
belongs to it.
And it can be self-replenished.
The higher-ups have recognized you
as a Special Grade Sorcerer
and plan to officially order
your indefinite confinement.
Because if you intentionally
created that thing,
it means you can easily create an army.
Answer me, Yaga.
Do you really not know
how that thing is made?
Yes.
Masamichi.
Everyone's worried about you.
They say you're listless.
Is that so?
So I bragged that
if you're listless,
I'll be the one to cheer you up.
I see.
Aren't I a genius?
You certainly are.
Takeru.
I'm sorry, but I can't come home
for a while.
Please tell everyone for me.
Another business trip?
Yes, a long one.
Don't worry.
Master Tengen will protect this forest.
Your mother will come to see you again.
You'll be fine without me.
Masamichi.
We'll be lonely without you.
Are you sure, Kusakabe?
Don't tell anyone I saved you.
You were captured to lure Mr. Yaga out.
I owe him one.
Come on, get going.
Are you sure?
He's not your nephew.
He's an entity with information
about your nephew.
You want me to stop obsessing
over someone who's dead.
Otherwise, I can't live in the future, right?
But...
My sister
can't live without Takeru now.
Masamichi, she's my mother, isn't she?
That's right.
I'm impressed you recognized her.
I thought so.
Aren't I a genius?
Takeru...
I'm sorry...
I know.
The existence of a fully independent
cursed corpse can't be made public.
They can't live together.
I'm sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
Thank you so much.
I mean it.
Where are you going without
a cursed corpse?
Principal Yaga.
I'm going to see my son.
I'll tell you the only way
you can survive.
Tell me how to make a fully
independent artificial cursed corpse.
Since Satoru left,
you've suddenly become more aggressive.
Principal.
I'll take it from here. You may leave.
Yes, sir.
First, I'll copy the information
from the body and the soul.
Then we input that information
into the core of the cursed corpse.
But that's not enough.
The cores of three souls
that are compatible
must be placed into one cursed corpse,
so that the three souls can
keep observing each other.
By doing this,
the souls will stabilize
and form self-awareness.
Around three months after birth,
they started replenishing
their cursed energy.
Why are you telling me this now?
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
Why didn't you want to live?
Because this is a curse.
Principal Gakuganji.
This is the curse I put on you.
Masamichi!
Why don't you fight?
Don't you hate me?
Pandas don't get hung up
on things like that.
Besides, you and Masamichi
don't have a bad relationship.
To me, you're just a dagger
that fell on the ground.
But you'd better remember one thing.
Even pandas cry.
JUJUTSU KAISEN
(JUJUTSU KAISEN THE CULLING GAME PART 1)
Kinji Hakari is currently at the old
parking lot in Tochigi Prefecture.
He's making money as a bookmaker
for gambling tournaments.
Gambling tournaments?
It's where jujutsu sorcerers
fight each other.
So the gamblers are...
Basically, non-sorcerers.
Doesn't that completely violate
Jujutsu Rule No. 8, "Secrecy"?
There must be curse users
among the participants.
Be careful when taking action.
Why do we have to change clothes?
Hakari was suspended because
of a dispute with the higher-ups.
And he's currently violating
the Jujutsu Regulations.
If he finds out we're from Jujutsu High,
he might just run away.
Our relationship is like
a police officer and a thief.
What?
Are we considered part
of Jujutsu High right now?
It's a bit delicate.
But at least in Hakari's eyes, we are.
Anyway, is he the type to
help us in the first place?
I don't know.
After all, the upperclassmen
said he's scum.
But even Okkotsu said
he's stronger than him.
In terms of combat power,
we definitely need his help.
Go home, brats.
This is not a place for you
to fool around.
I'll count to three.
Turn around and leave.
If you do anything else, I'll beat you up.
I need money.
Let me take part
in the gambling competition here.
Rule number one.
Don't mention the club.
Answer me. Who told you?
I'll beat you up after you confess.
I don't know his name.
Because I killed him.
It was about a month ago.
Isn't there a good-for-nothing
who just acts tough?
Kondo disappeared a month ago.
I can fill his shoes.
Or I can steamroll up in front
of the bookmaker.
I see.
If we ask to meet him right away,
he'll be more cautious.
- And he can't reveal he knows Hakari.
- Yes. No, there's no proof.
- I'll just keep my mouth shut.
- Are you sure?
That's enough.
The boss allowed them to enter.
We'll send him in as today's seed.
However...
It's going to be the other kid.
Just as I wanted.
Itadori is more suitable for
the competition than me.
No, I'll go.
The boss said he doesn't
like the look of you.
Forget it if you don't accept.
Understood. Let's do that.
Fushiguro, isn't that too dangerous?
That's too much of a bluff.
It's not that bad.
Since a curse user is involved,
there should be some staff rotation.
Anyway,
yes, he's here.
Since he saw us
through the monitor just now,
there's a high chance Hakari is there.
Itadori, you'll investigate
from the inside.
I'll sneak into that parking lot
during that time...
Probably.
Probably?
They're probably letting me
do whatever I want.
If they find out I've snuck in,
they'll lose trust in me.
And I'll lose my chance to contact Hakari.
Then we'll have to use brute force.
That's the real last resort.
After all,
we're asking for his help.
We must avoid any situation
that might affect our future.
To be honest,
I don't think I should
make a move tonight.
But I don't want to waste any time
before Tsumiki's deadline
to declare for the Culling Game.
Currently...
It's 5 p.m. on the 10th.
Nine days left until the deadline?
It took us longer
to get here than expected.
So I'll sneak in tonight too.
I'll investigate Hakari in secret.
If things go south, I'll stop.
That's why I said "probably".
Got it.
There are two rules.
"No running away" and
"No cursed techniques".
Why?
I don't mind
if the opponent uses cursed techniques.
Most of the customers are non-sorcerers.
They can't see cursed techniques.
They won't understand the fight,
and the atmosphere won't be lively.
What about "No running away"?
It means "fight within sight
of the customers".
It's all about the customers.
Of course. We're doing business.
What kind of person is the boss?
Are you curious?
Kind of.
You'll find out when you meet him.
Can I meet him?
There are two types of matches.
Today's tournament is a "Real Match".
The other is a "Fake Match".
Of course, the boss writes the script.
If you put on a good show,
he might seek you out.
So, all I have to do is go wild, right?
That makes things a lot simpler.
That's your opponent.
I was shocked when I first saw him too.
He truly is a tourist attraction.
All right, tonight's match
is about to begin.
Gachinko Fight Club Tournament!
I, your familiar host, John Bobi,
will be broadcasting.
Let's introduce tonight's
super exciting contestants.
A sudden assassin appears,
an unexpected guest emerges.
The dangerous and thrilling
Fireball Boy, Yuji Itadori.
He stands like a Panda, sits like a Panda.
He walks exactly like a Panda.
Here comes Panda!
(ARENA)
Come on, place your bets!
Have you placed your bets? No more bets!
I can feel the excitement fading.
Why is that, Kinji?
Whether "luck" is good or bad,
you won't know until you try, right?
A bet where the outcome is
obvious from the start is boring.
Among rogue sorcerers, few can beat Panda.
- This has to be the best match
- I don't think so.
in my live broadcasting career!
(ARENA)
Panda, have you met Hakari yet?
Not yet.
(POKE)
Even though we know each other,
he wasn't wary of me.
But he avoided seeing me.
(POKE...)
(WHOA!)
Another problem is the cursed technique
of the other third-year.
You're hiding your identity
as a Jujutsu High student, right?
Yes.
Very good.
You know what to do next, right?
This is definitely the best match
in my live broadcasting career!
Even though I've only been
an announcer for half a month.
(POKE)
(POKE...)
The winner is Itadori!
His punch is too strong. I can't move!
Animal rights groups won't stand for this!
Such lame acting.
After the tournament,
bring Itadori to the rooftop.
What?
He's going to win all the matches anyway.
Besides, he deliberately
made stereoscopic moves
to attract the audience upstairs.
I think I can write a good script.
Didn't I always say,
strike while the iron is hot? Get it?
That seems foolish. Let's not do that.
Okay.
But what about the other kid?
Continue to keep an eye on him.
I'll send Kirara
to join the security later.
I like this excitement.
The last time I was this excited
was when my ex-girlfriend
went on a crazy installment spree.
Don't talk about your ex-girlfriend!
(KINJI HAKARI,JUJUTSU HIGH THIRD-YEAR
KIRARA HOSHI,JUJUTSU HIGH THIRD-YEAR)
I see.
It looks like Itadori has a chance
to meet Hakari.
Panda,
why haven't you met Hakari yet?
I know where he is.
He's in the control room on the roof.
But I just can't get close.
You can't get close?
No matter how long I walk
towards the door, I can't get any closer.
It's similar to Satoru's cursed technique.
It's probably Kirara's cursed technique?
Kirara?
Isn't the other third-year a boy?
He is a boy.
That phenomenon,
does it only happen when Kirara
is in the control room?
I don't know.
I thought that rather than chasing him
and letting him get away,
I should be a panda
that attracts tourists.
I'm glad you two are here.
Do you think Itadori can convince him?
It won't be easy.
But I think it's just a matter of time.
Itadori is cheerful and naturally likable,
so he should get along with Hakari.
But he's not good at lying, right?
It's not that he's not good at it.
He's more like someone who wouldn't
even think of lying in the first place.
So?
The moment Itadori enters
the control room,
we must immediately sneak in
and neutralize their base
to buy them time to talk.
No, this method...
Don't worry.
We'll just have them take a nap.
I've already mapped out
the camera locations and blind spots.
How many guards are there?
Four at the entrance.
Two on each floor, except the rooftop.
This might work.
My only concern is Kirara's
cursed technique.
That can't be helped.
If he teleports Itadori away
or calls his comrades,
we'll give up on persuading Hakari.
Yuji, you're only a first-year
high schooler? So young.
Yuji...
Kinji repeated a year
in middle school, you know.
You look happy.
I am.
It's been a while since Kinji
has been so zealous.
You know,
I love a passionate Kinji.
Itadori.
If someone told you,
"You can earn a million yen a month
by doing something for an hour a day,"
would you believe it?
What?
It depends on what it is.
But if you want to know
what that "something" is,
you have to pay 200,000 yen
for the information first.
How could I believe that?
Exactly. It's just as you feel.
It's a typical scam.
The con artist presents himself as rich.
He sells a way to get rich
and makes money that way.
If you think about it,
it's obviously a scam.
But there are a lot of idiots
who get scammed.
Why?
It's all because of "zeal."
Zeal?
Both the con artist and the victim
have the "zeal"
to "turn their lives around here."
Once a person is blinded by "zeal,"
they make poor judgments.
But without "zeal,"
you can't even fall in love.
And I love "zeal."
There's a more direct way
of communicating "zeal"...
Do you know what it is?
Is it gambling?
You really get it.
Life is a gamble.
A lot of women dumped me
because they hated gambling.
But they got it all wrong.
In this society, the first to be
eliminated are those who can't bluff
and those who don't know
when to quit while they're ahead.
Who in the world doesn't gamble?
It's not gambling that they hate.
It's "defeat" and "disillusion."
Some people just want
to live a peaceful life.
I don't care about those people.
I love "zeal."
"Zeal" is a "gamble."
"Gambling" is "life."
And "love" is "domination."
In the future,
with the Gachinko Fight Club,
I'm going to dominate
this country's "passion."
The existence of cursed spirits
is widely known now.
The Jujutsu Headquarters
can barely function.
It's a good opportunity for me
to expand my business.
I'm going to eliminate all obstacles.
While the Jujutsu Regulations
are being revised,
I'll use this opportunity to get
the fight club officially acknowledged.
In short,
I need a good pawn now.
Itadori.
Do you want to indulge in my "passion"?
Bookie, I'd like to discuss--
Itadori, do you want something to drink?
Anything is fine, except alcohol.
What? You can't hold your liquor?
It's not about that. I'm a minor.
I didn't think you'd care about that.
You know what?
Satoru Gojo can't hold his liquor either.
Who's Gojo?
And you said "either." I didn't...
Hey.
What sorcerer hasn't heard of Satoru Gojo?
Why are you pretending not to know?
You...
Are you from Jujutsu High?
Listen, I'm...
Wait, listen...
Listen...
Kirara is calling from his phone.
It's a sign that something is wrong.
Hear me out!
I won't!
It's because I've cooled down.
(EPISODE 52 ZEAL)
If I can persuade him somehow,
negotiations with Hakari
will go more smoothly.
Wait, Kirara!
Stay out of this.
You have to tell me right here!
Please. We don't have much time.
Kinji is in danger.
(NEXT EPISODE, PARTS)