♪ If I could escape from fate's predetermined path ♪
♪ And touch the true essence of time and space, the ultimate secret ♪
♪ I'll awaken this extraordinary destiny ♪
♪ And awaken another version of myself ♪
♪ The clearest, most resilient eyes of yours ♪
♪ Crystals filled with infinite power ♪
♪ Unleash my true nature ♪
♪ Take every breath at lightning speed ♪
♪ Shining justice ♪
♪ The only truth in the duel ♪
♪ Now you guys are hearing my cry ♪
♪ My life was full of regrets ♪
♪ Restart ♪
♪ Striving, fighting, honing ♪
♪ Finding my future ♪
♪ Do not just dream it, have a try ♪
♪ Nothing can beat me, bravery's in my chest ♪
♪ I'll smash myself to protect your tenderness ♪
♪ Never bow down again ♪
[Super Cube]
[Episode 10]
The show has just begun.
I guarantee
no one can guess what the next evil beast is.
This is
a special gift I prepared for you.
Combining the agility of cats and the strength of bears,
here's the ultimate masterpiece of Du Biotech,
Taowu 17!
What is that?
What the hell is that?
These psychos.
His only weakness is that he's too cruel,
instinctively tearing apart all living things around him.
He even
ate the man who tied the golden bell on him.
Now,
which of you warriors would like to challenge this epic beast?
This feeling...
No.
It's not that beast.
Someone's
trying to stir up trouble.
Even the organizer and committee missed it.
There's a mole
in my team.
The reward for getting Taowu 17's bell
is twice as much as Nicholas!
Young Master Yan from Youzhou has
sent out the first challenger.
What?
It... It's attacking the glass!
Run! It's getting out!
Please don't worry.
We have absolute security.
Abso-solutely safe...
How dare you ignore me!
Die!
Where'd it go?
Huh?
What the hell's going on?
He did it.
Though it was covert,
he couldn't escape my microwave vision.
I thought he sprinkled the powder
to deal with the crocodile.
Now it seems...
it was to set up this accident.
Don't just stand there!
Stop the beast!
Mr. Murong.
Thanks for saving me.
Mr. Murong!
Please allow my guards to enter
the banquet with armed weapons!
No.
It'll only make things worse.
Hey,
is this some special segment, Du?
You guys know you did it.
But chaos is good.
I can get what I want from the Yans.
Get me out of here now!
Yes, sir!
We four order keepers will bring things under control.
Please return to your positions.
Please don't worry.
Alright.
You can all relax now.
The issue's been resolved.
Enjoy the rest of the banquet.
They went to such great lengths
but still failed.
Jianeng,
you really know how to make things tense.
But it's fine.
Since we're here, we'll protect you.
Eight.
Nine.
Someone's missing.
I see.
You said there was an issue?
Please respond.
The order keepers stepped up
to resolve it.
All's good.
Next, the seven teams will take care of the rest.
Understood.
Huh?
The light's out?
Such lousy stuff in the Du Mansion?
This is...
Access approved.
There really are rats who can break into the treasure vault.
Is that all you've got?
Take this!
You're strong, huh?
Oh, hello, Miss Pigtails.
Intruder!
Did no one tell you
not to turn your back on the enemy?
that stabbing someone in the back is low?
Why are you here?
On my way to the restroom,
I got lost.
Think I'm dumb?
You got lost and came all the way here?
If you wanna chit-chat, do it in hell!
Oh, shut up, Level-C loser.
Level-C...
loser?
Are you a friend or foe?
Tell me!
I'm your bodyguard.
You...
What are you on about?
You're the real employer.
And your aim is
to sneak into Du Mansion for a secret mission,
right?
How did you know?
Your position.
Even if Mr. Piao can fight,
as the boss,
he wouldn't stand in front of a bodyguard.
Unless
you're the one who should be protected.
It's pointless to say this now.
This area's been sealed.
And Rudra's order keepers
will arrive in two minutes.
Two minutes?
Let's hurry up and go in then.
Are you dumb?
It must be empty!
Who knows where that sly fox
hid the treasure?
I'm curious.
You seem to know how to escape.
Why do you ask?
I'll tell you where the treasure is,
and you'll help me escape.
Deal?
You know where the treasure is?
Come out.
Hide-and-seek is over, kids.
Give me that.
Game over.
You sure it's that way?
Mumu Xia!
Wang Xiaoxiu!
Distracted, huh?
What an unfair fight.
Three Level-Bs against us two;
aren't you ashamed?
The dead don't talk.
Fine, let's die together.
A dud?
No.
It's fake?
I think we're good for now.
They're strong
and in sync.
Good thing that toy distracted them.
But it's a matter of time before they find us.
So,
can you move?
Thanks.
If
you were alone,
you'd have escaped.
I need intel.
On the Yans.
On Xigu Qin.
Anything that will help me find Yao.
Yao?
They're coming.
We can't just sit and wait.
I've got it.
Where's the other one?
That weak girl would just hold me back.
You actually left her behind?
Where exactly?
You go catch that woman.
Seriously?
Fine.
You've the final say.
Don't resist.
You'll suffer less.
Bin De!
Don't get distracted during the fight!
Follow me!
You're so strong.
Why didn't you break the walls just now?
Then we'd be buried here.
It's because this area's reinforced
that we're safe.
Listen.
This scroll is mine, you hear me?
Who cares for paper books?
I only read e-books now.
It's here!
The Obsidian Essence.
What's the floor below?
Du Weibang's biogenetic research institute.
There's a large drainage pipe that
leads to the outside.
How do you know everything?
No comment.
I have a bad feeling.
Hey, are you okay?
I was careless.
I just took a nap,
and the place is wrecked?
My Lord.
Eat this.
[Next Episode Preview]
This is...
Du Weibang's biogenetics research institute.
You're here.
The professor's been waiting for you.
These people are zealots of bioengineering.
They believe they can transform lives, living, and military prowess.
He has a gun.
Wang Xiaoxiu!
Our gene hybridization experiment's shown
that the human body can be greatly enhanced.
I can't die yet.
Let's see... who will die first!
Are you okay?
♪ It's like a dream ♪
♪ I want to touch you but I plunge ♪
♪ Into the swarming crowd ♪
♪ Like being pushed into a boundless whirlpool ♪
♪ I'm excluded from your light ♪
♪ How can I get close to you? ♪
♪ I need to convey my yearning to you ♪
♪ It's too late ♪
♪ At this chapter of our story, I'm all alone ♪
♪ Swirling petals ♪
♪ Mirroring the regret of disappointment ♪
♪ Before the starry sky dims ♪
♪ Can I catch a last glimpse of you? ♪
♪ It doesn't matter if you don't notice me ♪
♪ Memories of us stranded in my chest ♪
♪ Suddenly plunging me into an abyss ♪
♪ I shut my eyes ♪
♪ Can't bear to see yesterday replay ♪
♪ Say goodbye ♪
♪ My feet are still lingering ♪
♪ How can I ♪
♪ Let go and get over it? ♪
♪ Say goodbye ♪
♪ Leave with nothing ♪
♪ Where is my light? ♪
♪ All that's left is a void ♪