♪ If I could escape from fate's predetermined path ♪
♪ And touch the true essence of time and space, the ultimate secret ♪
♪ I'll awaken this extraordinary destiny ♪
♪ And awaken another version of myself ♪
♪ The clearest, most resilient eyes of yours ♪
♪ Crystals filled with infinite power ♪
♪ Unleash my true nature ♪
♪ Take every breath at lightning speed ♪
♪ Shining justice ♪
♪ The only truth in the duel ♪
♪ Now you guys are hearing my cry ♪
♪ My life was full of regrets ♪
♪ Restart ♪
♪ Striving, fighting, honing ♪
♪ Finding my future ♪
♪ Do not just dream it, have a try ♪
♪ Nothing can beat me, bravery's in my chest ♪
♪ I'll smash myself to protect your tenderness ♪
♪ Never bow down again ♪
Congrats on passing the rigorous assessment.
Next, let's welcome Mr. Piao.
Congratulations.
You've earned the chance to be my bodyguard.
With you capable talents...
I believe tonight's banquet
will be interesting.
Do your best.
If you do well, you'll get extra rewards.
I'll leave the rest to you,
Mr. Xu.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Piao's
already transferred the commission to you in advance.
Other than the agreed-upon 3 million Earth Coins,
Mr. Piao promised
- that after the banquet, there'll be more...
- Huh? What 3 million?
Mr. Wang Xiaoxiu.
Don't you know?
Your agent, Mu Yuqian, has confirmed
the payment.
I'm getting only 50,000 out of the 3 million.
Mu Yuqian, this isn't a deal. It's a scam!
So
there's still six hours until
the banquet begins.
You have a really busy day ahead.
Scentless Jasmine
will brief you about the details on the way.
The following content is strictly confidential.
This Rudra Banquet held in State H on Earth
involves seven missions.
One of them is the auction.
Mr. Piao's target is this:
the ancient mask.
Mr. Piao's set his heart on it.
And we will
help him achieve his goal.
What is this?
The Obsidian Essence,
one of the main auction items.
What are you trying to say, Cube?
Obsi... dian...
Cube clearly said "obsidian."
Is this...
You have to memorize all the info before we arrive.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Though I was tricked by that woman,
there are many
things I want at this banquet.
Just you wait, Yan Luo.
I will find you!
Dear distinguished guests,
it's my pleasure to welcome you to the Rudra Banquet.
Let's skip the boring opening speech
and get right into it.
I hope you have a wonderful time.
As usual,
we'll start off with
a warm-up game.
The game is called
"The Warrior's Golden Bell."
Don't panic.
Your safety is the top priority of this banquet.
This is reinforced bulletproof glass.
Starting things off with such a monster.
Impatient as always, Du.
Exactly.
Where's the build up?
Shouldn't you start off with
less threatening wolves and mastiffs?
Oh, don't you worry.
Tonight will be one climax after another.
Well,
the rules of the game are simple.
A golden bell's tied
around the beast's neck.
You can only
use cold weapons.
If you remove the bell from the evil beast, you win.
As they say,
incentives are the best motivation.
And this
is the reward for brave warriors.
Last but not least,
the last rule.
Before you get the bell,
you cannot leave the cage.
These scumbags.
How's this bodyguarding?
They're toying with lives!
Alright!
Our warriors are ready!
Open the cage!
Come on, you evil beast!
Babe, isn't it exciting?
That guy was a joke.
To think I was counting on him to exhaust that beast.
No, he wasn't weak.
Something's off with that beast.
It's way too speedy.
Unfortunately,
the first challenger failed.
Nonetheless,
we still thank him for his
wonderful performance before his passing.
Sorry.
I forgot to explain.
Nicholas isn't an ordinary crocodile.
It's the masterpiece of our Du Biotech,
a crocodile with enhanced functions.
Its explosive power is 1.5 times greater.
According to the rules,
the reward will increase by 30%.
Who will be our next warrior?
Hao'er, are you up to it?
Though that crocodile's speedy,
his attack range is short.
I will
fight for you, Young Master.
I think we have our second warrior.
Let's see what he's got.
The second challenger chose polearms that can be thrown.
Looks like he wants to attack from a distance.
Why are there always money-hungry idiots
offering to die?
You really didn't read the contract?
What?
If no one volunteers,
someone will be randomly forced to fight.
What an unfair clause!
Why'd you think the daily salary is three million Earth Coins?
But I can only get 50,000!
That dang scammer!
Was there always a man there?
Don't stare.
He's from the Rudra Banquet Committee.
He maintains order.
An order keeper?
No wonder he's so powerful.
Bullseye again!
If I use the terrain to my advantage,
a giant lizard's no match for me.
Although it's injured,
the crocodile
doesn't seem compromised.
Howl of the wolf with sharp fangs!
Adios!
Nice one.
That man...
is doomed.
What do you think?
One climax after another!
Exciting, huh?
Let's resume the game.
The reward has increased by another 30%.
Where is our real warrior?
I know these beasts
are nothing to you.
What I want to say is,
as long as you defeat that evil beast and make me proud,
I'll double the reward out of my own pocket.
Double?
If I win the reward,
my life will turn around overnight.
This is how people are blinded by greed.
Let me, Fabian Modi,
fight on your behalf, Mr. Sanmu.
Modi.
Good luck.
Great.
Wait!
I'm Gold Poison.
I want to join in the fun too.
Last Man Standing!
Now this is a show.
What's Last Man Standing?
If more than one warrior
wants to challenge the caged beast,
they'll have to fight each other
to the death.
That's simple and crude.
But even if Gold Poison defeats Modi...
I doubt he'd have any energy left after.
You clearly don't know Gold Poison.
Do your best, young man.
Reward awaits you.
Modi.
If you kill him,
you'll get a long vacation,
and a promotion and a raise.
Thank you so much,
Mr. San—
Mu!
Let... go!
Modi!
Looks like Modi wasn't destined to enjoy the benefits.
Mr. Sanmu.
Why don't you transfer them to me?
Useless trash!
Gold Poison's skill
is boosting combat power by sucking the blood of his target.
The stronger the target, the greater the boost to his power.
The downside is
after the effects wear off,
he'll become afraid of the cold and light.
Wow, what a skill.
Wonderful performance.
Gold Poison
has qualified to challenge the caged beast.
Open the cage!
Young man,
no need for weapons?
It's weaponless too.
I hate winning unfairly.
Is he crazy?
I have a bad feeling.
I may be bloodthirsty,
but I'm an animal rights activist.
I'll show you mercy
by making it quick for you.
His burst of speed's comparable to Level-B fighters.
He's a master we can't underestimate.
Congrats, Gold Poison.
You got the first golden bell tonight.
Will you collect your reward directly, or...
By delivery.
I don't want to be so high-profile.
Okay.
Let’s toast to the warrior!
Du.
Things are just starting to heat up.
Don't tell me it's the end?
Mr. Yan.
Rest assured.
The show has just begun.
I guarantee
no one can guess what the next evil beast is.
Du, don’t be so certain.
Is there anything we veterans haven’t seen?
This is... a special gift
I prepared for you.
Oh no.
There's a sense of foreboding.
Combining the agility of cats
and the strength of bears,
here's the ultimate masterpiece of Du Biotech,
Taowu 17!
Don't resist. You'll suffer less.
Intruder!
This area's been sealed.
And Rudra's order keeper will arrive in two minutes.
Hello, Miss Pigtails.
Are you a friend or foe? Tell me!
It's attacking the glass!
Please don't worry.
We have absolute security.
There's a... mole in my team.
♪ It's like a dream ♪
♪ I want to touch you but I plunge ♪
♪ Into the swarming crowd ♪
♪ Like being pushed into a boundless whirlpool ♪
♪ I'm excluded from your light ♪
♪ How can I get close to you? ♪
♪ I need to convey my yearning to you ♪
♪ It's too late ♪
♪ At this chapter of our story, I'm all alone ♪
♪ Swirling petals ♪
♪ Mirroring the regret of disappointment ♪
♪ Before the starry sky dims ♪
♪ Can I catch a last glimpse of you? ♪
♪ It doesn't matter if you don't notice me ♪
♪ Memories of us stranded in my chest ♪
♪ Suddenly plunging me into an abyss ♪
♪ I shut my eyes ♪
♪ Can't bear to see yesterday repeat ♪
♪ Say goodbye ♪
♪ My feet are still lingering ♪
♪ How can I ♪
♪ Let go and get over it? ♪
♪ Say goodbye ♪
♪ Leave with nothing ♪
♪ Where is my light? ♪
♪ All that's left is a void ♪