Yuji.
You're a strong kid, so help people.
>title
Episode 41
Thunderclap II
>Shibuya 109
23:05
Dogenzaka, In Front of Shibuya 109
In my Ten Shadows Technique,
only two Divine Dogs are granted to the user at first.
To use other cursed beasts, they must be subjugated.
The user gains cursed beasts which
they can use to subjugate more of them,
until they command all ten cursed beasts.
You done?
You're really strong, just like that girl earlier.
And you're all still young.
Even on your last legs,
you give me no openings to get close.
But with all that bleeding,
I won't even have to do anything.
Thing is, this subjugation
can be done with multiple people.
Doing so will void the ritual afterward, though.
Which means it becomes pointless for the sorcerer.
But even a pointless ritual has its uses.
Someone's being real flashy!
I'll continue.
While a cursed beast can't be used
without subjugating it first,
it can be summoned for the subjugation
ritual as many times as necessary.
You don't mean...
Not a single sorcerer has ever managed to subjugate this one.
Do you know why the Gojo clan
and the Zenin clan are on bad terms?
They're on bad terms?
Sparks are constantly flying!
Since the Edo Era? Or maybe Keicho?
I forget when.
The heads of the clans back then got serious
during a duel before the aristocracy,
and they both died.
Were the heads of those clans...
Just like me, one of them possessed
both the Six Eyes and the Limitless technique.
And coincidentally, the other had the same technique as you.
The Ten Shadows Technique.
You see what I'm getting at?
That doesn't mean I can become strong enough to beat you.
I bet the head of the clan back then
used it in much the same way.
Furube Yurayura
Sacred treasure, swing and ring...
Is something the matter, Sukuna-sama?
An urgent business.
I see.
It won't be much longer before I'm free.
Do not slack on your preparations.
See you later, Uraume.
Understood.
I shall be awaiting your return.
He got me!
He's starting the ritual!
And he's forcing me in this damn thing with him!
Eight-Handled Sword
Divergent Sila Divine General
Makora.
See you later.
Right!
Sorry, Itadori.
Hey, asshole!
Good luck dealiny with this shit.
I'll see you in hell.
Wait...
Wait, wa-wait, wait, wait!
Oh, fuck you!
Damn it!
Wake up, you piece of shit!
Curse user Shigemo Haruta's technique
erases life's little daily miracles
from his memory and stores them up.
They manifest as markings under his eyes,
and a miracle is released when
he is faced with a threat to his life.
However, he is unaware of this fact himself.
Suspended animation, huh?
I see what's going on.
Saving this piece of trash was the right move indeed.
He must have been dragged into the subjugation ritual.
If this trash dies too, the ritual will be complete,
and Fushiguro Megumi will die as well.
Don't die on me.
There's something I need you to do.
U-Um...
Silence.
In order for Fushiguro Megumi to survive,
I must defeat this cursed beast as an outsider,
and nullify the subjugation ritual.
Time for a tasting, then.
>eyecatch
_
Dismantle.
That sword...
It's the Sword of Exorcism,
specialized in combating cursed spirits.
It carries the same positive energy
that's generated by reverse cursed technique.
If I were a cursed spirit, that would have
eliminated me on the first hit.
Tastes awful.
You wanna go?!
Oh?
You did something, didn't you?
Now that felt odd.
Again?!
Cursed energy?!
You really are something!
You see it, don't you?
You can see my technique!
I knew it.
You're like the Eight-Headed Serpent.
You recognized my slices.
You even started attacking with cursed energy.
Both happened after that Great Wheel revolved.
The incantation of sacred treasures and the Great Wheel
together represent a continuous cycle of balance.
Which suggests that this cursed beast's ability
is to adapt to anything and everything.
It's the ultimate late-throw rock-paper-scissors!
You might have defeated me in the state I was in back then.
Well, you showed me, Fushiguro Megumi!
Domain Expansion:
Malevolent Shrine.
Fukuma Mizushi
Sukuna's Domain, Malevolent Shrine, is a curious one.
Unlike other domains, it does not
close its barrier to cut out a separate space.
Manifesting an innate domain without closing its barrier
is like painting an art piece not on a canvas but in the air.
It is truly a divine feat.
Additionally, allowing its victims a
path of escape acts as a Binding Vow
which vastly increases the range of its sure-hit
effect to a maximum radius of 200 meters.
Out of consideration for Fushiguro Megumi,
he has currently limited that effect to a 140 meter radius.
Anything?
Nope. No signal.
Same.
I don't think we need to worry too much, though.
Oh?
Remember the guy with the megaphone?
Sukuna's slices are comprised of two types.
Within the range of his sure-hit effect,
Cleave attacks objects that possess cursed energy,
while Dismantle attacks objects that do not.
Both rain down endlessly upon everything
until Malevolent Shrine disappears.
There is only one guaranteed way to defeat Makora:
Annihilate it with a new attack before it can adapt to it.
Cleave would have fulfilled those conditions,
but rather than adapting just to Dismantle,
if it had adapted to slices in general,
that would be a different case entirely.
Makora was close to finishing its regeneration.
Open.
Fūga
What are you looking at?
Begone.
E-E-Excuse me, then!
I really am lucky!
For another day...
I survived!
Shigemo's stock of miracles had been
exhausted in his battle with Nanami Kento.
Oh, it's almost time.
Fushiguro!
I think I saw Itadori for a moment.
No, was it Sukuna?!
23:14
Dogenzaka, In Front of Shibuya 109
Hey, brat, be sure to savor this.
I should've died.
I was supposed to die!
U R MY SPECIAL
It should've been me!
Just kill yourself!
Right now!
U R MY SPECIAL
Let's keep dancing until our dying breath
imawa no kiwakiwa de odorimashou
Tokyo's the heart of all the action
Tōkyō zensen kyou no miyako
Let's keep struggling until there's nothing left
oujou giwa no kiwakiwa de agakimashou
Show me just how wild you can get
ogyougi no warui tsura mo misete yo
i luv u 6a6y
Let's keep singing
utai tsuzukemashou
No matter how absurd it is
donna shiremono mo
No matter how out of place
donna yosomono mo
Every move you make
kokoro moeru
Lights a fire in my heart
ikkyoshu ittousoku
Got me losing control
hashiridashitara ankontorooru
'cause U R MY SPECIAL
Won't you mess me up, set the night on fire?
muchakucha ni shite kurenai kai?
Devour everything to your heart's content
issai wo zonbun ni kuraitsukushite
After an eternity in this maze, we meet at last
isshou meikyuu kaiyuu randebuu
To the point it makes me faint
memai ga suru hodo
U R MY SPECIAL
World goes round and round, with or without answers
uyamuya na mama mawaru sekai
I have to get up.
No! No! No need to bring along your sanity
no! no! no! sou reisei ni wa naranaide
I have to fight.
After an eternity in this maze, we meet at last
isshou meikyuu kaiyuu randebuu
No matter what anyone says
dare ga dou iou to
U R MY SPECIAL
Otherwise, I'm...
WE R SPECIAL
>title
Shibuya Incident
nothing but a murderer.
Things are really getting out of hand!
I'll count the prime numbers to calm down.
One, two, three... uh, nine...
You missed five and seven.
Next time, Right and Wrong.
Next Episode
Right and Wrong
You'll turn into a panda if you don't watch!
You really are an animal.