Body improvement!
Fight on! Fight on! Fight on! Fight!
Psychic powers don't make a man appealing.
And so, in order to change myself,
I joined the Body Improvement Club.
Body improvement!
Fight on! Fight on! Fight on!
Fight... on... Fight... on...
This isn't good.
He must be anemic.
Sh-Showwy......
Mob's Stamina:  0  %
cial
cial
cial
what
you
want
what
you
want
what
be
you
what
want
you
to
want
Everyone will surely find their own answer
appu
appu
Longing... Distress... Pump up!
appu
shii
shii
Searching for yourself... Telepathy!
shii
shou
shou
da
Asking for too much... Psycho punch!
shou
shun
sshu
sei
shun
sshu
Youthful days... Salt splash!
sei
shun
sshu
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
Mob?
What
do
you
want?
Mob?
What
do
you
want?
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
Mob?
What
do
you
want?
Mob?
Why
do
you
want?
Mob?
Why
do
you
want?
Mob?
Why
do
you
want?
Mob?
Who
do
you
want?
Mob?
Who
do
you
want?
Mob?
Who
do
you
want?
Move!
Just
like
Mob!
Move!
Just
like
Mob!
Move!
Just
like
Mob!
cial
cial
If
Mob!
cial
what
you
want
what
you
want
what
be
you
what
want
you
to
want
Even if you're burdened by happiness and sadness...
Your
life
is
your
own,
O
K?
Your
life
is
your
own,
O
K?
Your
life
is
your
own,
It's OK to not be special
Everyone will surely find their own answer
There's definitely something wrong with him.
Who would choose the
Body Improvement Club in that situation?
Well, let's not dwell on the past.
Come on. It's your turn, President Kurata.
Hey.
Ah, Musashi!
Lower Body Strengthening Month!!
Body Improvement!!
Thank you so much for
letting us use this room!
You don't have to grovel...
All we want the room for is to store our equipment.
What's with him?
Oh, Kageyama passed out.
Sorry, but could you watch over him?
Seriously, dude.
Why did you join the Body Improvement Club?
I've never been the most athletic guy.
And I'm a really slow runner.
It's because I've relied on my
psychic powers for everything.
Huh? What kind of excuse is that?
If you actually have psychic powers,
I'd love to see them, jeez.
Is that enough for you to believe me?
This is heavy!
Seriously? He could only bend spoons before!
Please! Help me make my dream come true!
Believe it or not...
My dream is to contact and interact
with extraterrestrial lifeforms!
At first, I followed a guidebook
and tried it out, but it didn't work.
And before I knew it, I was just lazing around...
But now,
I've got my big break!
Mob, let's research telepathy together,
seek a new life, and boldly go
where no man has gone before!
Actually, I've got weight lifting to do.
Wait, why?
I'm burning with passion here.
Why are you so ice-cold?
I've finally found something that I want to do.
What, putting on muscle?
But you have psychic powers...
Actually, maybe I should say I want to
become more appealing as a man.
You want to be popular, Mob?
No, not really...
Well, you won't be.
Even if you gain muscle, you won't become popular.
Not a chance!
Th-Then what should I do?
Read girls' minds using telepathy.
Then you'll be super popular.
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
What? Telepathy?
Yeah, I can't really do that.
I can hear the voices of spirits, though...
What brought this on?
I was just wondering...
Is there someone whose mind you want to read?
A girl, huh?
My, my, Mob...
You're so easy to read.
Well, every middle school boy wants to be popular,
so there's no need to be embarrassed.
Even I want to be popular.
It's not like I want to be popular.
I just want to get close to Tsubomi.
Pardon me, young man.
Something must be troubling you.
You aren't laughing or smiling.
No...
I can tell.
You're worried about your studies, right?
I'm not.
Of course not. It's not your studies...
Yes, it must be hard dealing with family issues.
Actually, I don't have any.
Of course you don't.
It must be your health... No...
It's about love.
How did you know?!
If you want to resolve your troubles, come with me.
Actually, I have to head home.
You'll be popular.
I'll go!
An Invite to a Meeting
~Simply Put, I Just Want to Be Popular~
I belong to a brand-new religious order
that came into existence last month.
Religious order?
It's called (LOL).
Founded by our leader, Dimple,
it's the happiest and trendiest
gathering of the century!
Dimple has the mysterious power
to make anyone laugh immediately.
So, how do I become popular?
Now, now, don't be so hasty.
(LOL) is in no way a suspicious group.
LOL
Wow, there are a lot of people.
I wonder if they all want to be popular, too.
Oh, are you new, too?
Huh?
Then get on stage.
Why?
Come on, now.
Hurry.
Heave-ho, heave-ho!
I have no idea what's going on anymore.
Huh? Mob?
Do you recognize me?
I'm Mezato from your class.
Mezato Ichi
Ah, I've never talked to her before.
Did they lure you in?
Um, I...
He's here!
It's Dimple!
Everyone...
Are you laughing?
Are you sufficiently warmed up now?
Why don't we take off those masks, then?
Sparkle!
You're all smiling so brightly.
What a creepy bunch...
Stop!
Today, we have three new
smilemates joining us.
Give them a big hand!
Huh? What?
Hey, don't...
In order to accept happiness,
you must set your hearts free.
But your hearts are locked up.
See? It's completely obvious
why you're unhappy.
You aren't laughing.
LOL
Laugh. If you laugh even in pain,
your hearts will be unlocked!
And once they have been set free,
your hearts will have the ability to
accept happiness as it comes.
In order to have a happy life,
you must have a hearty laugh!
That is the teaching of (LOL).
Hah. How I wish people could
be happy just by laughing.
Who might this be?
We found him on a park bench.
How sad. A victim of the recession!
It's no wonder you've lost your smile.
But worry not!
Let's put on this smile mask and fix that.
Hey, what are you...
Hey...
This is our way of saving you.
We just want you to smile.
No resistance.
Lastly, the girl.
It appears that you have something to say.
Religious order (LOL), established last month?
You managed to attract this many
followers in just one month?
I don't believe that!
Oh? And you are...?
I work for Salt Middle School's newspaper!
I'm Mezato from Class 2-1!
I'm reporting on the bad rumor
concerning you guys.
Bad rumor?
That you're using group hypnosis to
brainwash and force people into joining.
She has the nerve to say that
after sneaking in by herself.
Splendid.
Let me provide you with proof, then.
Please take a look at
the gentleman from earlier.
A few minutes ago, he was a very sad man.
Sparkle!
What a wonderful smile!
How funny...
He's laughing? Why?
He has now truly grasped happiness.
What do you think, young lady?
True, they didn't do anything bad...
I'm sure you'll find a job.
But something's still off.
There's something strange in the air here...
This story is a bit too much
for me to handle,
so if you'll excuse me...
That won't do.
You infiltrated (LOL) and
doubted our smiles for no reason.
I'm terribly sorry.
I won't write about you in the school paper.
That is not enough!
It won't ease our hard feelings!
We won't let you leave until you laugh.
I-I don't really feel like laughing right now.
And if I forced myself to right now,
it wouldn't be sincere.
Start with a smile.
No! I don't want to lie to myself.
Hey!
What is this?!
H-Huh? I'm...
No! Don't!
No!
Sparkle!
Look at that magnificent smile!
Congratulations!
You seem completely different now.
No, I...
What a gleaming smile.
No...
What is this feeling?
We're all smiling, and it feels really nice...
But no! I don't really want to smile!
Someone save me!
Um, excuse me.
Mob!
So the theme here is smiling and happiness?
It doesn't have anything to do
with being popular?
May I leave now, then?
Who's that?
He looked troubled on his way home
from school, so I brought him here.
It seems he's having trouble with love.
I'm not really troubled, though.
He's not smiling!
Are you telling me that
the smile mask didn't work?
Huh? He's not smiling?
Bye.
W-Wait!
Do you plan to live the rest
of your life with that face?
You are missing out on life!
My dad said that
"people who've never smoked before
are missing out on half of their lives."
It made me realize that everyone has
a different idea of "missing out."
That's not what I'm talking about.
(LOL) is the start line for me to become
a religious figure for all of humanity!
I can't let this trip me up!
I just want you to know
how wonderful it is to smile.
That's okay.
Th-Then would you like to
play a game before you leave?
A staring contest. You'll have a staring
contest with three of my smile leaders.
Smile
Leaders
You'll all drink milk,
and the first to laugh loses.
What do you think?
Mob, this is a trap!
Progress Toward
Mob's Explosion
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 58%
Are you ready? If you laugh, you lose.
Why did you accept the challenge?!
Mob loves milk.
Ready, go!
Why?!
Go!
Impossible...
Those two are pathetic.
With my smiling powers, I'll throw
that boy into a smiley maelstrom...
Smile Leader
O-Oh, I see!
Forcing them to laugh all the time backfired!
I won, so I'm going home now.
Wait!
You'll have to face me now!
What?
Dimple is going to face him himself?
I will not let you win.
I will make you spit out that milk!
Ready, go!
That milk...
clearly had something mixed in.
He laughed!
He spit it out!
Nothing less from our Dimple!
He saved another!
Even I'm starting to have fun now...
I... didn't laugh.
Huh? My smile...
Wait, why am I here again?
Because it's so much fun!
You just...
No, he couldn't possibly have
undone my hypnosis.
But why can't I make him laugh?
I have no choice. I'll have to go all out.
Everyone! Let us save
the laughter trapped within him!
If he stayed this way,
I'd feel too sorry for him!
How wonderful!
Dimple!
Let us laugh!
Hey, wait. I...
Smile and live a good life!
See? You don't have a single enemy here,
so what exactly are you fighting?
Get a clue.
Hey, Mob.
Why do you always look so bored?
Huh?
If you're bored, go home.
But I'm not.
You're the only one who's not laughing.
Mob.
Tsubomi.
Get a clue.
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 74%
I will show you my true power.
Now, laugh!
There it is!
It's Dimple's divine power!
What?!
Why?!
Why aren't you laughing?!
Are you saying my powers don't work on you?
Laugh! Come on, laugh, you brat! Laugh!
I see. He has psychic powers, too.
Are you a corpse?!
Your powers can't make me laugh.
I don't hate it.
I just couldn't, even if I wanted to.
I don't mean anything bad by it, though.
I see... He...
You must not have emotions, brat.
They mentioned that you were
having troubles with love.
With a personality like that, you won't
be able to laugh with the girl you like.
The feelings of people resonate
with one another, you know.
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 88%
But you're unable to do that.
You can't cry together, or even be moved.
You'll be forever alone.
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 92%
I'll give you one last chance...
Laugh!
Make me laugh with your psychic powers.
You... I see.
So you have similar powers...
I thought I picked a peaceful religious order
that'd cause the least bloodshed,
but you're in my way, brat.
I'll have to get rid of the outsider
that brings chaos to this environment.
Thank goodness. You're not a person.
Thank goodness the one who said
something as horrible as "get a clue"
was an evil spirit.
My followers!
Do not let him leave alive!
A strong commanding signal...
Mob.
Get a clue.
There is an esper present here.
A grade-schooler called
"Mob" by those around him.
Even though he's blessed with tremendous powers,
he's subconsciously always avoided
trying to display those powers.
As he grew,
he gradually realized
how dangerous his powers were.
When people are unable to act
or do as they please,
their emotions come to a halt.
Mob hasn't realized that his aversion to
using his powers has become a complex.
The emotions that are locked away
deep inside Mob's heart
expand little by little.
However, there is a limit to
how much his emotions can take
before leaking out and going wild.
And now, an emotion was swirling
about like a torrent, trying to go past the limit.
That was...
Rage.
To think that you were such a powerful esper...
No wonder the smile mask didn't work.
Mask? So there was a trick to that, too?
I didn't even notice
because it was so weak.
Oh, well.
If the policy of your religion
is to kill the outsiders,
come at me with everything you've got.
That might be easier than making me laugh.
"Come at me with everything you've got"?
Two seconds is plenty of time
to make you disappear, brat!
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
You're just livestock without emotions!
Don't try to act like you're actually angry!
How about you cry next?
Oho, how flashy.
What is this?
Well, I'll be damned.
I never thought I'd have to
fight with my full powers...
You may be the real thing, brat,
but this is where you die!
Wha...
What?!
Y-You're...
They came out upon your request.
These are my emotions.
This is what happens if I let them show.
A-Are you some kind of monster?!
But...
Wraither Beam!
Yes! A direct hit!
The number of fights I've endured
is what decides the victor and loser here!
I'm... terrible.
Ah.
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
You want to be able to get a clue?
Social skills like that are beyond you.
The only ones capable of them
have common sense and experience.
On the other hand, your
existence itself makes no sense.
Hey, why are you bummed out about that now?
Because I'm such a downer,
I ruined a whole bunch of people's fun.
Huh? Why do you have to be like them?
You're the protagonist of your own life.
That whole group is now gone because of me.
All they were doing was laughing...
Well, your inability to get a clue
is pretty destructive.
Get a Clue
What happened? You can tell me all about it.
Huh? What were we...
Dimple is passed out.
Did he always look like that?
Wasn't he trying to make some
boy smile, but he wouldn't?
Who was that boy?
Let's look for him.
He might be the true messenger of God.
I see... so typical mind control.
That's not salvation. He was just
having them depend on him.
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
It's a popular con
based on crowd psychology,
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
but considering you're hyper dense,
it didn't work on you.
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
Which means, Mob,
today you happened to save some people
that only you could have saved.
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion :   0   %
Shige, wake up!
You're going to be late.
Good morning.
Isn't it a lovely morning, Partner?
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion:   0 %
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion:   1 %
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion:   2 %
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion:   3 %
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion:   4 %
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion:   5 %
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 15 %
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 16 %
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 17 %
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 18 %
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 19 %
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 20 %
Mob gets dragged into an idiotic
event run by idiots for idiots.
The one that then appears before him
is a violent yet handsome guy.
What are you going to do, Mob?!
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 Episode 4:
"Idiots Only Event ~Kin~"
DVD? That's an excellent decision!
Idiots Only Event
~Kin~