JUJUTSU KAISEN
(JUJUTSU KAISEN THE
CULLING GAME PART 1)
(JUJUTSU KAISEN)
I was wondering who it was.
That face is a mess.
And it can't be healed, can it?
What are you going
to do now, Maki?
I didn't know you could tell
women apart by their faces.
I thought you only
had eyes for butts.
I'm asking you what
you're going to do next.
Answer me, you piece of trash.
You can't use jujutsu
or see cursed spirits.
Even the only thing decent
about you, your face is ruined.
No one will take you
seriously anymore.
How lonely.
Do you want me to
bully you like before?
What now?
Are you going to follow
Okkotsu and Megumi around?
Say something, you trash.
Maki, turn back now.
Did you forget?
We're not allowed in
the cursed warehouse.
But the head of the
Zen'in family agreed to it.
The head of the
Zen'in family? Me?
Yes, it was Naobito's will.
I refuse. It's too
much of a hassle.
No can do, I'm sorry.
Please accept it.
Naobito stated
that he would hand over all of
the Zen'in family's assets to you.
Including money
and cursed tools.
If you become the
head of the family,
you'll get information on the Big
Three Families and the higher-ups.
This will greatly affect
our future activities.
Then you be the head.
I'll give it to you.
No one will acknowledge
me as I am now.
Or follow me.
You've inherited the
family's cursed technique.
You've even mastered
Domain Expansion.
And Satoru values you.
Only you, with such a
good hand, can barely be it.
What do you mean, acknowledge?
It doesn't matter what the
Zen'in family thinks, right?
The benefits I
mentioned just now
can be obtained if you become
the head of the family, right?
I'm not qualified yet.
I... can't create a
sanctuary for Mai.
I understand.
Come back!
Why?
Why are you always like this?
Just for once,
make me glad I
gave birth to you.
Maki.
Dad.
If that was your plan, why
didn't you say so earlier?
You were too impatient.
It seems Megumi Fushiguro
is more capable than you.
What?
Many people support him.
They want to use this to repair
their relationship with the Gojo family.
However, giving all the
assets to Megumi Fushiguro
is something we cannot accept.
Then what's taking them so long?
It's not just the Gojo family.
Megumi Fushiguro and
Noritoshi Kamo, the next head of
the Kamo family, are on good terms.
If we eliminate him for no reason,
the Zen'in family's position will worsen.
Satoru Gojo is sealed.
The power struggle is
ever-changing, and we'll fall behind.
Of course, I know that.
But why now?
You didn't pay attention to the notice
from the Jujutsu Headquarters, did you?
(2. LIST GOJO AS CO-PERPETRATOR)
There's no reason not to make use of this.
(OF THE SHIBUYA INCIDENT) Megumi
Fushiguro, Maki, and Mai are deemed
(EXILE HIM FROM JUJUTSU SOCIETY)
rebels for attempting to free Satoru Gojo
(IT'S A CRIME TO UNSEAL
GOJO) and will be killed.
After all, killing your own
daughters makes it more justifiable.
Yes.
This way, we can gain more
trust from the Jujutsu Headquarters.
But will Uncle Ogi accept this?
This was Ogi's suggestion.
There are no more
cursed tools here, Maki.
We saw through your moves
and cleared them out beforehand.
Why are you here?
Idiot.
(JUZO KUMIYA'S
MASTERPIECE, "DRAGONBONE")
(ESOTERIC TECHNIQUE
"FALLING BLOSSOM EMOTION")
Do you know why I wasn't
made the head of the family,
but my brother Naobito was?
Because you're a
bastard who kills children.
Why didn't I become the head?
Why?
It's because of you kids.
It should have broken.
You're so useless.
The blade...
You think that by
breaking the blade,
you're shortening
the attack range,
and that's why you
got too close to me?
That's why you're useless.
I'm not a swordsman,
but a sorcerer.
You're just a defect, yet you want to
measure me by your own standards.
How ridiculous.
I'll say it as many
times as you want.
The reason I wasn't
chosen as the previous head
is because of you two.
The history of my brother's
cursed technique is short.
Whether it's family-inherited
or not isn't even the issue.
As a sorcerer,
my brother only outdo
me in one aspect.
That is the quality
of our children.
Children must never
hold their parents back.
Don't you know that?
In this country, holding
each other back is a virtue.
This is a training
and punishment room.
Countless Grade 2 or lower
cursed spirits are kept here.
Cursed spirits are
afraid of me now.
But they will crawl
out and eat you soon.
Heavenly Restriction,
physical prowess.
So what?
We sorcerers train our bodies every day
and use cursed energy to strengthen them.
Maki.
That ability of yours...
Every one of us has it.
Farewell,
the stain on my life.
You're so tenacious.
I knew it.
This would happen one day.
This is the worst.
You should know my
cursed technique by now.
I can't create anything
too big or complicated.
Besides, I was
just slashed by him.
I'll die after this.
I'm going first.
You're on your own now.
Hey, Mai. Wait.
What are you talking about?
Just come back.
I've known this for a long time.
Why are twins a bad
omen for jujutsu sorcerers?
If you want something,
you have to pay a price for it.
It's not limited
to Binding Vows.
It's the same as getting
stronger after suffering.
But for us,
this kind of relationship
is not always valid.
Because in jujutsu,
identical twins are seen
as the same person.
Do you understand?
You are me, and I am you.
Even if you throw up blood
trying to become
stronger, it's meaningless.
Because I don't
want to get stronger.
If you don't have
a cursed technique,
it's useless if I'm
the only one with it.
As long as I'm here, Maki,
you'll always be a half-baked.
I get it!
Come back!
I'll keep only this.
You can throw away the rest.
Be it cursed energy
or anything else,
I'll take it all away for you.
Just promise me one thing.
Destroy everything.
All of it.
My sister.
Mai...
Wake up...
Mai.
Wake up!
Mai!
Wake up...
Mai...
Mai... Wake up...
It's a reaction to the
cursed spirit's annihilation.
What's going on?
My body still remembers.
It's something I
wanted to forget.
That fear.
Cursed technique,
Blazing Courage!
I'll fight you!
With my own hands,
I'll burn you to
ashes once again!
Come here!
You useless--
Mai, let's get started.
(EPISODE 51 THE
PERFECT PREPARATION)
(JUJUTSU KAISEN)
What's with all the noise?
Mr. Jinichi!
Maki has lost her mind.
She killed Mr. Ogi.
The Kukuru Unit
is handling it now.
No matter how good Mr. Ogi is,
it's normal to miss an attack while
sleeping or using the bathroom.
Capture her before I get there.
Yes, sir.
If you dawdle, I'll be the one
getting yelled at by Jinichi.
Don't kill her.
(KUKURU UNIT, CAPTAIN,
NOBUAKI ZEN'IN) Don't kill her.
NOBUAKI ZEN'IN) I'll wrap things up.
- The "Kukuru Unit" is
comprised -Do you hear me?
- of Zen'in men without jujutsu.
- Hurry up!
As a subordinate
organization of the Hei,
- they undergo martial arts training.
- Found her!
She's in the Room of Tonnage.
What are you going to do?
What was I going to do?
We can see her holding
two unknown cursed tools.
Before Maki went
to Jujutsu High,
she was also in the Kukuru Unit.
Why won't you fall with me?
That's right.
Round her up!
Now that I think about it,
that was the right
answer for us.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Mai.
Surround her!
Promise me.
Destroy everything.
All of it.
How did it go?
You scared me.
It's Chojuro's cursed technique.
Has the Hei made their move?
The Hei,
(THE "HEI") based on
Jujutsu High qualifications,
(THE "HEI") all of them
are Semi-Grade 1 or above.
(THE "HEI") They
are the Zen'in family's
strongest group of sorcerers.
How is she still moving
after being attacked by Chojuro?
She's fast.
Even my cursed energy
defense was easily...
Is she really...
that Maki?
Mr. Jinichi!
Keep suppressing her!
Ranta!
I... I can't hold her down!
Don't worry about
me, Mr. Jinichi!
The Zen'in Clan only exists now
because Mr. Toji
wasn't interested.
You've noticed, haven't you?
Maki is just like him now!
Right now,
right here,
you must kill her!
You did it, Mr. Jinichi.
You're so cruel.
(HEAD OF THE HEI, NAOYA ZEN'IN)
Do you have a conscience?
No.
Because that guy took it all.
Everyone says I'm a genius.
They say I'm the next
head of the Zen'in family.
I heard there's a loser
in the Zen'in family.
He's a man,
but he has no
cursed Energy at all.
What a pathetic loser.
What a miserable
look on his face.
3, 4, 5, 9, 10, 11.
You...
You're not Toji!
The sin of a small fry
is not knowing what
it means to be strong.
No one understood
Toji back then.
I'm afraid only Satoru did.
You won't be the one.
The one who will be on that side
is me!
- Projection Sorcery,
- This is bad.
it can't make movements
that defy the laws of physics
- or trajectories.
- 6, 7, 8,
- And also, in terms
of speed, -13, 14.
there's a limit to the acceleration
upon activating the cursed technique.
On the other hand, if you
keep using the cursed technique,
you can keep
increasing your speed.
The one who will be on that side
is me!
I won't stop anymore.
I won't make
mistakes like that time.
Power comes from
weight and speed.
Does she want to
fight me head-on?
I'm going to hug you.
I'll pierce her body
as fast as I can.
Projection Sorcery,
when activated, the object
you touch with your palm
must move in
one-twenty-fourth of a second.
If you fail, your movement
will pause for one second.
Do you plan to take my attack
even if it means destroying your ribs?
You're trying to stop my
movement, aren't you?
Did you think I'd fall for
such an obvious trap?
You really are just a fake.
It's 24 times, right?
You and that old man
Naobito weren't just fast.
I knew something was off.
It's 24 movements in one second.
Now that I'm in this
body, I can finally see it.
You fake--
I'm sorry.
Could you say that again?
Mom.
No, don't come near me!
- Why?
- Please, listen to me.
Why did you...
Back then, why did you
tell me to "come back"?
What are you talking about?
No...
No!
You're too careless, bitch!
Are you kidding me?
I can't gather my cursed energy.
Useless trash.
I'm so glad I gave
birth to you both.
Mai!
That's why I told you not to go.
I'll leave her to you.
What will you do now, Maki?
(SIX MEMBERS OF THE HEI, NINE
OF THE AKASHI IN THE ZEN'IN CLAN)
(AND 21 OF THE KUKURU UNIT ABSENT FROM THE
ZEN'IN HOUSE THAT DAY WERE LATER KILLED)
(NO RESIDUAL CURSED ENERGY
WAS LEFT AT THE CRIME SCENE.)
(CURSED ENERGY DETECTED FROM THE WOUNDS,
WEAPON PRESUMED TO BE A CURSED TOOL)
(A FEW DAYS LATER, THE GOJO AND KAMO
PROPOSED TO THE JUJUTSU HEADQUARTERS)
(TO REMOVE THE ZEN'IN FROM THE BIG THREE.
THE HQ TEMPORARILY TABLED THE MATTER.)
Hakari was suspended for
arguing with the higher-ups.
A gambling tournament?
Do not mention the club.
But I can't get close to it.
Itadori, investigate
from the inside.
I love my passionate Kinji.
Do you want to
drown in my "passion"?
(NEXT EPISODE, ZEAL) Do
you want to drown in my "passion"?